<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T11:14:48Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-06-19" from="2017-06-19" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1206.1527</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1206.1527</id><created>2012-06-07</created><updated>2017-06-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Anwar</keyname><forenames>M. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lacoste</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aarts</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Anisotropic magnetothermoelectric power of ferromagnetic thin films</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.other</categories><comments>6 pages, 7 figures</comments><doi>10.1016/j.jmmm.2017.06.055</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compare the behavior of the magnetothermoelectric power (MTEP)in metallic
ferromagnetic thin films of Ni80Fe20 (Permalloy; Py), Co and CrO2 at
temperatures in the range of 100 K to 400 K. In 25 nm thick Py films and 50 nm
thick Co films both the anisotropic magnetoresistance (AMR) and MTEP show a
relative change in resistance and thermoelectric power (TEP) of the order of
0.2% when the magnetic field is reversed, and in both cases there is no
significant change in AMR or MTEP any more after the saturation field has been
reached. Surprisingly, both Py and Co films have opposite MTEP behavior
although both have the same sign for AMR and TEP. The data on 100 nm films of
fully spin-polarized CrO2, grown both on TiO2 and on sapphire, show a different
picture. The MTEP behavior at low fields shows peaks similar to the AMR in
these films, with variations up to 1%. With increasing field both the MR and
the MTEP variations keeps growing, with MTEP showing relative changes of 1.5%
with the thermal gradient along the b-axis and even 20% with the gradient along
the c-axis, with an intermediate value of 3% for the film on sapphire. It
appears that the low-field effects are due to magnetic domain switching, while
the high-field effects are intrinsic to the electronic structure of CrO2.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1210.4119</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1210.4119</id><created>2012-10-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Darbandi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rubel</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Single-carrier impact ionization favored by a limited band dispersion</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Appl. Phys. 113, 203104 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4807650</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A critical requirement for high gain and low noise avalanche photodiodes is
the single-carrier avalanche multiplication. We propose that the single-carrier
avalanche multiplication can be achieved in materials with a limited width of
the conduction or valence band resulting in a restriction of kinetic energy for
one of the charge carriers. This feature is not common to the majority of
technologically relevant semiconductors, but it is observed in chalcogenides,
such as Selenium and compound I2-II-IV-VI4 alloys.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1306.4617</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1306.4617</id><created>2013-06-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Asenbaum</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuhn</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nimmrichter</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sezer</keyname><forenames>Ugur</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arndt</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author></authors><title>Cavity cooling of free silicon nanoparticles in high-vacuum</title><categories>quant-ph physics.atom-ph physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Nat. Commun. 4:2743 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms3743</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Laser cooling has given a boost to atomic physics throughout the last thirty
years since it allows one to prepare atoms in motional states which can only be
described by quantum mechanics. Most methods, such as Doppler cooling,
polarization gradient cooling or sub-recoil laser cooling rely, however, on a
near-resonant and cyclic coupling between laser light and well-defined internal
states. Although this feat has recently even been achieved for diatomic
molecules, it is very hard for mesoscopic particles. It has been proposed that
an external cavity may compensate for the lack of internal cycling transitions
in dielectric objects and it may thus provide assistance in the cooling of
their centre of mass state. Here, we demonstrate cavity cooling of the
transverse kinetic energy of silicon nanoparticles propagating in genuine
high-vacuum (&lt; 10^8 mbar). We create and launch them with longitudinal
velocities even down to v &lt; 1 m/s using laser induced thermomechanical stress
on a pristine silicon wafer. The interaction with the light of a high-finesse
infrared cavity reduces their transverse kinetic energy by more than a factor
of 30. This is an important step towards new tests of recent proposals to
explore the still speculative non-linearities of quantum mechanics with objects
in the mass range between 10^7 and 10^10 amu.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1307.6567</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1307.6567</id><created>2013-07-24</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cassani</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martelli</keyname><forenames>Dario</forenames></author></authors><title>Supersymmetry on curved spaces and superconformal anomalies</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>33 pages; v2: minor changes, references added; v3: typos corrected,
  minor improvements; v4: equations (5.9) and (5.10) of v3 corrected</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP10(2013)025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the consequences of unbroken rigid supersymmetry of four-dimensional
field theories placed on curved manifolds. We show that in Lorentzian signature
the background vector field coupling to the R-current is determined by the Weyl
tensor of the background metric. In Euclidean signature, the same holds if two
supercharges of opposite R-charge are preserved, otherwise the (anti-)self-dual
part of the vector field-strength is fixed by the Weyl tensor. As a result of
this relation, the trace and R-current anomalies of superconformal field
theories simplify, with the trace anomaly becoming purely topological. In
particular, in Lorentzian signature, or in the presence of two Euclidean
supercharges of opposite R-charge, supersymmetry of the background implies that
the term proportional to the central charge c vanishes, both in the trace and
R-current anomalies. This is equivalent to the vanishing of a superspace Weyl
invariant. We comment on the implications of our results for holography.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1402.7371</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1402.7371</id><created>2014-02-28</created><updated>2016-09-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Fan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirschberger</keyname><forenames>Max</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loew</keyname><forenames>Toshinao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Gang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lawson</keyname><forenames>Benjamin J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asaba</keyname><forenames>Tomoya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kemper</keyname><forenames>J. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Tian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Porras</keyname><forenames>Juan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boebinger</keyname><forenames>G. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singleton</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keimer</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Lu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ong</keyname><forenames>N. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>The magnetic phase diagram of underdoped YBa2Cu3Oy inferred from torque
  magnetization and thermal conductivity</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>7 pages, 8 figures; New version of previous posting, reporting torque
  measurements to 45 Tesla and final magnetic phase diagram</comments><journal-ref>PNAS 113, 45 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1073/pnas.1612591113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Strong evidence for charge-density correlation in the underdoped phase of the
cuprate YBa2Cu3Oy was obtained by nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) and resonant
x-ray scatter- ing. The fluctuations were found to be enhanced in strong
magnetic fields. Recently, 3D (three dimensional) charge-density wave (CDW)
formation with long-range order (LRO) was observed by x-ray diffraction in H
&gt;15 T. To elucidate how the CDW transition impacts the pair condensate, we have
used torque magnetization to 45 T and thermal conductivity $\kappa_{xx}$ to
construct the magnetic phase diagram in untwinned crystals with hole density p
= 0.11. We show that the 3D CDW transitions appear as sharp features in the
susceptibility and $\kappa_{xx}$ at the fields HK and Hp, which define phase
boundaries in agreement with spectroscopic techniques. From measurements of the
melting field Hm(T) of the vortex solid, we obtain evidence for two vortex
solid states below 8 K. At 0.5 K, the pair condensate appears to adjust to the
3D CDW by a sharp transition at 24 T between two vortex solids with very
different shear moduli. At even higher H (42 T) the second vortex solid melts
to a vortex liquid which survives to fields well above 45 T. de Haas-van Alphen
oscillations appear at fields 24-28 T, below the lower bound for the upper
critical field Hc2.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1403.1114</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1403.1114</id><created>2014-03-05</created><updated>2014-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Keating</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Linden</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wells</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Random matrices and quantum spin chains</title><categories>math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>Updated figures, as accepted in 'Markov Processes and Related Fields'
  on 3 March 2014</comments><journal-ref>Markov Processes and Related Fields: Volume 21, Issue 3 (2015),
  Pages 537-555</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Random matrix ensembles are introduced that respect the local tensor
structure of Hamiltonians describing a chain of $n$ distinguishable spin-half
particles with nearest-neighbour interactions. We prove a central limit theorem
for the density of states when $n \rightarrow\infty$, giving explicit bounds on
the rate of approach to the limit. Universality within a class of probability
measures and the extension to more general interaction geometries are
established. The level spacing distributions of the Gaussian Orthogonal,
Unitary and Symplectic Ensembles are observed numerically for the energy levels
in these ensembles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1403.1121</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1403.1121</id><created>2014-03-05</created><updated>2015-01-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Keating</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Linden</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wells</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectra and eigenstates of spin chain Hamiltonians</title><categories>math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>Updated figures, as accepted in 'Communications in Mathematical
  Physics' on 5 January 2015</comments><journal-ref>Communications in Mathematical Physics: Volume 338, Issue 1
  (2015), Pages 81-102</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00220-015-2366-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove that translationally invariant Hamiltonians of a chain of $n$ qubits
with nearest-neighbour interactions have two seemingly contradictory features.
Firstly in the limit $n\rightarrow\infty$ we show that any translationally
invariant Hamiltonian of a chain of $n$ qubits has an eigenbasis such that
almost all eigenstates have maximal entanglement between fixed-size sub-blocks
of qubits and the rest of the system; in this sense these eigenstates are like
those of completely general Hamiltonians (i.e. Hamiltonians with interactions
of all orders between arbitrary groups of qubits). Secondly in the limit
$n\rightarrow\infty$ we show that any nearest-neighbour Hamiltonian of a chain
of $n$ qubits has a Gaussian density of states; thus as far as the eigenvalues
are concerned the system is like a non-interacting one. The comparison applies
to chains of qubits with translationally invariant nearest-neighbour
interactions, but we show that it is extendible to much more general systems
(both in terms of the local dimension and the geometry of interaction).
Numerical evidence is also presented which suggests that the translational
invariance condition may be dropped in the case of nearest-neighbour chains.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1404.7794</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1404.7794</id><created>2014-04-30</created><updated>2014-11-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Tian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gibson</keyname><forenames>Quinn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ali</keyname><forenames>Mazhar N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Minhao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cava</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ong</keyname><forenames>N. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultrahigh mobility and giant magnetoresistance in the Dirac semimetal
  Cd$_3$As$_2$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>Main text has 7 pages, 4 figures and 1 table. Text has been
  re-written with new results added. Supplement has 8 pages, 13 figures and 1
  table, Nature Materials online Nov 24, 2014</comments><journal-ref>Nat. Mat. 14, 280 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/NMAT4143</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dirac semimetals and Weyl semimetals are 3D analogs of graphene in which
crystalline symmetry protects the nodes against gap formation [1-3]. Na$_3$Bi
and Cd$_3$As$_2$ were predicted to be Dirac semimetals [4,5], and recently
confirmed to be so by photoemission [6-8]. Several novel transport properties
in a magnetic field $\bf H$ have been proposed for Dirac semimetals [2,9-11].
Here we report an interesting property in Cd$_3$As$_2$ that was unpredicted,
namely a remarkable protection mechanism that strongly suppresses
back-scattering in zero $\bf H$. In single crystals, the protection results in
a very high mobility that exceeds $&gt;10^7$ cm$^2$/Vs below 4 K. Suppression of
backscattering results in a transport lifetime 10$^4\times$ longer than the
quantum lifetime. The lifting of this protection by $\bf H$ leads to an unusual
giant $\bf H$-linear magnetoresistance that violates Kohler's rule. We discuss
how this may relate to changes to the Fermi surface induced by $\bf H$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.3960</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.3960</id><created>2014-12-12</created><updated>2015-12-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sznitman</keyname><forenames>Alain-Sol</forenames></author></authors><title>Disconnection, random walks, and random interlacements</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>38 pages, corresponds to the version published in Probability Theory
  and Related Fields except for the numbering of the sections</comments><msc-class>60F10, 60K35, 60J27, 82B43</msc-class><journal-ref>Probab. Theory Relat. Fields, 167, 1-44 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00440-015-0676-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider random interlacements on Z^d, with d bigger or equal to 3, when
their vacant set is in a strongly percolative regime. We derive an asymptotic
upper bound on the probability that the random interlacements disconnect a box
of large side-length from the boundary of a larger homothetic box. As a
corollary, we obtain an asymptotic upper bound on a similar quantity, where the
random interlacements are replaced by the simple random walk. It is plausible,
but open at the moment, that these asymptotic upper bounds match the asymptotic
lower bounds obtained by Xinyi Li and the author in arXiv:1310.2177, for random
interlacements, and by Xinyi Li in a recent article, for the simple random
walk. In any case, our bounds capture the principal exponential rate of decay
of these probabilities, in any dimension d bigger or equal to 3.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.02006</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.02006</id><created>2015-02-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Hirschberger</keyname><forenames>Max</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krizan</keyname><forenames>Jason W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cava</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ong</keyname><forenames>N. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermal Hall conductivity in the frustrated pyrochlore magnet Tb2Ti2O7</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Science 348, 106 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1126/science.1257340</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a ferromagnet, the spin excitations are the well-studied magnons. In
frustrated quantum magnets, long-range magnetic order fails to develop despite
a large exchange coupling between the spins. In contrast to the magnons in
conventional magnets, their spin excitations are poorly understood. Are they
itinerant or localized? Here we show that the thermal Hall conductivity
$\kappa_{xy}$ provides a powerful probe of spin excitations in the &quot;quantum
spin ice&quot; pyrochlore Tb$_2$Ti$_2$O$_7$. The thermal Hall response is large even
though the material is transparent. The Hall response arises from spin
excitations with specific characteristics that distinguish them from magnons.
At low temperature ($T&lt;$ 1 K), the thermal conductivity imitates that of a
dirty metal. Using the Hall angle, we construct a phase diagram showing how the
excitations are suppressed by a magnetic field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.03005</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.03005</id><created>2015-04-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Kochiashvili</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xf8;ller</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Milvang-Jensen</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Christensen</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fynbo</keyname><forenames>J. P. U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Freudling</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cl&#xe9;ment</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cuby</keyname><forenames>J. -G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zabl</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zibetti</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Emission line selected galaxies at $z=0.6-2$ in GOODS South: Stellar
  masses, SFRs, and large scale structure</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>18 pages, 19 figures, version accepted for publication in A&amp;A</comments><journal-ref>A&amp;A, 580, A42 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201425535</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have obtained deep NIR narrow and broad (J and Y) band imaging data of the
GOODS-South field. The narrow band filter is centered at 1060 nm corresponding
to redshifts $z = 0.62, 1.15, 1.85$ for the strong emission lines H$\alpha$,
$[$OIII$]$/H$\beta$ and $[$OII$]$, respectively. From those data we extract a
well defined sample ($M(AB)=24.8$ in the narrow band) of objects with large
emission line equivalent widths in the narrow band. Via SED fits to published
broad band data we identify which of the three lines we have detected and
assign redshifts accordingly. This results in a well defined, strong emission
line selected sample of galaxies down to lower masses than can easily be
obtained with only continuum flux limited selection techniques. We compare the
(SED fitting-derived) main sequence of star-formation (MS) of our sample to
previous works and find that it has a steeper slope than that of samples of
more massive galaxies. We conclude that the MS steepens at lower (below
$M_{\star} = 10^{9.4} M_{\odot}$) galaxy masses. We also show that the SFR at
any redshift is higher in our sample. We attribute this to the targeted
selection of galaxies with large emission line equivalent widths, and conclude
that our sample presumably forms the upper boundary of the MS. We briefly
investigate and outline how samples with accurate redshifts down to those low
stellar masses open a new window to study the formation of large scale
structure in the early universe. In particular we report on the detection of a
young galaxy cluster at $z=1.85$ which features a central massive galaxy which
is the candidate of an early stage cD galaxy, and we identify a likely filament
mapped out by $[$OIII$]$ and $H\beta$ emitting galaxies at $z=1.15$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.01791</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.01791</id><created>2015-05-07</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tahamtan</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Svitek</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Kundt spacetimes minimally coupled to scalar field</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>updated to published version</comments><msc-class>83C15, 83C22, 83C50</msc-class><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 77 (2017) 384</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4945-z</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We derive an exact solution belonging to Kundt class of spacetimes both with
and without a cosmological constant that are minimally coupled to a free
massless scalar field. We show the algebraic type of these solutions and give
interpretation of the results. Subsequently, we look for solutions additionally
containing an electromagnetic field satisfying nonlinear field equations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.01859</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.01859</id><created>2015-05-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Zabl</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>N&#xf8;rgaard-Nielsen</keyname><forenames>H. U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fynbo</keyname><forenames>J. P. U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laursen</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ouchi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kj&#xe6;rgaard</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Deep rest-frame far-UV spectroscopy of the giant Lyman-alpha emitter
  'Himiko'</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><journal-ref>MNRAS, 451, 2050 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv1019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present deep 10h VLT/XSHOOTER spectroscopy for an extraordinarily luminous
and extended Lya emitter at z=6.595 referred to as Himiko and first discussed
by Ouchi et al. (2009), with the purpose of constraining the mechanisms
powering its strong emission. Complementary to the spectrum, we discuss NIR
imaging data from the CANDELS survey. We find neither for HeII nor any metal
line a significant excess, with 3 sigma upper limits of 6.8, 3.1, and
5.8x10^{-18} erg/s/cm^2 for CIV $\lambda$1549, HeII $\lambda$1640, CIII]
$\lambda$1909, respectively, assuming apertures with 200 km/s widths and offset
by -250 km/s w.r.t to the peak Lya redshift. These limits provide strong
evidence that an AGN is not a major contribution to Himiko's Lya flux. Strong
conclusions about the presence of PopIII star-formation or gravitational
cooling radiation are not possible based on the obtained HeII upper limit. Our
Lya spectrum confirms both spatial extent and flux (8.8+/-0.5x10^{-17}
erg/s/cm^2) of previous measurements. In addition, we can unambiguously exclude
any remaining chance of it being a lower redshift interloper by significantly
detecting a continuum redwards of Lya, while being undetected bluewards.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.04043</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.04043</id><created>2015-05-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Semiz</keyname><forenames>&#x130;brahim</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#xc7;aml&#x131;bel</keyname><forenames>A. Kaz&#x131;m</forenames></author></authors><title>What do the cosmological supernova data really tell us?</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>27 regular LaTeX pages, 16 figures, 4 tables</comments><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2015/12/038</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Not much by themselves, aparently.
  We try to reconstruct the scale factor $a(t)$ of the universe from the SNe Ia
data, i.e. the luminosity distance $d_{L}(z)$, using only the cosmological
principle and the assumption that gravitation is governed by a metric theory.
In our hence &quot;model-independent,&quot; or &quot;cosmographic&quot; study, we fit functions to
$d_{L}(z)$ rather than $a(t)$, since $d_{L}(z)$ is what is measured. We find
that the acceleration history of the universe cannot be reliably determined in
this approach due to the irregularity and parametrization-dependence of the
results.
  However, adding the GRB data to the dataset cures most of the irregularities,
at the cost of compromising the model-independent nature of the study slightly.
Then we can determine the redshift of transition to cosmic acceleration as
$z_{\rm t} \sim 0.50 \pm 0.09$ for a flat universe (larger for positive spatial
curvature).
  If Einstein gravity (GR) is assumed, we find a redshift at which the density
of the universe predicted from the $d_{L}(z)$ data is independent of curvature.
We use this point to derive an upper limit on matter density, hence a lower
limit on the density of dark energy. While these limits do not improve the
generally accepted ones, they are derived *only using the $d_{L}(z)$ data*.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.05721</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.05721</id><created>2015-05-21</created><updated>2015-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Caputi</keyname><forenames>K. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ilbert</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laigle</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCracken</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fevre</keyname><forenames>O. Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fynbo</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Milvang-Jensen</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Capak</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salvato</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taniguchi</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spitzer bright, UltraVISTA faint sources in COSMOS: the contribution to
  the overall population of massive galaxies at z=3-7</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>18 pages, 15 figures, 4 tables. Updated to match version in press at
  the ApJ</comments><journal-ref>ApJ, 810, 73 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0004-637X/810/1/73</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have analysed a sample of 574 Spitzer 4.5 micron-selected galaxies with
[4.5]&lt;23 and Ks_auto&gt;24 (AB) over the UltraVISTA ultra-deep COSMOS field. Our
aim is to investigate whether these mid-IR bright, near-IR faint sources
contribute significantly to the overall population of massive galaxies at
redshifts z&gt;=3. By performing a spectral energy distribution (SED) analysis
using up to 30 photometric bands, we have determined that the redshift
distribution of our sample peaks at redshifts z~2.5-3.0, and ~32% of the
galaxies lie at z&gt;=3. We have studied the contribution of these sources to the
galaxy stellar mass function (GSMF) at high redshifts. We found that the
[4.5]&lt;23, Ks_auto&gt;24 galaxies produce a negligible change to the GSMF
previously determined for Ks_auto&lt;24 sources at 3=&lt;z&lt;4, but their contribution
is more important at 4=&lt;z&lt;5, accounting for &gt;~50% of the galaxies with stellar
masses Mst&gt;~6 x 10^10 Msun. We also constrained the GSMF at the highest-mass
end (Mst&gt;~2 x 10^11 Msun) at z&gt;=5. From their presence at 5=&lt;z&lt;6, and virtual
absence at higher redshifts, we can pinpoint quite precisely the moment of
appearance of the first most massive galaxies as taking place in the ~0.2 Gyr
of elapsed time between z~6 and z~5. Alternatively, if very massive galaxies
existed earlier in cosmic time, they should have been significantly
dust-obscured to lie beyond the detection limits of current, large-area, deep
near-IR surveys.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.06302</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.06302</id><created>2015-05-23</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cremonesi</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferlito</keyname><forenames>Giulia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hanany</keyname><forenames>Amihay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mekareeya</keyname><forenames>Noppadol</forenames></author></authors><title>Instanton Operators and the Higgs Branch at Infinite Coupling</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>v1: 35 pages + appendices. v2: published version with several
  changes, 37 pages + appendices</comments><report-no>IMPERIAL-TP-15-AH-03, CERN-PH-TH-2015-115</report-no><doi>10.1007/JHEP04(2017)042</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The richness of 5d $\mathcal{N}=1$ theories with a UV fixed point at infinite
coupling is due to the existence of local disorder operators known as instanton
operators. By considering the Higgs branch of $SU(2)$ gauge theories with $N_f
\leq 7$ flavours at finite and infinite coupling, we write down the explicit
chiral ring relations between instanton operators, the glueball superfield and
mesons. Exciting phenomena appear at infinite coupling: the glueball superfield
is no longer nilpotent and the classical chiral ring relations are quantum
corrected by instanton operators bilinears. We also find expressions for the
dressing of instanton operators of arbitrary charge. The same analysis is
performed for $USp(2k)$ with an antisymmetric hypermultiplet and pure $SU(N)$
gauge theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.08834</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.08834</id><created>2015-06-29</created><updated>2017-06-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Harrow</keyname><forenames>Aram W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Natarajan</keyname><forenames>Anand</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Xiaodi</forenames></author></authors><title>An improved semidefinite programming hierarchy for testing entanglement</title><categories>quant-ph cs.DS math.OC</categories><comments>22 pages. v2: published version, adds numerical results. Matlab code
  available at https://github.com/isobovine/dpsplus/</comments><report-no>MIT-CTP/4587</report-no><journal-ref>Commun. Math. Phys. Vol. 352, No. 3, pp 881-904 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00220-017-2859-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a stronger version of the Doherty-Parrilo-Spedalieri (DPS)
hierarchy of approximations for the set of separable states. Unlike DPS, our
hierarchy converges exactly at a finite number of rounds for any fixed input
dimension. This yields an algorithm for separability testing which is singly
exponential in dimension and polylogarithmic in accuracy. Our analysis makes
use of tools from algebraic geometry, but our algorithm is elementary and
differs from DPS only by one simple additional collection of constraints.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.04695</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.04695</id><created>2015-10-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Krogager</keyname><forenames>J. -K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fynbo</keyname><forenames>J. P. U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noterdaeme</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zafar</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xf8;ller</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ledoux</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kr&#xfc;hler</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stockton</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>A quasar reddened by a sub-parsec sized, metal-rich and dusty cloud in a
  damped Lyman-alpha absorber at z=2.13</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>14 pages, accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS, 455, 2698 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv2346</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a detailed analysis of a red quasar at z=2.32 with an intervening
damped Lyman-alpha absorber (DLA) at z=2.13. Using high quality data from the
X-shooter spectrograph at ESO Very Large Telescope we find that the absorber
has a metallicity consistent with Solar. We observe strong C I and H$_2$
absorption indicating a cold, dense absorbing medium. Partial coverage effects
are observed in the C I lines, from which we infer a covering fraction of $27
\pm 6$ % and a physical diameter of the cloud of 0.1 pc. From the covering
fraction and size, we estimate the size of the background quasar's broad line
region. We search for emission from the DLA counterpart in optical and
near-infrared imaging. No emission is observed in the optical data. However, we
see tentative evidence for a counterpart in the H and K' band images. The DLA
shows high depletion (as probed by [Fe/Zn]=-1.22) indicating that significant
amounts of dust must be present in the DLA. By fitting the spectrum with
various dust reddened quasar templates we find a best-fitting amount of dust in
the DLA of $A(V)_{\rm DLA}=0.28 \pm 0.01|_{\rm stat} \pm 0.07|_{\rm sys}$. We
conclude that dust in the DLA is causing the colours of this intrinsically very
luminous background quasar to appear much redder than average quasars, thereby
not fulfilling the criteria for quasar identification in the Sloan Digital Sky
Survey. Such chemically enriched and dusty absorbers are thus underrepresented
in current samples of DLAs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.07807</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.07807</id><created>2015-10-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Lipunov</keyname><forenames>V. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorosabel</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pruzhinskaya</keyname><forenames>M. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Postigo</keyname><forenames>A. de Ugarte</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pelassa</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsvetkova</keyname><forenames>A. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sokolov</keyname><forenames>I. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kann</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Dong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorbovskoy</keyname><forenames>E. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krushinski</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kornilov</keyname><forenames>V. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balanutsa</keyname><forenames>P. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boronina</keyname><forenames>S. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Budnev</keyname><forenames>N. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cano</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Castro-Tirado</keyname><forenames>A. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chazov</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Connaughton</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delvaux</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frederiks</keyname><forenames>D. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fynbo</keyname><forenames>J. F. U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gabovich</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldstein</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greiner</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gress</keyname><forenames>O. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ivanov</keyname><forenames>K. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jakobsson</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klose</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knust</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Komarova</keyname><forenames>V. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Konstantinov</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krylov</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuvshinov</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuznetsov</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lipunova</keyname><forenames>G. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moskvitin</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pal'shin</keyname><forenames>V. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>S. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poleshchuk</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidl</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sergienko</keyname><forenames>Yu. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinyakov</keyname><forenames>E. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schulze</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sokolov</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sokolova</keyname><forenames>T. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sparre</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thone</keyname><forenames>C. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tlatov</keyname><forenames>A. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tyurina</keyname><forenames>N. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ulanov</keyname><forenames>M. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yazev</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yurkov</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>The optical identifcation of events with poorly defined locations: The
  case of the Fermi GBM GRB140801A</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>in press MNRAS, 2015</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS, 455, 712 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv2228</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the early discovery of the optical afterglow of gamma-ray burst
(GRB) 140801A in the 137 deg$^2$ 3-$\sigma$ error-box of the Fermi Gamma-ray
Burst Monitor (GBM). MASTER is the only observatory that automatically react to
all Fermi alerts. GRB 140801A is one of the few GRBs whose optical counterpart
was discovered solely from its GBM localization. The optical afterglow of GRB
140801A was found by MASTER Global Robotic Net 53 sec after receiving the
alert, making it the fastest optical detection of a GRB from a GBM error-box.
Spectroscopy obtained with the 10.4-m Gran Telescopio Canarias and the 6-m BTA
of SAO RAS reveals a redshift of $z=1.32$. We performed optical and
near-infrared photometry of GRB 140801A using different telescopes with
apertures ranging from 0.4-m to 10.4-m. GRB 140801A is a typical burst in many
ways. The rest-frame bolometric isotropic energy release and peak energy of the
burst is $E_\mathrm{iso} = 5.54_{-0.24}^{+0.26} \times 10^{52}$ erg and
$E_\mathrm{p, rest}\simeq280$ keV, respectively, which is consistent with the
Amati relation. The absence of a jet break in the optical light curve provides
a lower limit on the half-opening angle of the jet $\theta=6.1$ deg. The
observed $E_\mathrm{peak}$ is consistent with the limit derived from the
Ghirlanda relation. The joint Fermi GBM and Konus-Wind analysis shows that GRB
140801A could belong to the class of intermediate duration. The rapid detection
of the optical counterpart of GRB 140801A is especially important regarding the
upcoming experiments with large coordinate error-box areas.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.06105</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.06105</id><created>2015-11-19</created><updated>2017-06-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Murakami</keyname><forenames>Yuta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Werner</keyname><forenames>Philipp</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsuji</keyname><forenames>Naoto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aoki</keyname><forenames>Hideo</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiple amplitude modes in strongly-coupled phonon-mediated
  superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>11pages, 11figures published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 094509 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.094509</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study collective amplitude modes of the superconducting order parameter in
strongly-coupled electron-phonon systems described by the Holstein model using
the nonequilibrium dynamical mean-field theory with the self-consistent Migdal
approximation as an impurity solver. The frequency of the Higgs amplitude mode
is found to coincide with the superconducting gap even in the strongly-coupled
(beyond BCS) regime. Besides the Higgs mode, we unravel another collective mode
involving the dynamics of both the phonons and the superconducting order
parameter. The frequency of this mode, higher than twice the renormalized
phonon frequency in the superconducting phase, is shown to reflect a strong
electron-mediated phonon-phonon interaction. Both types of collective
excitations contribute to time-resolved photoemission spectra after a strong
laser pump as vertex corrections to produce resonance peaks, which allows one
to distinguish them from quasiparticle excitations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.07365</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.07365</id><created>2015-10-27</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Bin</forenames><affiliation>USTC, Cornell</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lai</keyname><forenames>Dong</forenames><affiliation>Cornell</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Ye-Fei</forenames><affiliation>USTC</affiliation></author></authors><title>Merging Compact Binaries in Hierarchical Triple Systems: Resonant
  Excitation of Binary Eccentricity</title><categories>astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>Another typo in Eq.(38) is corrected. In Eq.(38): (a1/a2)^{3} should
  be (a1/a2)^{-3}. Two previous typos are as follows: in Eq.12: (1-e_2^2)^{5/2}
  should be (1-e_2^2)^2, and in Eq.14: (4+3e_1) should be (4+3 e_1^2). Thanks
  to Ryan Miranda for pointing this out</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review D 92, 124048 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.92.124048</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the secular dynamics of compact binaries (consisting of white
dwarfs, neutron stars or black holes) with tertiary companions in hierarchical
triple systems. As the inner binary (with initially negligible eccentricity)
undergoes orbital decay due to gravitational radiation, its eccentricity can be
excited by gravitational forcing from the tertiary. This excitation occurs when
the triple system passes through an &quot;apsidal precession resonance&quot;, when the
precession rate of the inner binary, driven by the gravitational perturbation
of the external companion and general relativity, matches the precession rate
of the outer binary. The eccentricity excitation requires the outer companion
to be on an eccentric orbit, with the mutual inclination between the inner and
outer orbits less than $\sim 40^\circ$. Gravitational wave (GW) signals from
the inner binary can be significantly modified as the system evolves through
the apsidal precession resonance. For some system parameters (e.g., a white
dwarf binary with a brown dwarf tertiary), the resonance can happen when the
binary emits GWs in the $10^{-4}-10^{-1}$~Hz range (the sensitivity band of
LISA).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.05109</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.05109</id><created>2016-01-19</created><updated>2017-06-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Helou</keyname><forenames>Alexis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Musco</keyname><forenames>Ilia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>John C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Causal Nature and Dynamics of Trapping Horizons in Black Hole Collapse</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>33 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Classical and Quantum Gravity 34, 135012 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6382/aa6d8f</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In calculations of gravitational collapse to form black holes, trapping
horizons (foliated by marginally trapped surfaces) make their first appearance
either within the collapsing matter or where it joins on to a vacuum exterior.
Those which then move outwards with respect to the matter have been proposed
for use in defining black holes, replacing the global concept of an &quot;event
horizon&quot; which has some serious drawbacks for practical applications. We here
present results from a study of the properties of both outgoing and ingoing
trapping horizons, assuming strict spherical symmetry throughout. We have
investigated their causal nature (i.e. whether they are spacelike, timelike or
null), making contact with the Misner-Sharp- Hernandez formalism, which has
often been used for numerical calculations of spherical collapse. We follow two
different approaches, one using a geometrical quantity related to expansions of
null geodesic congruences, and the other using the horizon velocity measured
with respect to the collapsing matter. After an introduction to these concepts,
we then implement them within numerical simulations of stellar collapse,
revisiting pioneering calculations from the 1960s where some features of the
emergence and subsequent behaviour of trapping horizons could already be seen.
Our presentation here is aimed firmly at &quot;real world&quot; applications of interest
to astrophysicists and includes the effects of pressure, which may be important
for the asymptotic behaviour of the ingoing horizon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04508</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04508</id><created>2016-02-14</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ibrahim</keyname><forenames>Ahmed K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vojta</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Emerging critical behavior at a first-order phase transition rounded by
  disorder</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 eps figures included, builds on arXiv:1504.00408, final
  version as published</comments><journal-ref>Fortschr. Phys. 65, No. 6-8, 1600018 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/prop.201600018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the two-dimensional four-color Ashkin-Teller model by means of
large-scale Monte-Carlo simulations. We demonstrate that the first-order phase
transition of the clean system is destroyed by random disorder introduced via
site dilution. The critical behavior of the emerging continuous transition
belongs to the clean two-dimensional Ising universality class, apart from
logarithmic corrections. These results confirm perturbative
renormalization-group predictions; they also agree with recent findings for the
three-color case, indicating that the critical behavior is universal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07219</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07219</id><created>2016-02-23</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hirschberger</keyname><forenames>Max</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kushwaha</keyname><forenames>Satya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhijun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gibson</keyname><forenames>Quinn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Belvin</keyname><forenames>Carina A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernevig</keyname><forenames>B. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cava</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ong</keyname><forenames>N. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>The chiral anomaly and thermopower of Weyl fermions in the half-Heusler
  GdPtBi</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures (Added Supplement with 11 additional pages and 14
  new figures)</comments><journal-ref>Nat. Mat. 15, 1161 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nmat4684</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Dirac and Weyl semimetals are unusual materials in which the nodes of the
bulk states are protected against gap formation by crystalline symmetry. The
chiral anomaly~\cite{Adler,Bell}, predicted to occur in both systems, was
recently observed as a negative longitudinal magnetoresistance (LMR) in
Na$_3$Bi and in TaAs. An important issue is whether Weyl physics appears in a
broader class of materials. We report evidence for the chiral anomaly in the
half-Heusler GdPtBi. In zero field, GdPtBi is a zero-gap semiconductor with
quadratic bands. In a magnetic field, the Zeeman energy leads to Weyl nodes. We
have observed a large negative LMR with the field-steering properties specific
to the chiral anomaly. The chiral anomaly also induces strong suppression of
the thermopower. We report a detailed study of the thermoelectric response
function $\alpha_{xx}$ of Weyl fermions. The scheme of creating Weyl nodes from
quadratic bands suggests that the chiral anomaly may be observable in a broad
class of semimetals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07653</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07653</id><created>2016-02-24</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Amaral</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aschheim</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Irwin</keyname><forenames>Klee</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum walk on a spin network</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>Talk given at the Fourth International Conference on the Nature and
  Ontology of Spacetime, 30 May - 2 June 2016, Golden Sands, Varna, Bulgaria.
  And published as part of one chapter of the proceedings of the conference.
  Minkowski Institute Press, Montreal (Quebec, Canada). (2017)</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  We apply a discrete quantum walk from a quantum particle on a discrete
quantum spacetime from loop quantum gravity and show that the related
Entanglement Entropy can drive a entropic force. We apply this concepts to
propose a model of a walker position topologically encoded on a spin network.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02214</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02214</id><created>2016-04-07</created><updated>2016-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Furusawa</keyname><forenames>Hisanori</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kashikawa</keyname><forenames>Nobunari</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>Masakazu A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dunlop</keyname><forenames>James S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shimasaku</keyname><forenames>Kazuhiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takata</keyname><forenames>Tadafumi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sekiguchi</keyname><forenames>Kazuhiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naito</keyname><forenames>Yoshiaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Furusawa</keyname><forenames>Junko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ouchi</keyname><forenames>Masami</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakata</keyname><forenames>Fumiaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yasuda</keyname><forenames>Naoki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okura</keyname><forenames>Yuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taniguchi</keyname><forenames>Yoshiaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamada</keyname><forenames>Toru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kajisawa</keyname><forenames>Masaru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fynbo</keyname><forenames>Johan P. U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fevre</keyname><forenames>Olivier Le</forenames></author></authors><title>A New Constraint on the Ly$\alpha$ Fraction of UV Very Bright Galaxies
  at Redshift 7</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>20 pages, 7 figures, accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><journal-ref>ApJ, 822, 46 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/822/1/46</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the extent to which very bright (-23.0 &lt; MUV &lt; -21.75) Lyman-break
selected galaxies at redshifts z~7 display detectable Lya emission. To explore
this issue, we have obtained follow-up optical spectroscopy of 9 z~7 galaxies
from a parent sample of 24 z~7 galaxy candidates selected from the 1.65 sq.deg
COSMOS-UltraVISTA and SXDS-UDS survey fields using the latest near-infrared
public survey data, and new ultra-deep Subaru z'-band imaging (which we also
present and describe in this paper). Our spectroscopy has yielded only one
possible detection of Lya at z=7.168 with a rest-frame equivalent width EW_0 =
3.7 (+1.7/-1.1) Angstrom. The relative weakness of this line, combined with our
failure to detect Lya emission from the other spectroscopic targets allows us
to place a new upper limit on the prevalence of strong Lya emission at these
redshifts. For conservative calculation and to facilitate comparison with
previous studies at lower redshifts, we derive a 1-sigma upper limit on the
fraction of UV bright galaxies at z~7 that display EW_0 &gt; 50 Angstrom, which we
estimate to be &lt; 0.23. This result may indicate a weak trend where the fraction
of strong Lya emitters ceases to rise, and possibly falls between z~6 and z~7.
Our results also leave open the possibility that strong Lya may still be more
prevalent in the brightest galaxies in the reionization era than their fainter
counterparts. A larger spectroscopic sample of galaxies is required to derive a
more reliable constraint on the neutral hydrogen fraction at z~7 based on the
Lya fraction in the bright galaxies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02350</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02350</id><created>2016-04-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Laigle</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCracken</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ilbert</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hsieh</keyname><forenames>B. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davidzon</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Capak</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hasinger</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silverman</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pichon</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coupon</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aussel</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borgne</keyname><forenames>D. Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caputi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cassata</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Y. -Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Civano</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dunlop</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fynbo</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>kartaltepe</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koekemoer</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fevre</keyname><forenames>O. Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Floc'h</keyname><forenames>E. Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leauthaud</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lilly</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marchesi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Milvang-Jensen</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salvato</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanders</keyname><forenames>D. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scoville</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smolcic</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stockmann</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taniguchi</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tasca</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toft</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vaccari</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zabl</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>The COSMOS2015 Catalog: Exploring the 1&lt;z&lt;6 Universe with half a million
  galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><report-no>ApJS, 224, 24 (2016)</report-no><doi>10.3847/0067-0049/224/2/24</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the COSMOS2015 catalog which contains precise photometric
redshifts and stellar masses for more than half a million objects over the
2deg$^{2}$ COSMOS field. Including new $YJHK_{\rm s}$ images from the
UltraVISTA-DR2 survey, $Y$-band from Subaru/Hyper-Suprime-Cam and infrared data
from the Spitzer Large Area Survey with the Hyper-Suprime-Cam Spitzer legacy
program, this near-infrared-selected catalog is highly optimized for the study
of galaxy evolution and environments in the early Universe. To maximise catalog
completeness for bluer objects and at higher redshifts, objects have been
detected on a $\chi^{2}$ sum of the $YJHK_{\rm s}$ and $z^{++}$ images. The
catalog contains $\sim 6\times 10^5$ objects in the 1.5 deg$^{2}$
UltraVISTA-DR2 region, and $\sim 1.5\times 10^5$ objects are detected in the
&quot;ultra-deep stripes&quot; (0.62 deg$^{2}$) at $K_{\rm s}\leq 24.7$ (3$\sigma$, 3&quot;,
AB magnitude). Through a comparison with the zCOSMOS-bright spectroscopic
redshifts, we measure a photometric redshift precision of $\sigma_{\Delta
z/(1+z_s)}$ = 0.007 and a catastrophic failure fraction of $\eta=0.5$%. At
$3&lt;z&lt;6$, using the unique database of spectroscopic redshifts in COSMOS, we
find $\sigma_{\Delta z/(1+z_s)}$ = 0.021 and $\eta=13.2\% $. The deepest
regions reach a 90\% completeness limit of 10$^{10}M_\odot$ to $z=4$. Detailed
comparisons of the color distributions, number counts, and clustering show
excellent agreement with the literature in the same mass ranges. COSMOS2015
represents a unique, publicly available, valuable resource with which to
investigate the evolution of galaxies within their environment back to the
earliest stages of the history of the Universe. The COSMOS2015 catalog is
distributed via anonymous ftp
(ftp://ftp.iap.fr/pub/from_users/hjmcc/COSMOS2015/) and through the usual
astronomical archive systems (CDS, ESO Phase 3, IRSA).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.05652</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.05652</id><created>2016-04-19</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Chaobin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balu</keyname><forenames>Radhakrishnan</forenames></author></authors><title>Steady states of continuous-time open quantum walks</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Quantum Inf Process (2017) 16: 173</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11128-017-1625-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Continuous-time open quantum walks (CTOQW) are introduced as the formulation
of quantum dynamical semigroups of trace-preserving and completely positive
linear maps (or quantum Markov semigroups) on graphs. We show that a CTOQW
always converges to a steady state regardless of the initial state when a graph
is connected. When the graph is both connected and regular, it is shown that
the steady state is the maximally mixed state. As shown by the examples in this
article, the steady states of CTOQW can be very unusual and complicated even
though the underlying graphs are simple. The examples demonstrate that the
structure of a graph can affect quantum coherence in CTOQW through a long time
run. Precisely, the quantum coherence persists throughout the evolution of the
CTOQW when the underlying topology is certain irregular graphs (such as a path
or a star as shown in the examples). In contrast, the quantum coherence will
eventually vanish from the open quantum system when the underlying topology is
a regular graph (such as a cycle).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00835</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00835</id><created>2016-05-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Ellis</keyname><forenames>Matthew O. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fullerton</keyname><forenames>Eric E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chantrell</keyname><forenames>Roy W.</forenames></author></authors><title>All-optical switching in granular ferromagnets caused by magnetic
  circular dichroism</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>18 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6, 30522 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep30522</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magnetic recording using circularly polarized femto-second laser pulses is an
emerging technology that would allow write speeds much faster than existing
field driven methods. However, the mechanism that drives the magnetization
switching in ferromagnets is unclear. Recent theories suggest that the
interaction of the light with the magnetized media induces an opto-magnetic
field within the media, known as the inverse Faraday effect. Here we show that
an alternative mechanism, driven by thermal excitation over the anisotropy
energy barrier and a difference in the energy absorption depending on
polarization, can create a net magnetization over a series of laser pulses in
an ensemble of single domain grains. Only a small difference in the absorption
is required to reach magnetization levels observed experimentally and the model
does not preclude the role of the inverse Faraday effect but removes the
necessity that the opto-magnetic field is 10s of Tesla in strength.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01073</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01073</id><created>2016-05-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Milton</keyname><forenames>Kimball A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalauni</keyname><forenames>Pushpa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parashar</keyname><forenames>Prachi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu&#xe9;rout</keyname><forenames>Romain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ingold</keyname><forenames>Gert-Ludwig</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lambrecht</keyname><forenames>Astrid</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reynaud</keyname><forenames>Serge</forenames></author></authors><title>Negative Entropies in Casimir and Casimir-Polder Interactions</title><categories>quant-ph hep-th</categories><comments>8 pages, 12 figures, extended version of talk at Frontiers of Quantum
  and Mesoscopic Thermodynamics, Prague, 2015</comments><journal-ref>Fortschr. Phys. 65, 1600047 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/prop.201600047</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It has been increasingly becoming clear that Casimir and Casimir-Polder
entropies may be negative in certain regions of temperature and separation. In
fact, the occurrence of negative entropy seems to be a nearly ubiquitous
phenomenon. This is most highlighted in the quantum vacuum interaction of a
nanoparticle with a conducting plate or between two nanoparticles. It has been
argued that this phenomenon does not violate physical intuition, since the
total entropy, including the self-entropies of the plate and the nanoparticle,
should be positive. New calculations, in fact, seem to bear this out at least
in certain cases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03371</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03371</id><created>2016-05-11</created><updated>2017-02-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Prada</keyname><forenames>Marta</forenames></author></authors><title>The geometric phase of Z$_n$- and T-symmetric nanomagnets as a
  classification toolkit</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, Article number: 46614 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep46614</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive the general form of the non-trivial geometric phase resulting from
the unique combination of point group and time reversal symmetries. This phase
arises e.g. when a magnetic adatom is adsorbed on a non-magnetic C$_n$ crystal
surface, where $n$ denotes the fold of the principal axis. The energetic
ordering and the relevant quantum numbers of the eigenstates are entirely
determined by this quantity. Moreover, this phase allows to conveniently
predict the protection mechanism of any prepared state, shedding light onto a
large number of experiments and allowing a classification scheme. Owing to its
robustness this geometric phase also has great relevance for a large number of
applications in quantum computing, where topologically protected states bearing
long relaxation times are highly desired.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03420</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03420</id><created>2016-05-11</created><updated>2017-04-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dambach</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kubala</keyname><forenames>Bj&#xf6;rn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ankerhold</keyname><forenames>Joachim</forenames></author></authors><title>Time-resolved statistics of photon pairs in two-cavity Josephson
  photonics</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 7 figures; invited contribution to special volume &quot;FQMT'15:
  Frontiers of Quantum and Mesoscopic Thermodynamics (Prague, Czech Republic,
  27 July - 1 August 2015)&quot;</comments><journal-ref>Fortschr. Phys. 65, 1600061 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/prop.201600061</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the creation and emission of pairs of highly nonclassical
microwave photons in a setup where a voltage-biased Josephson junction is
connected in series to two electromagnetic oscillators. Tuning the external
voltage such that the Josephson frequency equals the sum of the two mode
frequencies, each tunneling Cooper pair creates one additional photon in both
of the two oscillators. The time-resolved statistics of photon emission events
from the two oscillators is investigated by means of single- and
cross-oscillator variants of the second-order correlation function
$g^{(2)}(\tau)$ and the waiting-time distribution $w(\tau)$. They provide
insight into the strongly correlated quantum dynamics of the two oscillator
subsystems and reveal a rich variety of quantum features of light including
strong antibunching and the presence of negative values in the Wigner function.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05787</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05787</id><created>2016-05-18</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Chenglong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gamba</keyname><forenames>Irene M.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Conservative Scheme for Vlasov Poisson Landau modeling collisional
  plasmas</title><categories>physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>To appear in Jour. Comp. Physics</comments><doi>10.1016/j.jcp.2017.03.046</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have developed a deterministic conservative solver for the inhomogeneous
Fokker-Planck-Landau equation coupled with the Poisson equation, which is a
{classical mean-field} primary model for collisional plasmas. Two subproblems,
i.e. the Vlasov-Poisson problem and homogeneous Landau problem, are obtained
through time-splitting methods, and treated separately by the Runge-Kutta
Discontinuous Galerkin method and a conservative spectral method, respectively.
To ensure conservation when projecting between the two different computing
grids, a special conservation routine is designed to link the solutions of
these two subproblems. This conservation routine accurately enforces
conservation of moments in Fourier space. The entire numerical scheme is
implemented with parallelization with hybrid MPI and OpenMP. Numerical
experiments are provided to study linear and nonlinear Landau Damping problems
and two-stream flow problem as well.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00596</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00596</id><created>2016-07-03</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bambi</keyname><forenames>Cosimo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cardenas-Avendano</keyname><forenames>Alejandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dauser</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garcia</keyname><forenames>Javier A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nampalliwar</keyname><forenames>Sourabh</forenames></author></authors><title>Testing the Kerr black hole hypothesis using X-ray reflection
  spectroscopy</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>19 pages, 12 figures. v2: refereed version</comments><journal-ref>Astrophys.J. 842: 76 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa74c0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the first X-ray reflection model for testing the assumption that
the metric of astrophysical black holes is described by the Kerr solution. We
employ the formalism of the transfer function proposed by Cunningham. The
calculations of the reflection spectrum of a thin accretion disk are split into
two parts: the calculation of the transfer function and the calculation of the
local spectrum at any emission point in the disk. The transfer function only
depends on the background metric and takes into account all the relativistic
effects (gravitational redshift, Doppler boosting, and light bending). Our code
computes the transfer function for a spacetime described by the Johannsen
metric and can easily be extended to any stationary, axisymmetric, and
asymptotically flat spacetime. Transfer functions and single line shapes in the
Kerr metric are compared with those calculated from existing codes to check
that we reach the necessary accuracy. We also simulate some observations with
NuSTAR and LAD/eXTP and fit the data with our new model to show the potential
capabilities of current and future observations to constrain possible
deviations from the Kerr metric.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06000</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06000</id><created>2016-08-21</created><updated>2016-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chess</keyname><forenames>Jordan J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Montoya</keyname><forenames>Sergio A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harvey</keyname><forenames>Tyler R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ophus</keyname><forenames>Colin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Couture</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lomakin</keyname><forenames>Vitaliy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fullerton</keyname><forenames>Eric E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McMorran</keyname><forenames>Benjamin J.</forenames></author></authors><title>A streamlined approach to mapping the magnetic induction of skyrmionic
  materials</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1016/j.ultramic.2017.02.004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, Lorentz transmission electron microscopy (LTEM) has helped
researchers advance the emerging field of magnetic skyrmions. These magnetic
quasi-particles, composed of topologically non-trivial magnetization textures,
have a large potential for application as information carriers in low-power
memory and logic devices. LTEM is one of a very few techniques for direct real
space imaging of magnetic features at the nanoscale. For Fresnel-contrast LTEM,
the transport of intensity equation (TIE) is the tool of choice for
quantitative reconstruction of the local magnetic induction through the sample
thickness. Typically this analysis requires collection of at least three
images.Here we show that for uniform thin magnetic films which includes many
skyrmionic samples, the magnetic induction can be quantitatively determined
from a single defocused image using a simplified TIE approach.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08404</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08404</id><created>2016-08-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Krogager</keyname><forenames>J. -K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fynbo</keyname><forenames>J. P. U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heintz</keyname><forenames>K. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geier</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ledoux</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xf8;ller</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noterdaeme</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Venemans</keyname><forenames>B. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vestergaard</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>The extended High A(V) Quasar Survey: Searching for dusty absorbers
  toward mid-infrared selected quasars</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>45 pages containing a large set of 100 figures and 2 long tables.
  Accepted for publication in ApJS</comments><journal-ref>ApJ, 832, 49 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/832/1/49</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the results of a new spectroscopic survey for dusty intervening
absorption systems, particularly damped Ly$\alpha$ absorbers (DLAs), towards
reddened quasars. The candidate quasars are selected from mid-infrared
photometry from the Wide-field Infrared Survey Explorer combined with optical
and near-infrared photometry. Out of 1073 candidates, we secure low-resolution
spectra for 108 using the Nordic Optical Telescope on La Palma, Spain. Based on
the spectra, we are able to classify 100 of the 108 targets as quasars. A large
fraction (50 %) is observed to have broad absorption lines (BALs). Moreover, we
find 6 quasars with strange breaks in their spectra, which are not consistent
with regular dust reddening. Using template fitting we infer the amount of
reddening along each line of sight ranging from A(V)$\approx$0.1 mag to 1.2 mag
(assuming an SMC extinction curve). In four cases, the reddening is consistent
with dust exhibiting the 2175{\AA} feature caused by an intervening absorber,
and for two of these, a MgII absorption system is observed at the best-fit
absorption redshift. In the rest of the cases, the reddening is most likely
intrinsic to the quasar. We observe no evidence for dusty DLAs in this survey.
However, the large fraction of BAL quasars hampers the detection of absorption
systems. Out of the 50 non-BAL quasars only 28 have sufficiently high redshift
to detect Ly$\alpha$ in absorption.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00937</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00937</id><created>2016-09-04</created><updated>2016-10-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bassauer</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r Kernphysik, Technische Universit&#xe4;t Darmstadt</affiliation></author><author><keyname>von Neumann-Cosel</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames><affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r Kernphysik, Technische Universit&#xe4;t Darmstadt</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tamii</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Research Center for Nuclear Physics, Osaka University</affiliation></author></authors><title>Gamma strength function and level density of $^{208}$Pb from
  forward-angle proton scattering at 295 MeV</title><categories>nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>7 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 94, 054313 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.054313</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Gamma strength functions (GSFs) and level densities (LDs) are essential
ingredients of statistical nuclear reaction theory with many applications in
astrophysics, reactor design, and waste transmutation. The aim of the present
work is a test of systematic parametrizations of the GSF recommended by the
RIPL-3 data base for the case of $^{208}$Pb. The upward GSF and LD in
$^{208}$Pb are compared to gamma decay data from an Oslo-type experiment to
examine the validity of the Brink-Axel (BA) hypothesis. The E1 and M1 parts of
the total GSF are determined from high-resolution forward angle inelastic
proton scattering data taken at 295 MeV at RCNP, Osaka, Japan. The total LD in
$^{208}$Pb is derived from the $1^-$ LD extracted with a fluctuation analysis
in the energy region of the isovector giant dipole resonance. The E1 GSF is
compared to parametrizations recommended by the RIPL-3 data base showing
systematic deficiencies of all models in the energy region around neutron
threshold. The new data for the poorly known spinflip M1 resonance call for a
substantial revision of the model suggested in RIPL-3. The total GSF derived
from the present data is larger in the PDR energy region than the Oslo data but
the strong fluctuations due to the low LD resulting from the double shell
closure of $^{208}$Pb prevent a conclusion on a possible violation of the BA
hypothesis. Using the parameters suggested by RIPL-3 for a description of the
LD in $^{208}$Pb with the back-shifted Fermi gas model, remarkable agreement
between the two experiments spanning a wide excitation energy range is
obtained. Systematic parametrizations of the E1 and M1 GSF parts need to be
reconsidered at low excitation energies. The good agreement of LD provides an
independent confirmation of the approach underlying the decomposition of GSF
and LDs in Oslo-type experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02412</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02412</id><created>2016-09-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Clark</keyname><forenames>Lewis A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stokes</keyname><forenames>Adam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khan</keyname><forenames>M. Mubashir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Gangcheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beige</keyname><forenames>Almut</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum-enhanced metrology without entanglement based on optical
  cavities with feedback</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures, IEEE conference proceedings</comments><journal-ref>PHOTOPTICS conference proceedings, p. 223 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There are a number of different strategies to measure the phase shift between
two pathways of light more efficiently than suggested by the standard quantum
limit. One way is to use highly entangled photons. Another way is to expose
photons to a non-linear or interacting Hamiltonian. This paper emphasises that
the conditional dynamics of open quantum systems provides an interesting
additional tool for quantum-enhanced metrology. As a concrete example, we
review a recent scheme which exploits the conditional dynamics of a
laser-driven optical cavity with spontaneous photon emission inside a quantum
feedback loop. Deducing information from second-order photon correlation
measurements requires neither optical non-linearities nor entangled photons and
should therefore be of immediate practical interest.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01844</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01844</id><created>2016-10-06</created><updated>2016-10-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>S&#xe1;nchez-Ram&#xed;rez</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hancock</keyname><forenames>P. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>J&#xf3;hannesson</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murphy</keyname><forenames>Tara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Postigo</keyname><forenames>A. de Ugarte</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorosabel</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kann</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kr&#xfc;hler</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oates</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Japelj</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Th&#xf6;ne</keyname><forenames>C. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lundgren</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perley</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malesani</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Monsalvo</keyname><forenames>I. de Gregorio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Castro-Tirado</keyname><forenames>A. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Elia</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fynbo</keyname><forenames>J. P. U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garcia-Appadoo</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldoni</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greiner</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Y. -D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jel&#xed;nek</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jeong</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamble</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klose</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuin</keyname><forenames>N. P. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Llorente</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mart&#xed;n</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guelbenzu</keyname><forenames>A. Nicuesa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rossi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schady</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sparre</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sudilovsky</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tello</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Updike</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiersema</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>B. -B.</forenames></author></authors><title>GRB 110715A: The peculiar multiwavelength evolution of the first
  afterglow detected by ALMA</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS, 464, 4624 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2608</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the extensive follow-up campaign on the afterglow of GRB 110715A
at 17 different wavelengths, from X-ray to radio bands, starting 81 seconds
after the burst and extending up to 74 days later. We performed for the first
time a GRB afterglow observation with the ALMA observatory. We find that the
afterglow of GRB 110715A is very bright at optical and radio wavelengths. We
use optical and near infrared spectroscopy to provide further information about
the progenitor's environment and its host galaxy. The spectrum shows weak
absorption features at a redshift z = 0.8225, which reveal a host galaxy
environment with low ionization, column density and dynamical activity. Late
deep imaging shows a very faint galaxy, consistent with the spectroscopic
results. The broadband afterglow emission is modelled with synchrotron
radiation using a numerical algorithm and we determine the best fit parameters
using Bayesian inference in order to constrain the physical parameters of the
jet and the medium in which the relativistic shock propagates. We fitted our
data with a variety of models, including different density profiles and energy
injections. Although the general behaviour can be roughly described by these
models, none of them are able to fully explain all data points simultaneously.
GRB 110715A shows the complexity of reproducing extensive multi-wavelength
broadband afterglow observations, and the need of good sampling in wavelength
and time and more complex models to accurately constrain the physics of GRB
afterglows.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.02025</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.02025</id><created>2016-10-06</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Flacke</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frugiuele</keyname><forenames>Claudia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fuchs</keyname><forenames>Elina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>Rick S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perez</keyname><forenames>Gilad</forenames></author></authors><title>Phenomenology of relaxion-Higgs mixing</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>46 pages, 6 figures, v3: typos fixed, references added, version
  matches the version published in JHEP</comments><report-no>CTPU-16-25</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1706 (2017) 050</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP06(2017)050</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the relaxion generically stops its rolling at a point that
breaks CP leading to relaxion-Higgs mixing. This opens the door to a variety of
observational probes since the possible relaxion mass spans a broad range from
sub-eV to the GeV scale. We derive constraints from current experiments (fifth
force, astrophysical and cosmological probes, beam dump, flavour, LEP and LHC)
and present projections from future experiments such as NA62, SHiP and PIXIE.
We find that a large region of the parameter space is already under the
experimental scrutiny. All the experimental constraints we derive are equally
applicable for general Higgs portal models. In addition, we show that simple
multiaxion (clockwork) UV completions suffer from a mild fine tuning problem,
which increases with the number of sites. These results favour a cut-off scale
lower than the existing theoretical bounds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03832</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03832</id><created>2016-10-12</created><updated>2016-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Asenbaum</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Overstreet</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kovachy</keyname><forenames>Tim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Daniel D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hogan</keyname><forenames>Jason M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kasevich</keyname><forenames>Mark A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase shift in atom interferometry due to spacetime curvature</title><categories>physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures, Supplemental material</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 183602 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.183602</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a single-source dual atom interferometer and utilize it as a
gradiometer for precise gravitational measurements. The macroscopic separation
between interfering atomic wave packets (as large as 16 cm) reveals the
interplay of recoil effects and gravitational curvature from a nearby Pb source
mass. The gradiometer baseline is set by the laser wavelength and pulse
timings, which can be measured to high precision. Using a long drift time and
large momentum transfer atom optics, the gradiometer reaches a resolution of $3
\times 10^{-9}$ s$^{-2}$ per shot and measures a 1 rad phase shift induced by
the source mass.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04230</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04230</id><created>2016-10-13</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mizera</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author></authors><title>Inverse of the String Theory KLT Kernel</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>25 pages, published version, Mathematica notebook attached</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1706 (2017) 084</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP06(2017)084</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The field theory Kawai-Lewellen-Tye (KLT) kernel, which relates scattering
amplitudes of gravitons and gluons, turns out to be the inverse of a matrix
whose components are bi-adjoint scalar partial amplitudes. In this note we
propose an analogous construction for the string theory KLT kernel. We present
simple diagrammatic rules for the computation of the $\alpha'$-corrected
bi-adjoint scalar amplitudes that are exact in $\alpha'$. We find compact
expressions in terms of graphs, where the standard Feynman propagators $1/p^2$
are replaced by either $1/\sin (\pi \alpha' p^2/2)$ or $1/\tan (\pi \alpha'
p^2/2)$, as determined by a recursive procedure. We demonstrate how the same
object can be used to conveniently expand open string partial amplitudes in a
BCJ basis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.06980</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.06980</id><created>2016-10-21</created><updated>2016-11-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>Alan C.</forenames></author></authors><title>The IBM Quantum Computer and the IBM Quantum Experience</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures. Didactic text in Portuguese. V2: Minor
  corrections and additional references</comments><journal-ref>Rev. Bras. Ens. Fis. 39(1), e1301 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1590/1806-9126-RBEF-2016-0155</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The announcement of a quantum computer that can be accessed remotely by
anyone from its laptop is a big event for the quantum computation scientist. In
this work we present the International Business Machines (IBM) quantum computer
and its platform IBM Quantum Experience (IBM-QE) as a didactic proposal in
quantum computation and information. In addition we also consider this paper as
scientific divulgation of the IMB advertisement. In this paper we show the main
tool (quantum gates) present in the IBM-QE and, through a simple strategy, we
discuss about a possible decoherence source in the IBM 5 q-bit chips. As an
example of application of our study, we show how to implement the quantum
teleportation using the IBM-QE.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.07744</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.07744</id><created>2016-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Sommer-Larsen</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>Dark Cosmology Centre, NBI, Univ. of Copenhagen</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Fynbo</keyname><forenames>J. P. U.</forenames><affiliation>Dark Cosmology Centre, NBI, Univ. of Copenhagen</affiliation></author></authors><title>The galaxy counterpart of the high-metallicity and 16 kpc impact
  parameter DLA towards Q0918+1636 - a challenge to galaxy formation models?</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>22 pages, 24 figures, MNRAS in press</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS, 464, 2441 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2532</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quasar Q0918+1636 (z=3.07) has an intervening high-metallicity Damped
Lyman-alpha Absorber (DLA) along the line of sight, at a redshift of z=2.58.
The DLA is located at a large impact parameter of 16.2 kpc, and has an almost
solar metallicity. It is shown, that a novel type of cosmological galaxy
formation models, invoking a new SNII feedback prescription, the Haardt &amp; Madau
(2012) UVB field and explicit treatment of UVB self-shielding, can reproduce
the observed characteristics of the DLA. UV radiation from young stellar
populations in the galaxy, in particular in the photon energy range 10.36-13.61
eV (relating to Sulfur II abundance), are also considered in the analysis. It
is found that a) for L~L* galaxies (at z=2.58), about 10% of the sight-lines
through the galaxies at impact parameter 16.2 kpc will display a Sulfur II
column density N(SII)$&gt;$ 10$^{15.82}$ cm$^{-2}$ (the observed value for the
DLA), and b) considering only cases where a near-solar metallicity will be
detected at 16.2 kpc impact parameter, the probability distribution of galaxy
SFR peaks near the value observed for the DLA galaxy counterpart of ~27
Msun/yr. It is argued, that the bulk of the alpha-elements, like Sulfur, traced
by the high metal column density, b=16.2 kpc absorption lines, were produced by
evolving young stars in the inner galaxy, and later transported outward by
galactic winds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.09273</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.09273</id><created>2016-10-28</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Khantoul</keyname><forenames>Boubakeur</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bounames</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maamache</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the invariant method for the time-dependent non-Hermitian
  Hamiltonians</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. Plus (2017) 132: 258</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjp/i2017-11524-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a scheme to deal with certain time-dependent non-Hermitian
Hamiltonian operators $H(t)$ that generate a real phase in their
time-evolution. This involves the use of invariant operators $I_{PH}(t)$ that
are pseudo-Hermitian with respect to the time-dependent metric operator, which
implies that the dynamics is governed by unitary time evolution. Furthermore,
$H(t)$ is not generally quasi-Hermitian and does not define an observable of
the system but $I_{PH}(t)$ obeys a quasi-hermiticity transformation as in the
completely time-independent Hamiltonian systems case. The harmonic oscillator
with a time-dependent frequency under the action of a complex time-dependent
linear potential is considered as an illustrative example.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00581</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00581</id><created>2016-12-02</created><updated>2017-06-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dinani</keyname><forenames>Hossein T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berry</keyname><forenames>Dominic W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Adaptive estimation of a time-varying phase with a power-law spectrum
  via continuous squeezed states</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, comments welcome</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 063821 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.063821</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  When measuring a time-varying phase, the standard quantum limit and
Heisenberg limit as usually defined, for a constant phase, do not apply. If the
phase has Gaussian statistics and a power-law spectrum $1/|\omega|^p$ with
$p&gt;1$, then the generalized standard quantum limit and Heisenberg limit have
recently been found to have scalings of $1/{\cal N}^{(p-1)/p}$ and $1/{\cal
N}^{2(p-1)/(p+1)}$, respectively, where ${\cal N}$ is the mean photon flux. We
show that this Heisenberg scaling can be achieved via adaptive measurements on
squeezed states. We predict the experimental parameters analytically, and test
them with numerical simulations. Previous work had considered the special case
of $p=2$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03972</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03972</id><created>2016-12-12</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dzsaber</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prochaska</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sidorenko</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eguchi</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Svagera</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Waas</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prokofiev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Si</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paschen</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Kondo Insulator to Semimetal Transformation Tuned by Spin-Orbit Coupling</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures plus Supplemental Material</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 246601 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.246601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent theoretical studies of topologically nontrivial electronic states in
Kondo insulators have pointed to the importance of spin-orbit coupling (SOC)
for stabilizing these states. However, systematic experimental studies that
tune the SOC parameter $\lambda_{\rm{SOC}}$ in Kondo insulators remain elusive.
The main reason is that variations of (chemical) pressure or doping strongly
influence the Kondo coupling $J_{\text{K}}$ and the chemical potential $\mu$ --
both essential parameters determining the ground state of the material -- and
thus possible $\lambda_{\rm{SOC}}$ tuning effects have remained unnoticed. Here
we present the successful growth of the substitution series
Ce$_3$Bi$_4$(Pt$_{1-x}$Pd$_x$)$_3$ ($0 \le x \le 1$) of the archetypal
(noncentrosymmetric) Kondo insulator Ce$_3$Bi$_4$Pt$_3$. The Pt-Pd substitution
is isostructural, isoelectronic, and isosize, and therefore likely to leave
$J_{\text{K}}$ and $\mu$ essentially unchanged. By contrast, the large mass
difference between the $5d$ element Pt and the $4d$ element Pd leads to a large
difference in $\lambda_{\rm{SOC}}$, which thus is the dominating tuning
parameter in the series. Surprisingly, with increasing $x$ (decreasing
$\lambda_{\rm{SOC}}$), we observe a Kondo insulator to semimetal transition,
demonstrating an unprecedented drastic influence of the SOC. The fully
substituted end compound Ce$_3$Bi$_4$Pd$_3$ shows thermodynamic signatures of a
recently predicted Weyl-Kondo semimetal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04781</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04781</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Chao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rubel</keyname><forenames>Oleg</forenames></author></authors><title>Ionization energy as a stability criterion for halide perovskites</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures, 3 tables</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Chem. C, 121 (22), pp 11977-11984 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jpcc.7b00333</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Instability of hybrid organic-inorganic halide perovskites hinders their
development for photovoltaic applications. First-principle calculations are
used for evaluation of a decomposition reaction enthalpy of hybrid halide
perovskites, which is linked to experimentally observed degradation of device
characteristics. However, simple criteria for predicting stability of halide
perovskites are lacking since Goldschmidt's tolerance and octahedral
geometrical factors do not fully capture formability of those perovskites. In
this paper, we extend the Born-Haber cycle to partition the reaction enthalpy
of various perovskite structures into lattice, ionization, and molecularization
energy components. The analysis of various contributions to the reaction
enthalpy points to an ionization energy of a molecule and a cage as an
additional criterion for predicting chemical trends in stability of hybrid
halide perovskites. Prospects of finding new perovskite structures with
improved chemical stability aimed for photovoltaic applications are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.06374</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.06374</id><created>2016-12-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Belov</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nazarov</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sorokin</keyname><forenames>A. O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Determination of CFT central charge by the Wang-Landau algorithm</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>8 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 95, 063308 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.063308</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a simple method to estimate the central charge of the conformal
field theory corresponding to a critical point of a two-dimensional lattice
model from Monte Carlo simulations. The main idea is to use the Wang-Landau
flat-histogram algorithm, which allows us to obtain the free energy of a
lattice model on a torus as a function of torus radii. The central charge is
calculated with a good precision from a free energy scaling at the critical
point. We apply the method to the Ising, tricritical Ising (Blume-Capel), Potts
and site-diluted Ising models, and also discuss estimation of conformal
weights.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08053</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08053</id><created>2016-12-23</created><updated>2017-06-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tresp</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Menke</keyname><forenames>Henri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Urvoy</keyname><forenames>Alban</forenames></author><author><keyname>Firstenberg</keyname><forenames>Ofer</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#xfc;chler</keyname><forenames>Hans Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hofferberth</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author></authors><title>Tutorial: Calculation of Rydberg interaction potentials</title><categories>quant-ph physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>accepted in J. Phys. B</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. B: At. Mol. Opt. Phys. 50, 133001 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6455/aa743a</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The strong interaction between individual Rydberg atoms provides a powerful
tool exploited in an ever-growing range of applications in quantum information
science, quantum simulation, and ultracold chemistry. One hallmark of the
Rydberg interaction is that both its strength and angular dependence can be
fine-tuned with great flexibility by choosing appropriate Rydberg states and
applying external electric and magnetic fields. More and more experiments are
probing this interaction at short atomic distances or with such high precision
that perturbative calculations as well as restrictions to the leading
dipole-dipole interaction term are no longer sufficient. In this tutorial, we
review all relevant aspects of the full calculation of Rydberg interaction
potentials. We discuss the derivation of the interaction Hamiltonian from the
electrostatic multipole expansion, numerical and analytical methods for
calculating the required electric multipole moments, and the inclusion of
electromagnetic fields with arbitrary direction. We focus specifically on
symmetry arguments and selection rules, which greatly reduce the size of the
Hamiltonian matrix, enabling the direct diagonalization of the Hamiltonian up
to higher multipole orders on a desktop computer. Finally, we present example
calculations showing the relevance of the full interaction calculation to
current experiments. Our software for calculating Rydberg potentials including
all features discussed in this tutorial is available as open source.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00414</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00414</id><created>2017-01-02</created><updated>2017-06-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Boiss&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>A</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berthet</keyname><forenames>G</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fouch&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>L</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salomon</keyname><forenames>G</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aspect</keyname><forenames>S</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lepoutre</keyname><forenames>S</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bourdel</keyname><forenames>T</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlinear scattering of atomic bright solitons in disorder</title><categories>physics.atom-ph cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><report-no>LCF-OA</report-no><journal-ref>Europhysics Letters, 117 (1), pp.10007 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We observe nonlinear scattering of 39 K atomic bright solitons launched in a
one-dimensional (1D) speckle disorder. We directly compare it with the
scattering of non-interacting particles in the same disorder. The atoms in the
soliton tend to be collectively either reflected or transmitted, in contrast
with the behavior of independent particles, thus demonstrating a clear
nonlinear effect in scattering. The observed strong fluctuations in the
reflected fraction, between zero and 100%, are interpreted as a consequence of
the strong sensitivity of the system to the experimental conditions and in
particular to the soliton velocity. This behavior is reproduced in a mean-field
framework by Gross-Pitaevskii simulations, and mesoscopic quantum
superpositions of the soliton being fully reflected and fully transmitted are
not expected for our parameters. We discuss the conditions for observing such
superpositions, which would find applications in atom interferometry beyond the
standard quantum limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04307</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04307</id><created>2017-01-16</created><updated>2017-06-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Houri</keyname><forenames>Tsuyoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakamoto</keyname><forenames>Makoto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tatsumi</keyname><forenames>Kentaro</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectral intertwining relations in exactly solvable quantum-mechanical
  systems</title><categories>quant-ph gr-qc hep-th nlin.SI</categories><comments>13 pages and 5 figures, published version</comments><report-no>KOBE-COSMO-16-14, KOBE-TH-16-08</report-no><journal-ref>Prog . Theor. Exp. Phys. (2017) 063A01</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/ptep/ptx074</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In exactly solvable quantum-mechanical systems, ladder and intertwining
operators play a central role because, if they are found, the energy spectra
can be obtained algebraically. In this paper, we propose the spectral
intertwining relation as a unified relation of ladder and intertwining
operators in a way that can depend on the energy eigenvalues. It is shown that
the spectral intertwining relations can connect eigenfunctions of different
energy eigenvalues belonging to two different Hamiltonians, which cannot be
obtained by previously known structures such as shape invariance. As an
application, we find new spectral intertwining operators for the Hamiltonians
of the hydrogen atom and the Rosen--Morse potential.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04406</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04406</id><created>2017-01-16</created><updated>2017-06-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cholis</keyname><forenames>Ilias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hooper</keyname><forenames>Dan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Linden</keyname><forenames>Tim</forenames></author></authors><title>Possible Evidence for the Stochastic Acceleration of Secondary
  Antiprotons by Supernova Remnants</title><categories>astro-ph.HE hep-ph physics.space-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures and 4 tables. Changes in v2: extended discussion
  on the method, title and some text revisions, all in agreement with final
  published PRD version. Results unchanged</comments><report-no>FERMILAB-PUB-17-010-A</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 123007 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.123007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The antiproton-to-proton ratio in the cosmic-ray spectrum is a sensitive
probe of new physics. Using recent measurements of the cosmic-ray antiproton
and proton fluxes in the energy range of 1-1000 GeV, we study the contribution
to the $\bar{p}/p$ ratio from secondary antiprotons that are produced and
subsequently accelerated within individual supernova remnants. We consider
several well-motivated models for cosmic-ray propagation in the interstellar
medium and marginalize our results over the uncertainties related to the
antiproton production cross section and the time-, charge-, and
energy-dependent effects of solar modulation. We find that the increase in the
$\bar{p}/p$ ratio observed at rigidities above $\sim$ 100 GV cannot be
accounted for within the context of conventional cosmic-ray propagation models,
but is consistent with scenarios in which cosmic-ray antiprotons are produced
and subsequently accelerated by shocks within a given supernova remnant. In
light of this, the acceleration of secondary cosmic rays in supernova remnants
is predicted to substantially contribute to the cosmic-ray positron spectrum,
accounting for a significant fraction of the observed positron excess.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04638</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04638</id><created>2017-01-17</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Borgani</keyname><forenames>Riccardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thor&#xe9;n</keyname><forenames>Per-Anders</forenames></author><author><keyname>Forchheimer</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dobryden</keyname><forenames>Illia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sah</keyname><forenames>Si Mohamed</forenames></author><author><keyname>Claesson</keyname><forenames>Per Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haviland</keyname><forenames>David B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Background force compensation in dynamic atomic force microscopy</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Author prepared version of a manuscript published at Physical Review
  Applied. Published by the American Physical Society under the terms of the
  Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International license. Further distribution
  of this work must maintain attribution to the author(s) and the published
  article's title, journal citation, and DOI</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Applied 7, 64018 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevApplied.7.064018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Background forces are linear long-range interactions of the cantilever body
with its surroundings that must be compensated for in order to reveal
tip-surface force, the quantity of interest for determining material properties
in atomic force microscopy. We provide a mathematical derivation of a method to
compensate for background forces, apply it to experimental data, and discuss
how to include background forces in simulation. Our method, based on
linear-response theory in the frequency domain, provides a general way of
measuring and compensating for any background force and it can be readily
applied to different force reconstruction methods in dynamic AFM.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05925</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05925</id><created>2017-01-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Lyman</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levan</keyname><forenames>A. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanvir</keyname><forenames>N. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fynbo</keyname><forenames>J. P. U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McGuire</keyname><forenames>J. T. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perley</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Angus</keyname><forenames>C. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bloom</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Conselice</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fruchter</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hjorth</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jakobsson</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Starling</keyname><forenames>R. L. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>The host galaxies and explosion sites of long-duration gamma ray bursts:
  Hubble Space Telescope near-infrared imaging</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>26 pages, accepted to MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS, 467, 1795 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx220</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the results of a Hubble Space Telescope WFC3/F160W SNAPSHOT sur-
vey of the host galaxies of 39 long-duration gamma-ray bursts (LGRBs) at z &lt; 3.
We have non-detections of hosts at the locations of 4 bursts. Sufficient
accuracy to as- trometrically align optical afterglow images and determine the
location of the LGRB within its host was possible for 31/35 detected hosts. In
agreement with other work, we find the luminosity distribution of LGRB hosts is
significantly fainter than that of a star formation rate-weighted field galaxy
sample over the same redshift range, indicating LGRBs are not unbiasedly
tracing the star formation rate. Morphologi- cally, the sample of LGRB hosts
are dominated by spiral-like or irregular galaxies. We find evidence for
evolution of the population of LGRB hosts towards lower-luminosity, higher
concentrated hosts at lower redshifts. Their half-light radii are consistent
with other LGRB host samples where measurements were made on rest-frame UV
obser- vations. In agreement with recent work, we find their 80 per cent
enclosed flux radii distribution to be more extended than previously thought,
making them intermedi- ate between core-collapse supernova (CCSN) and
super-luminous supernova (SLSN) hosts. The galactocentric projected-offset
distribution confirms LGRBs as centrally concentrated, much more so than CCSNe
and similar to SLSNe. LGRBs are strongly biased towards the brighter regions in
their host light distributions, regardless of their offset. We find a
correlation between the luminosity of the LGRB explosion site and the intrinsic
column density, N_H , towards the burst.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.06499</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.06499</id><created>2017-01-19</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xiyun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pikovsky</keyname><forenames>Arkady</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Zonghua</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics of oscillators globally coupled via two mean fields</title><categories>nlin.CD</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many studies of synchronization properties of coupled oscillators, based on
the classical Kuramoto approach, focus on ensembles coupled via a mean field.
Here we introduce a setup of Kuramoto-type phase oscillators coupled via two
mean fields. We derive stability properties of the incoherent state and find
traveling wave solutions with different locking patterns; stability properties
of these waves are found numerically. Mostly nontrivial states appear when the
two fields compete, i.e. one tends to synchronize oscillators while the other
one desynchronizes them. Here we identify normal branches which bifurcate from
the incoherent state in a usual way, and anomalous branches, appearance of
which cannot be described as a bifurcation. Furthermore, hybrid branches
combining properties of both are described. In the situations where no stable
traveling wave exists, modulated quasiperiodic in time dynamics is observed.
Our results indicate that a competition between two coupling channels can lead
to a complex system behavior, providing a potential generalized framework for
understanding of complex phenomena in natural oscillatory systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07233</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07233</id><created>2017-01-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Grabowska</keyname><forenames>Katarzyna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grabowski</keyname><forenames>Janusz</forenames></author></authors><title>Remarks on generalized Lie algebroids and related concepts</title><categories>math.DG math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>9 pages</comments><msc-class>17B66, 53D17, 17B66, 53D17, 22A22, 53C15, 70G45, 70H33, 70S05</msc-class><journal-ref>J. Math. Phys. 58 (2017), no. 2, 023505, 7 pp</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4975703</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove that &quot;generalized Lie algebroid&quot;, a geometric object which appeared
recently in the literature, is a misconception.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.08117</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.08117</id><created>2017-01-27</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dian</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames><affiliation>Hungarian Academy of Sciences, Centre for Energy Research, Budapest, Hungary</affiliation><affiliation>European Spallation Source ESS ERIC, Lund, Sweden</affiliation><affiliation>Budapest University of Technology and Economics, Institute of Nuclear Techniques, Budapest, Hungary</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kanaki</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames><affiliation>European Spallation Source ESS ERIC, Lund, Sweden</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hall-Wilton</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames><affiliation>European Spallation Source ESS ERIC, Lund, Sweden</affiliation><affiliation>Mid-Sweden University, Sundsvall, Sweden</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Zagyvai</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames><affiliation>Hungarian Academy of Sciences, Centre for Energy Research, Budapest, Hungary</affiliation><affiliation>Budapest University of Technology and Economics, Institute of Nuclear Techniques, Budapest, Hungary</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Czifrus</keyname><forenames>Sz.</forenames><affiliation>Budapest University of Technology and Economics, Institute of Nuclear Techniques, Budapest, Hungary</affiliation></author></authors><title>Neutron activation and prompt gamma intensity in Ar/CO$_{2}$-filled
  neutron detectors at the European Spallation Source</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>38 pages, LaTeX; formal changes: minor restructuring of Section 1 and
  2; new references added, typos corrected; Figure 2 slightly modified for
  better visibility</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Monte Carlo simulations using MCNP6.1 were performed to study the effect of
neutron activation in Ar/CO$_{2}$ neutron detector counting gas. A general MCNP
model was built and validated with simple analytical calculations. Simulations
and calculations agree that only the $^{40}$Ar activation can have a
considerable effect. It was shown that neither the prompt gamma intensity from
the $^{40}$Ar neutron capture nor the produced $^{41}$Ar activity have an
impact in terms of gamma dose rate around the detector and background level.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.08911</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.08911</id><created>2017-01-30</created><updated>2017-06-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ciani</keyname><forenames>Giacomo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chilton</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Apple</keyname><forenames>Stephen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olatunde</keyname><forenames>Taiwo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aitken</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mueller</keyname><forenames>Guido</forenames></author><author><keyname>Conklin</keyname><forenames>John W.</forenames></author></authors><title>A New Torsion Pendulum for Gravitational Reference Sensor Technology
  Development</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><journal-ref>Review of Scientific Instruments 88, 064502 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4985543</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the design and sensitivity of a new torsion pendulum for
measuring the performance of ultra-precise inertial sensors and for the
development of associated technologies for space-based gravitational wave
observatories and geodesy missions. The apparatus comprises a 1 m-long, 50
um-diameter, tungsten fiber that supports an inertial member inside a vacuum
system. The inertial member is an aluminum crossbar with four hollow cubic test
masses at each end. This structure converts the rotation of the torsion
pendulum into translation of the test masses. Two test masses are enclosed in
capacitive sensors which provide readout and actuation. These test masses are
electrically insulated from the rest of the cross-bar and their electrical
charge is controlled by photoemission using fiber-coupled ultraviolet light
emitting diodes. The capacitive readout measures the test mass displacement
with a broadband sensitivity of 30 nm / sqrt(Hz), and is complemented by a
laser interferometer with a sensitivity of about 0.5 nm / sqrt(Hz). The
performance of the pendulum, as determined by the measured residual torque
noise and expressed in terms of equivalent force acting on a single test mass,
is roughly 200 fN / sqrt(Hz) around 2 mHz, which is about a factor of 20 above
the thermal noise limit of the fiber.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.00410</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.00410</id><created>2017-02-01</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Deutschmann</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flacke</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Jong Soo</forenames></author></authors><title>Current LHC Constraints on Minimal Universal Extra Dimensions</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures, 2 tables; v2: typos fixed, references added;
  matches version published in Phys.Lett.B</comments><report-no>CTPU-17-02, LYCEN 2017-01</report-no><journal-ref>Phys.Lett. B771 (2017) 515-520</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.06.004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this letter, we present LHC limits on the minimal universal extra
dimension (MUED) model from LHC Run 1 data and current limits from searches of
the ongoing Run 2. Typical collider signals of the Kaluza-Klein (KK) states
mimic generic degenerate supersymmetry (SUSY) missing transverse momentum
signatures since the excited KK particles cascade decay to jets, leptons and
the lightest KK particle which is stable due to KK parity and thus evades
detection. We test the parameter space against a large number of supersymmetry
based missing energy searches implemented in the public code CheckMATE. We
demonstrate the complementarity of employing various searches which target a
large number of final state signatures, and we derive the most up to date
limits on the MUED parameter space from 13 TeV SUSY searches.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02664</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02664</id><created>2017-02-08</created><updated>2017-05-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cole</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pollmann</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Betouras</keyname><forenames>Joseph J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement scaling and spatial correlations of the transverse field
  Ising model with perturbations</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>9 pages, 12 figures, version accepted in PRB</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 214410 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.214410</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study numerically the entanglement entropy and spatial correlations of the
one dimensional transverse field Ising model with three different
perturbations. First, we focus on the out of equilibrium, steady state with an
energy current passing through the system. By employing a variety of
matrix-product state based methods, we confirm the phase diagram and compute
the entanglement entropy. Second, we consider a small perturbation that takes
the system away from integrability and calculate the correlations, the central
charge and the entanglement entropy. Third, we consider periodically weakened
bonds, exploring the phase diagram and entanglement properties first in the
situation when the weak and strong bonds alternate (period two-bonds) and then
the general situation of a period of n bonds. In the latter case we find a
critical weak bond that scales with the transverse field as $J'_c/J$ =
$(h/J)^n$, where $J$ is the strength of the strong bond, $J'$ of the weak bond
and $h$ the transverse field. We explicitly show that the energy current is not
a conserved quantity in this case.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.03004</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.03004</id><created>2017-02-09</created><updated>2017-06-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Passaglia</keyname><forenames>Samuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manzotti</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dodelson</keyname><forenames>Scott</forenames></author></authors><title>Cross-correlating 2D and 3D galaxy surveys</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>Revised version, new table with absolute cosmological constraints.
  Accepted in Phys. Rev. D</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 123508 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.123508</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  Galaxy surveys probe both structure formation and the expansion rate, making
them promising avenues for understanding the dark universe. Photometric surveys
accurately map the 2D distribution of galaxy positions and shapes in a given
redshift range, while spectroscopic surveys provide sparser 3D maps of the
galaxy distribution. We present a way to analyse overlapping 2D and 3D maps
jointly and without loss of information. We represent 3D maps using spherical
Fourier-Bessel (sFB) modes, which preserve radial coverage while accounting for
the spherical sky geometry, and we decompose 2D maps in a spherical harmonic
basis. In these bases, a simple expression exists for the cross-correlation of
the two fields. One very powerful application is the ability to simultaneously
constrain the redshift distribution of the photometric sample, the sample
biases, and cosmological parameters. We use our framework to show that combined
analysis of DESI and LSST can improve cosmological constraints by factors of
${\sim}1.2$ to ${\sim}1.8$ on the region where they overlap relative to
identically sized disjoint regions. We also show that in the overlap of DES and
SDSS-III in Stripe 82, cross-correlating improves photo-$z$ parameter
constraints by factors of ${\sim}2$ to ${\sim}12$ over internal photo-$z$
reconstructions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.03593</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.03593</id><created>2017-02-12</created><updated>2017-06-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Meng</keyname><forenames>Weiwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xiaoming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Zewen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jianbo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mitzi</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Yanfa</forenames></author></authors><title>Parity-Forbidden Transitions and Their Impacts on the Optical Absorption
  Properties of Lead-Free Metal Halide Perovskites and Double Perovskites</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1021/acs.jpclett.7b01042</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using density-functional theory calculations, we analyze the optical
absorption properties of lead (Pb)-free metal halide perovskites
(AB$^{2+}$X$_3$) and double perovskites (AB$^+$B$^{3+}$X$_6$) (A = Cs or
monovalent organic ion, B$^{2+}$ = non-Pb divalent metal, B$^+$ = monovalent
metal, B$^{3+}$ = trivalent metal, X = halogen). We show that, if B$^{2+}$ is
not Sn or Ge, Pb-free metal halide perovskites exhibit poor optical absorptions
because of their indirect bandgap nature. Among the nine possible types of
Pb-free metal halide double perovskites, six have direct bandgaps. Of these six
types, four show inversion symmetry-induced parity-forbidden or weak
transitions between band edges, making them not ideal for thin-film solar cell
application. Only one type of Pb-free double perovskite shows optical
absorption and electronic properties suitable for solar cell applications,
namely those with B$^+$ = In, Tl and B$^{3+}$ = Sb, Bi. Our results provide
important insights for designing new metal halide perovskites and double
perovskites for optoelectronic applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04629</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04629</id><created>2017-02-08</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Atanasov</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author></authors><title>Gravity at a Quantum Condensate</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 86, 074004 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.86.074004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Provided a quantum superconducting condensate is allowed to occupy a curved
hyper-plane of space-time, a geometric potential from the kinetic term arises.
An energy conservation relation involving the geometric field at every material
point in the superconductor can be demonstrated. The induced three-dimensional
scalar curvature is directly related to the wavefunction/order parameter of the
quantum condensate thus pointing the way to a possible experimental procedure
to artificially induce curvature of space-time via change in the
electric/probability current density.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.06016</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.06016</id><created>2017-02-20</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Del Vicario</keyname><forenames>Michela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaito</keyname><forenames>Sabrina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quattrociocchi</keyname><forenames>Walter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zignani</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zollo</keyname><forenames>Fabiana</forenames></author></authors><title>Public discourse and news consumption on online social media: A
  quantitative, cross-platform analysis of the Italian Referendum</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The rising attention to the spreading of fake news and unsubstantiated rumors
on online social media and the pivotal role played by confirmation bias led
researchers to investigate different aspects of the phenomenon. Experimental
evidence showed that confirmatory information gets accepted even if containing
deliberately false claims while dissenting information is mainly ignored or
might even increase group polarization. It seems reasonable that, to address
misinformation problem properly, we have to understand the main determinants
behind content consumption and the emergence of narratives on online social
media. In this paper we address such a challenge by focusing on the discussion
around the Italian Constitutional Referendum by conducting a quantitative,
cross-platform analysis on both Facebook public pages and Twitter accounts. We
observe the spontaneous emergence of well-separated communities on both
platforms. Such a segregation is completely spontaneous, since no
categorization of contents was performed a priori. By exploring the dynamics
behind the discussion, we find that users tend to restrict their attention to a
specific set of Facebook pages/Twitter accounts. Finally, taking advantage of
automatic topic extraction and sentiment analysis techniques, we are able to
identify the most controversial topics inside and across both platforms. We
measure the distance between how a certain topic is presented in the
posts/tweets and the related emotional response of users. Our results provide
interesting insights for the understanding of the evolution of the core
narratives behind different echo chambers and for the early detection of
massive viral phenomena around false claims.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.07433</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.07433</id><created>2017-02-23</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Parker</keyname><forenames>Daniel E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vasseur</keyname><forenames>Romain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moore</keyname><forenames>Joel E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement Entropy in Excited States of the Quantum Lifshitz Model</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Published version. Invited contribution to the special issue of J.
  Phys. A: &quot;John Cardy's scale-invariant journey in low dimensions: a special
  issue for his 70th birthday&quot;</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics A: Mathematical and Theoretical, Volume 50,
  Number 25 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa70b3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the entanglement properties of an infinite class of excited
states in the quantum Lifshitz model (QLM). The presence of a conformal quantum
critical point in the QLM makes it unusually tractable for a model above one
spatial dimension, enabling the ground state entanglement entropy for an
arbitrary domain to be expressed in terms of geometrical and topological
quantities. Here we extend this result to excited states and find that the
entanglement can be naturally written in terms of quantities which we dub
&quot;entanglement propagator amplitudes&quot; (EPAs). EPAs are geometrical probabilities
that we explicitly calculate and interpret. A comparison of lattice and
continuum results demonstrates that EPAs are universal. This work shows that
the QLM is an example of a 2+1d field theory where the universal behavior of
excited-state entanglement may be computed analytically.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00448</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00448</id><created>2017-03-01</created><updated>2017-06-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kelly</keyname><forenames>Kevin J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Searches for new physics at the Hyper-Kamiokande experiment</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>14 pages, 8 figures. Minor changes to results; matches published
  version</comments><report-no>NUHEP-TH/17-01</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 115009 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.115009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the ability of the upcoming Hyper-Kamiokande (Hyper-K)
neutrino experiment to detect new physics phenomena beyond the standard,
three-massive-neutrinos paradigm; namely the existence of a fourth, sterile
neutrino or weaker-than-weak, non-standard neutrino interactions. With both
beam-based neutrinos from the Japan Proton Accelerator Research Complex
(J-PARC) and atmospheric neutrinos, Hyper-K is capable of exploring new ranges
of parameter space in these new-physics scenarios. We find that Hyper-K has
comparable capability to the upcoming Deep Underground Neutrino Experiment
(DUNE), and that combining both beam- and atmospheric-based data can clear up
degeneracies in the parameter spaces of interest. We also comment on the
potential improvement in searches for new physics if a combined analysis were
performed using Hyper-K and DUNE data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00865</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00865</id><created>2017-03-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Oltean</keyname><forenames>Marius</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sopuerta</keyname><forenames>Carlos F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spallicci</keyname><forenames>Alessandro D. A. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>A frequency-domain implementation of the particle-without-particle
  approach to EMRIs</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>2 pages, to appear in the proceedings of the 11th International LISA
  Symposium (Zurich, 5-9 September 2016), in Journal of Physics: Conference
  Series</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Conf. Ser. 840, 012056 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/840/1/012056</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The gravitational waves emitted by binary systems with extreme mass ratios
carry unique astrophysical information expected to be probed by the next
generation of gravitational wave detectors such as LISA. The detection of these
binaries rely on an accurate modeling of the gravitational self-force that
drives their orbital evolution. Although the theoretical formalism to compute
the self-force has been largely established, the mathematical tools needed to
implement it are still under development, and the self-force computation
remains an open problem. We present here a frequency-domain implementation of
the particle-without-particle (PwP) technique previously developed for the
computation of the scalar self-force -- a helpful testbed for the gravitational
self-force.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00917</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00917</id><created>2017-03-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Denissenya</keyname><forenames>Mikhail</forenames></author><author><keyname>Linder</keyname><forenames>Eric V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmic Growth Signatures of Modified Gravitational Strength</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>12 pages, 14 figures</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 1706, 030 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/06/030</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cosmic growth of large scale structure probes the entire history of cosmic
expansion and gravitational coupling. To get a clear picture of the effects of
modification of gravity we consider a deviation in the coupling strength
(effective Newton's constant) at different redshifts, with different durations
and amplitudes. We derive, analytically and numerically, the impact on the
growth rate and growth amplitude. Galaxy redshift surveys can measure a product
of these through redshift space distortions and we connect the modified gravity
to the observable in a way that may provide a useful parametrization of the
ability of future surveys to test gravity. In particular, modifications during
the matter dominated era can be treated by a single parameter, the &quot;area&quot; of
the modification, to an accuracy of $\sim0.3\%$ in the observables. We project
constraints on both early and late time gravity for the Dark Energy
Spectroscopic Instrument and discuss what is needed for tightening tests of
gravity to better than 5% uncertainty.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.03887</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.03887</id><created>2017-03-10</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ganz</keyname><forenames>Maor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sattath</keyname><forenames>Or</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum coin hedging, and a counter measure</title><categories>quant-ph cs.CR</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A quantum board game is a multi-round protocol between a single quantum
player against the quantum board. Molina and Watrous discovered quantum
hedging. They gave an example for perfect quantum hedging: a board game with
winning probability &lt; 1, such that the player can win with certainty at least
1-out-of-2 quantum board games played in parallel. Here we show that perfect
quantum hedging occurs in a cryptographic protocol - quantum coin flipping. For
this reason, when cryptographic protocols are composed, hedging may introduce
serious challenges into their analysis.
  We also show that hedging cannot occur when playing two-outcome board games
in sequence. This is done by showing a formula for the value of sequential
two-outcome board games, which depends only on the optimal value of a single
board game; this formula applies in a more general setting, in which hedging is
only a special case.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.04493</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.04493</id><created>2017-03-13</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guimar&#xe3;es</keyname><forenames>Filipe S. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dias</keyname><forenames>Manuel dos Santos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bouaziz</keyname><forenames>Juba</forenames></author><author><keyname>Costa</keyname><forenames>Antonio T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muniz</keyname><forenames>Roberto B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lounis</keyname><forenames>Samir</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical amplification of magnetoresistances and Hall currents up to
  the THz regime</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>19 pages, 4 figures, Supplementary Information</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 7, 3686 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-03924-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Spin-orbit-related effects offer a highly promising route for reading and
writing information in magnetic units of future devices. These phenomena rely
not only on the static magnetization orientation but also on its dynamics to
achieve fast switchings that can reach the THz range. In this work, we consider
Co/Pt and Fe/W bilayers to show that accounting for the phase difference
between different processes is crucial to the correct description of the
dynamical currents. By tuning each system towards its ferromagnetic resonance,
we reveal that dynamical spin Hall angles can non-trivially change sign and be
boosted by over 500%, reaching giant values. We demonstrate that charge and
spin pumping mechanisms can greatly magnify or dwindle the currents flowing
through the system, influencing all kinds of magnetoresistive and Hall effects,
thus impacting also dc and second harmonic experimental measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.04584</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.04584</id><created>2017-03-14</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Anselmi</keyname><forenames>Damiano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piva</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author></authors><title>A new formulation of Lee-Wick quantum field theory</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>27 pages, 17 figures; v2: details about Lorentz invariance above LW
  thresholds; v3: minor changes, JHEP</comments><journal-ref>J. High Energy Phys. 06 (2017) 066</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP06(2017)066</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Lee-Wick models are higher-derivative theories that are claimed to be
unitary thanks to a peculiar cancelation mechanism. In this paper, we provide a
new formulation of the models, to clarify several aspects that have remained
quite mysterious, so far. Specifically, we define them as nonanalytically Wick
rotated Euclidean theories. The complex energy plane is divided into
disconnected regions, which can be related to one another by a well-defined,
albeit nonanalytic procedure. Working in a generic Lorentz frame, the models
are intrinsically equipped with the right recipe to treat the pinchings of the
Lee-Wick poles, with no need of external ad hoc prescriptions. We describe
these features in detail by calculating the one-loop bubble diagram and
explaining how the key properties generalize to more complicated diagrams. The
physical results of our formulation are different from those of the previous
ones. The unusual behaviors of the physical amplitudes lead to interesting
phenomenological predictions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.06703</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.06703</id><created>2017-03-20</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Green</keyname><forenames>Jeremy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hasan</keyname><forenames>Nesreen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meinel</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Engelhardt</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krieg</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laeuchli</keyname><forenames>Jesse</forenames></author><author><keyname>Negele</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orginos</keyname><forenames>Kostas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pochinsky</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Syritsyn</keyname><forenames>Sergey</forenames></author></authors><title>Up, down, and strange nucleon axial form factors from lattice QCD</title><categories>hep-lat hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>29 pages, 17 figures. v2: additional comparison with phenomenology
  and discussion of systematics; new appendix with fit parameters</comments><report-no>RBRC 1232</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 114502 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.114502</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report a calculation of the nucleon axial form factors $G_A^q(Q^2)$ and
$G_P^q(Q^2)$ for all three light quark flavors $q\in\{u,d,s\}$ in the range
$0\leq Q^2\lesssim 1.2\text{ GeV}^2$ using lattice QCD. This work was done
using a single ensemble with pion mass 317 MeV and made use of the hierarchical
probing technique to efficiently evaluate the required disconnected loops. We
perform nonperturbative renormalization of the axial current, including a
nonperturbative treatment of the mixing between light and strange currents due
to the singlet-nonsinglet difference caused by the axial anomaly. The form
factor shapes are fit using the model-independent $z$ expansion. From
$G_A^q(Q^2)$, we determine the quark contributions to the nucleon spin and
axial radii. By extrapolating the isovector $G_P^{u-d}(Q^2)$, we obtain the
induced pseudoscalar coupling relevant for ordinary muon capture and the
pion-nucleon coupling constant. We find that the disconnected contributions to
$G_P$ form factors are large, and give an interpretation based on the dominant
influence of the pseudoscalar poles in these form factors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.06799</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.06799</id><created>2017-03-20</created><updated>2017-06-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Z. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tan</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernal</keyname><forenames>O. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ho</keyname><forenames>P. -C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morris</keyname><forenames>G. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hillier</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Biswas</keyname><forenames>P. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cottrell</keyname><forenames>S. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiang</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>MacLaughlin</keyname><forenames>D. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shu</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author></authors><title>Discovery of slow magnetic fluctuations and critical slowing down in the
  pseudogap phase of YBa$_2$Cu$_3$O$_y$</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>8 pages 7 figures including supplemental material; added discussion
  of statistics and other experiments</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Evidence for intra-unit-cell (IUC) magnetic order in the pseudogap region of
high-$T_c$ cuprates below a temperature $T^\ast$ is found in several studies,
but NMR and $\mu$SR experiments do not observe the expected static local
magnetic fields. It has been noted, however, that such fields could be averaged
by fluctuations. Our measurements of muon spin relaxation rates in single
crystals of YBa$_2$Cu$_3$O$_y$ reveal magnetic fluctuations of the expected
order of magnitude that exhibit critical slowing down at $T^\ast$. These
results are strong evidence for fluctuating IUC magnetic order in the pseudogap
phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05380</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05380</id><created>2017-04-18</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Acebron</keyname><forenames>Ana</forenames><affiliation>LAM</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Jullo</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames><affiliation>LAM</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Limousin</keyname><forenames>Marceau</forenames><affiliation>LAM</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tilquin</keyname><forenames>Andr&#xe9;</forenames><affiliation>CPPM</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Giocoli</keyname><forenames>Carlo</forenames><affiliation>Universit&#xe0; di Bologna</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Jauzac</keyname><forenames>Mathilde</forenames><affiliation>Durham University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Mahler</keyname><forenames>Guillaume</forenames><affiliation>CRAL</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Richard</keyname><forenames>Johan</forenames><affiliation>CRAL</affiliation></author></authors><title>Hubble Frontier Fields: systematic errors in strong lensing models of
  galaxy clusters - Implications for cosmography</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>19 pages, 11 figures, 3 tables. Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1330</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Strong gravitational lensing by galaxy clusters is a fundamental tool to
study dark matter and constrain the geometry of the Universe. Recently, the
Hubble Space Telescope Frontier Fields programme has allowed a significant
improvement of mass and magnification measurements but lensing models still
have a residual root mean square between 0.2 arcsec and few arcsec- onds, not
yet completely understood. Systematic errors have to be better understood and
treated in order to use strong lensing clusters as reliable cosmological
probes. We have analysed two simulated Hubble-Frontier-Fields-like clusters
from the Hubble Frontier Fields Comparison Challenge, Ares and Hera. We use
several estimators (relative bias on magnification, den- sity profiles,
ellipticity and orientation) to quantify the goodness of our reconstructions by
comparing our multiple models, optimized with the parametric software LENSTOOL
, with the input models. We have quantified the impact of systematic errors
arising, first, from the choice of different density profiles and
configurations and, secondly, from the availability of con- straints
(spectroscopic or photometric redshifts, redshift ranges of the background
sources) in the parametric modelling of strong lensing galaxy clusters and
therefore on the retrieval of cosmological parameters. We find that
substructures in the outskirts have a significant im- pact on the position of
the multiple images, yielding tighter cosmological contours. The need for
wide-field imaging around massive clusters is thus reinforced. We show that
competitive cosmological constraints can be obtained also with complex
multimodal clusters and that photometric redshifts improve the constraints on
cosmological parameters when considering a narrow range of (spectroscopic)
redshifts for the sources.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05492</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05492</id><created>2017-04-18</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schlachtberger</keyname><forenames>David P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Tom</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schramm</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greiner</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author></authors><title>The Benefits of Cooperation in a Highly Renewable European Electricity
  Network</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 10 figures, accepted by Energy</comments><doi>10.1016/j.energy.2017.06.004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To reach ambitious European CO$_2$ emission reduction targets, most scenarios
of future European electricity systems rely on large shares of wind and solar
photovoltaic power generation. We interpolate between two concepts for
balancing the variability of these renewable sources: balancing at continental
scales using the transmission grid and balancing locally with storage. This
interpolation is done by systematically restricting transmission capacities
from the optimum level to zero. We run techno-economic cost optimizations for
the capacity investment and dispatch of wind, solar, hydroelectricity, natural
gas power generation and transmission, as well as storage options such as
pumped-hydro, battery, and hydrogen storage. The simulations assume a 95%
CO$_2$ emission reduction compared to 1990, and are run over a full historical
year of weather and electricity demand for 30 European countries. In the
cost-optimal system with high levels of transmission expansion, energy
generation is dominated by wind (65%) and hydro (15%), with average system
costs comparable to today's system. Restricting transmission shifts the balance
in favour of solar and storage, driving up costs by a third. As the restriction
is relaxed, 85% of the cost benefits of the optimal grid expansion can be
captured already with only 44% of the transmission volume.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08075</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08075</id><created>2017-04-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Krogager</keyname><forenames>Jens-Kristian</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xf8;ller</keyname><forenames>Palle</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fynbo</keyname><forenames>Johan P. U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noterdaeme</keyname><forenames>Pasquier</forenames></author></authors><title>Consensus report on 25 years of searches for damped Ly$\alpha$ galaxies
  in emission: Confirming their metallicity-luminosity relation at $z \gtrsim
  2$</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>25 pages (7 of which in appendix), accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS, 469, 2959 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Starting from a summary of detection statistics of our recent X-shooter
campaign, we review the major surveys, both space and ground based, for
emission counterparts of high-redshift damped Ly$\alpha$ absorbers (DLAs)
carried out since the first detection 25 years ago. We show that the detection
rates of all surveys are precisely reproduced by a simple model in which the
metallicity and luminosity of the galaxy associated to the DLA follow a
relation of the form, ${\rm M_{UV}} = -5 \times \left(\,[{\rm M/H}] + 0.3\,
\right) - 20.8$, and the DLA cross-section follows a relation of the form
$\sigma_{DLA} \propto L^{0.8}$. Specifically, our spectroscopic campaign
consists of 11 DLAs preselected based on their equivalent width of SiII
$\lambda1526$ to have a metallicity higher than [Si/H] &gt; -1. The targets have
been observed with the X-shooter spectrograph at the Very Large Telescope to
search for emission lines around the quasars. We observe a high detection rate
of 64% (7/11), significantly higher than the typical $\sim$10% for random,
HI-selected DLA samples. We use the aforementioned model, to simulate the
results of our survey together with a range of previous surveys: spectral
stacking, direct imaging (using the `double DLA' technique), long-slit
spectroscopy, and integral field spectroscopy. Based on our model results, we
are able to reconcile all results. Some tension is observed between model and
data when looking at predictions of Ly$\alpha$ emission for individual targets.
However, the object to object variations are most likely a result of the
significant scatter in the underlying scaling relations as well as
uncertainties in the amount of dust which affects the emission.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.01912</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.01912</id><created>2017-05-04</created><updated>2017-06-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kritsuk</keyname><forenames>Alexei G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ustyugov</keyname><forenames>Sergey D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Norman</keyname><forenames>Michael L.</forenames></author></authors><title>The structure and statistics of interstellar turbulence</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>36 pages, 19 figures, a special issue article published in New J.
  Phys</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19, 065003 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa7156</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore the structure and statistics of multiphase, magnetized ISM
turbulence in the local Milky Way by means of driven periodic box numerical MHD
simulations. Using the higher order-accurate piecewise-parabolic method on a
local stencil (PPML), we carry out a small parameter survey varying the mean
magnetic field strength and density while fixing the rms velocity to observed
values. We quantify numerous characteristics of the transient and steady-state
turbulence, including its thermodynamics and phase structure, kinetic and
magnetic energy power spectra, structure functions, and distribution functions
of density, column density, pressure, and magnetic field strength. The
simulations reproduce many observables of the local ISM, including molecular
clouds, such as the ratio of turbulent to mean magnetic field at 100 pc scale,
the mass and volume fractions of thermally stable HI, the lognormal
distribution of column densities, the mass-weighted distribution of thermal
pressure, and the linewidth-size relationship for molecular clouds. Our models
predict the shape of magnetic field probability density functions (PDFs), which
are strongly non-Gaussian, and the relative alignment of magnetic field and
density structures. Finally, our models show how the observed low rates of star
formation per free-fall time are controlled by the multiphase thermodynamics
and large-scale turbulence.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02169</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02169</id><created>2017-05-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Mammarella</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author></authors><title>Meson Physics in Asymmetric Matter</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures, proceeding of CSQCD V conference. arXiv admin
  note: text overlap with arXiv:1509.06887</comments><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/861/1/012017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper describes dynamic and thermodynamic (at $T=0$) properties of
mesons in asymmetric matter in the framework of Chiral Perturbation Theory. We
consider a mesonic system at vanishing temperature with nonzero isospin
chemical potential and strangeness chemical potential and we study their effect
on the phase diagram. We also study meson masses and mixing in the resulting
normal phase, pion condensation phase and kaon condensation phase. We find
differences with previous papers regarding meson masses and mixing in the
condensed phases; the results presented here are supported by theory group
analysis and direct calculations. Pressure, density and equation of state of
the system at $T=0$ and nonzero $\mu_I$ are calculated, finding remarkable
agreement with analogue studies performed by lattice calculations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02334</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02334</id><created>2017-05-05</created><updated>2017-06-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hamers</keyname><forenames>Adrian S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lai</keyname><forenames>Dong</forenames></author></authors><title>Secular chaotic dynamics in hierarchical quadruple systems, with
  applications to hot Jupiters in stellar binaries and triples</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Revised to match MNRAS publication. 16 pages, 10 figures</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1319</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hierarchical quadruple systems arise naturally in stellar binaries and
triples that harbour planets. Examples are hot Jupiters (HJs) in stellar triple
systems, and planetary companions to HJs in stellar binaries. The secular
dynamical evolution of these systems is generally complex, with secular chaotic
motion possible in certain parameter regimes. The latter can lead to extremely
high eccentricities and, therefore, strong interactions such as efficient tidal
evolution. These interactions are believed to play an important role in the
formation of HJs through high-eccentricity migration. Nevertheless, a deeper
understanding of the secular dynamics of these systems is still lacking. Here
we study in detail the secular dynamics of a special case of hierarchical
quadruple systems in either the `2+2' or `3+1' configurations. We show how the
equations of motion can be cast in a form representing a perturbed hierarchical
three-body system, in which the outer orbital angular momentum vector is
precessing steadily around a fixed axis. In this case, we show that
eccentricity excitation can be significantly enhanced when the precession
period is comparable to the Lidov-Kozai oscillation time-scale of the inner
orbit. This arises from an induced large mutual inclination between the inner
and outer orbits driven by the precession of the outer orbit, even if the
initial mutual inclination is small. We present a simplified semi-analytic
model that describes the latter phenomenon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02480</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02480</id><created>2017-05-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Guseva</keyname><forenames>Ksenia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feudel</keyname><forenames>Ulrike</forenames></author></authors><title>Aggregation and fragmentation dynamics in random flows: From tracers to
  inertial aggregates</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>12 pages,11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 95, 062604 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.062604</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate aggregation and fragmentation dynamics of tracers and inertial
aggregates in random flows leading to steady state size distributions. Our
objective is to elucidate the impact of changes in aggregation rates, due to
differences in advection dynamics, especially with respect to the influence of
inertial effects. This aggregation process is, at the same time, balanced by
fragmentation triggered by local hydrodynamic stress. Our study employs an
individual-particle-based model, tracking position, velocity and size of each
aggregate. We compare the steady-state size distribution formed by tracers and
inertial aggregates, characterized by different sizes and densities. On the one
hand, we show that the size distributions change their shape with changes of
the dilution rate of the suspension. On the other hand, we obtain that the size
distributions formed with different binding strengths between monomers can be
rescaled to a single form with the use of a characteristic size for both dense
inertial particles and tracer monomers. Nevertheless, this last scaling
relation also fails if the size distribution contains aggregates that behave as
tracer-like and as inertial-like, which results in a crossover between
different scalings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02581</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02581</id><created>2017-05-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Nokhrina</keyname><forenames>E. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beskin</keyname><forenames>V. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the acceleration and deceleration of relativistic jets in active
  galactic nuclei - II. Mass-loading</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>12 pages, 7 figures, accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS, 469(4), 3840-3850 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1144</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The effect of a mass-loading of the magnetohydrodynamic (MHD) flow in a
relativistic jet from active galactic nuclei (AGN) due to
$\gamma\gamma\rightarrow e^+e^-$ conversion is considered analytically. We
argue that the effects of charge average separation due to specific initial
pairs' motion lead to partial magnetic and electric fields screening or
enhancement. The effect of the fields screening has not been considered
earlier. The pairs with the center-of-mass moving faster or slower than the
bulk plasma flow create a surface charge and a current which either screen or
enhance both electric and magnetic fields in a pair creation domain. This
impacts the bulk flow motion, which either accelerates or decelerates. The
pairs with the center-of-mass moving with exactly the drift velocity does not
induce the fields disturbance. In this case the flow decelerates due to pure
mass-loading. For these different cases the Lorentz factor of the loaded
outflow is calculated as a function of loading pairs number density. The effect
may be important on sub-parsec to parsec scales due to conversion of TeV jet
radiation on soft infra-red to ultra-violet external isotropic photon field.
This leads to an outer shell acceleration. The conversion of MeV jet radiation
on larger scales may account for the flow deceleration due to pure
mass-loading. The proposed mechanism may be a source of internal shocks and
instabilities in the pair creation region.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.03319</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.03319</id><created>2017-05-09</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fromang</keyname><forenames>S&#xe9;bastien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lesur</keyname><forenames>Geoffroy</forenames></author></authors><title>Angular momentum transport in accretion disks: a hydrodynamical
  perspective</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>23 pages, 4 figures, proceeding for the Astrofluid conference in
  honor of Jean-Paul Zahn (Paris, June 2016), references added</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The radial transport of angular momentum in accretion disk is a fundamental
process in the universe. It governs the dynamical evolution of accretion disks
and has implications for various issues ranging from the formation of planets
to the growth of supermassive black holes. While the importance of magnetic
fields for this problem has long been demonstrated, the existence of a source
of transport solely hydrodynamical in nature has proven more difficult to
establish and to quantify. In recent years, a combination of results coming
from experiments, theoretical work and numerical simulations has dramatically
improved our understanding of hydrodynamically mediated angular momentum
transport in accretion disk. Here, based on these recent developments, we
review the hydrodynamical processes that might contribute to transporting
angular momentum radially in accretion disks and highlight the many questions
that are still to be answered.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.03347</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.03347</id><created>2017-05-09</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sillitoe</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karr</keyname><forenames>Jean-Philippe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heinrich</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Louvradoux</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Douillet</keyname><forenames>Albane</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hilico</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames></author></authors><title>$\bar{\textrm{H}}^{+}$ Sympathetic Cooling Simulations with a Variable
  Time Step</title><categories>physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>LEAP 2016 proceeding</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we present a new variable time step criterion for the
velocity-Verlet algorithm allowing to correctly simulate the dynamics of
charged particles exchanging energy via Coulomb collisions while minimising
simulation time. We present physical arguments supporting the use of the
criterion along with numerical results proving its validity. We numerically
show that $\bar{\textrm{H}}^{+}$ ions with 18 meV initial energy can be
captured and sympathetically cooled by a Coulomb crystal of $\textrm{Be}^{+}$
and $\textrm{HD}^{+}$ in less than 10 ms, an important result for the GBAR
project.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04177</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04177</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Orain</keyname><forenames>J. -C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernu</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mendels</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clark</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aidoudi</keyname><forenames>F. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lightfoot</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morris</keyname><forenames>R. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bert</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nature of the spin liquid ground state in a breathing kagome compound
  studied by NMR and series expansion</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures, to appear in Phys. Rev. Lett</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.237203</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the vanadium oxyfluoride compound
(NH$_4$)$_2$[C$_7$H$_{14}$N][V$_7$O$_6$F$_{18}$] (DQVOF), the V$^{4+}$ (3d$^1$,
$S=1/2$) ions realize a unique, highly frustrated breathing kagome lattice
composed of alternately-sized, corner-sharing equilateral triangles. Here we
present an $^{17}$O NMR study of DQVOF, which isolates the local susceptibility
of the breathing kagome network. By a fit to series expansion we extract the
ratio of the interactions within the breathing kagome plane, $J_\triangledown /
J_\vartriangle = 0.55(4)$, and the mean antiferromagnetic interaction
$\bar{J}=60(7)$~K. Spin lattice, $T_1$, measurements reveal an essentially
gapless excitation spectrum with a maximum gap $\Delta / \bar{J}=0.007(7)$. Our
study provides new impetus for further theoretical investigations in order to
establish whether the gapless spin liquid behavior displayed by DQVOF is
intrinsic to its breathing kagome lattice or whether it is due to perturbations
to this model, such as a residual coupling of the V$^{4+}$ ions in the
breathing kagome planes to the interlayer V$^{3+}$ ($S=1$) spins.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05641</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05641</id><created>2017-05-16</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zubko</keyname><forenames>Pavlo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Haidong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bark</keyname><forenames>Chung-Wung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mart&#xed;</keyname><forenames>Xavi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santiso</keyname><forenames>Jos&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eom</keyname><forenames>Chang-Beom</forenames></author><author><keyname>Catalan</keyname><forenames>Gustau</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gruverman</keyname><forenames>Alexei</forenames></author></authors><title>On the persistence of polar domains in ultrathin ferroelectric
  capacitors</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>13 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 29, 284001 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-648X/aa73c3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The instability of ferroelectric ordering in ultra-thin films is one of the
most important fundamental issues pertaining realization of a number of
electronic devices with enhanced functionality, such as ferroelectric and
multiferroic tunnel junctions or ferroelectric field effect transistors. In
this paper, we investigate the polarization state of archetypal ultrathin
(several nanometres) ferroelectric heterostructures: epitaxial
single-crystalline BaTiO$_3$ films sandwiched between the most habitual
perovskite electrodes, SrRuO$_3$, on top of the most used perovskite substrate,
SrTiO$_3$. We use a combination of piezoresponse force microscopy, dielectric
measurements and structural characterization to provide conclusive evidence for
the ferroelectric nature of the relaxed polarization state in ultrathin
BaTiO$_3$ capacitors. We show that even the high screening efficiency of
SrRuO$_3$ electrodes is still insufficient to stabilize polarization in
SrRuO$_3$/BaTiO$_3$/SrRuO$_3$ heterostructures at room temperature. We identify
the key role of domain wall motion in determining the macroscopic electrical
properties of ultrathin capacitors and discuss their dielectric response in the
light of the recent interest in negative capacitance behaviour.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.07644</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.07644</id><created>2017-05-22</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>M. C. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rattenbury</keyname><forenames>N. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bond</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sumi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bennett</keyname><forenames>D. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koshimoto</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abe</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asakura</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barry</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattacharya</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Donachie</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evans</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Freeman</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fukui</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirao</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Itow</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ling</keyname><forenames>C. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masuda</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsubara</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muraki</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nagakane</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohnishi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saito</keyname><forenames>To.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharan</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sullivan</keyname><forenames>D. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tristram</keyname><forenames>P. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yonehara</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>The First Eclipsing Binary Catalogue from the MOA-II database</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>13 pages, 9 figures, MNRAS accepted</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1280</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the first catalogue of eclipsing binaries in two MOA fields
towards the Galactic bulge, in which over 8,000 candidates, mostly contact and
semi-detached binaries of periods &lt; 1 d, were identified. In this paper, the
light curves of a small number of interesting candidates including eccentric
binaries, binaries with noteworthy phase modulations and eclipsing RS CVn type
stars are shown as examples. In addition, we identified three triple object
candidates by detecting the light-travel-time effect in their eclipse time
variation curves.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.10666</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.10666</id><created>2017-05-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>X. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Z. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>J. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>X. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>X. F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Low-temperature heat transport of CuFe$_{1-x}$Ga$_x$O$_2$ ($x =$
  0--0.12) single crystals</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>11 pages, 12 figures, accepted for publication in Phys. Rev. B</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 224419 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.224419</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report a study on the thermal conductivity of CuFe$_{1-x}$Ga$_x$O$_2$ ($x
=$ 0--0.12) single crystals at temperatures down to 0.3 K and in magnetic
fields up to 14 T. CuFeO$_2$ is a well-known geometrically frustrated
triangular lattice antiferromagnet and can be made to display multiferroicity
either by applying magnetic field along the $c$ axis or by doping nonmagnetic
impurities, accompanied with rich behaviors of magnetic phase transitions. The
main experimental findings of this work are: (i) the thermal conductivities
($\kappa_a$ and $\kappa_c$) show drastic anomalies at temperature- or
field-induced magnetic transitions; (ii) the low-$T$ $\kappa(H)$ isotherms
exhibit irreversibility in a broad region of magnetic fields; (iii) there are
phonon scattering effect caused by magnetic fluctuations at very low
temperatures. These results demonstrate strong spin-phonon coupling in this
material and reveal the non-negligible magnetic fluctuations in the &quot;ground
state&quot; of pure and Ga-doped samples.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.00624</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.00624</id><created>2017-06-02</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Davies</keyname><forenames>Joshua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steinhauser</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wellmann</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Hadronic Higgs boson decay at order $\alpha_s^4$ and $\alpha_s^5$</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 0 figures. Contribution to the proceedings of the XXV
  International Workshop on Deep-Inelastic Scattering and Related Topics
  (DIS2017), 3-7 April 2017, University of Birmingham, UK. V2: Reference added</comments><report-no>TTP17-028</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compute corrections to the decay of the Standard Model Higgs boson to
hadrons, to the fourth order in the strong coupling constant $\alpha_s$. We use
an effective theory in which the Higgs boson couples directly to bottom quarks
and to gluons, via top quark--mediated effective couplings. Numerically, our
results are of a comparable size to the previously-known &quot;massless&quot;
contributions and complete the order $\alpha_s^4$ corrections to the hadronic
decay of the Higgs boson. In these proceedings we also provide an independent
cross check of the gluonic Higgs boson decay at order $\alpha_s^5$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.00791</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.00791</id><created>2017-06-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Oltean</keyname><forenames>Marius</forenames></author><author><keyname>Epp</keyname><forenames>Richard J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McGrath</keyname><forenames>Paul L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mann</keyname><forenames>Robert B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Relativistic geoids and time dependence: quasilocal frames versus
  isochronometric surfaces</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.EP physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a recent paper [D. Philipp, V. Perlick, D. Puetzfeld, E. Hackmann, and C.
L\&quot;ammerzahl, Phys. Rev. D 95, 104037 (2017)], a definition of a
general-relativistic geoid, restricted to stationary spacetimes, was presented
in terms of &quot;isochronometric surfaces&quot;. In this note, we explicate how this
definition is just a special, highly restrictive case of our earlier
formulation of the general-relativistic geoid using quasilocal frames, which is
valid for generic, non-stationary spacetimes [M. Oltean, R.J. Epp, P.L.
McGrath, and R.B. Mann, Class. Quantum Grav. 33, 105001 (2016)]. Moreover, like
the isochronometric surface geoid, we show how our &quot;geoid quasilocal frame&quot;
(GQF) can also be defined, simply and operationally, in terms of redshift
measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01903</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01903</id><created>2017-06-06</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Monnier</keyname><forenames>Samuel</forenames></author></authors><title>The anomaly field theories of six-dimensional (2,0) superconformal
  theories</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>51 pages. v2: references added, comment in the introduction about the
  conformal anomaly modified</comments><msc-class>81T50, 81T30</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We construct 7-dimensional quantum field theories encoding the anomalies of
conformal field theories with (2,0) supersymmetry in six dimensions. We explain
how the conformal blocks of the (2,0) theories arise in this context. A result
of independent interest is a detailed specification of the data required to
define a (2,0) theory with topologically non-trivial spacetime and R-symmetry
bundle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.04320</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.04320</id><created>2017-06-14</created><updated>2017-06-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pyak</keyname><forenames>P. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andreeva</keyname><forenames>E. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Usachenko</keyname><forenames>V. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spatial asymmetry of photoelectron emission in strong-field ionization
  of atoms irradiated by a bichromatic laser field</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures, 25 references</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The phenomenon of spatial (polar) asymmetry of produced photoelectron
emission due to strong-field multiphoton process of above-threshold ionization
(ATI) in atoms irradiated by a linearly polarized two-color (bichromatic) laser
field consisting of coherent superposition of two commensurate harmonics (of
frequencies and is considered and studied theoretically. The problem is
addressed within the conventional strong-field approximation (SFA) in standard
velocity gauge (VG) formulation under condition of arbitrary value of the
so-called Keldysh parameter $\gamma$ , including both the multiphoton (for
$\gamma \gg 1$) and tunneling (for $\gamma \ll 1$) regimes of ionization.
According to such VG-SFA consideration, the calculated photoelectron momentum
distributions (PMD) demonstrate a clear spatial asymmetry (viz., the
photoelectron emission proved to be different along the opposite directions
with respect to incident laser field polarization) even for particular
bichromatic field(s) with polar symmetry of its total electric field strength.
Moreover, a clear correlation between the spatial symmetry/asymmetry of
photoelectron emission and that of applied vector potential of bichromatic
field is reliably established, so that the symmetry of calculated PMD proved to
follow precisely the symmetry of applied vector potential of incident laser
bichromatic field, in a close analogy with the well-known Aharonov-Bohm effect.
Based on these our findings, the attempt is undertaken to identify the physical
mechanism underlying this intriguing phenomenon and provide it with a kind of
semiclassical interpretation in terms of the partial contributions from
photoelectron momenta in final continuum states to partial strong-field ATI
amplidude(s) corresponding to a certain (fixed) number of either of two
harmonics absorbed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.04854</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.04854</id><created>2017-06-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Giampa</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames><affiliation>for the DEAP Collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>In-situ Surface Contamination Removal and Cool-down Process of the
  DEAP-3600 Experiment</title><categories>physics.ins-det astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures, XIV International Conference on Topics in
  Astroparticle and Underground Physics (TAUP 2015)</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics: Conference Series 718 (2016) 042025</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/718/4/042025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The DEAP-3600 experiment is a single-phase detector that uses 3600 Kg of
liquid argon to search for Dark Matter at SNOLAB, Sudbury, Canada, 6800 ft.
underground. The projected sensitivity to the spin-independent WIMP-nucleon
cross-section is $10^{-46}$ cm$^{2}$ for a WIMP mass of 100 GeV. A key
experimental requirement is the reduction of any possible source of background
that would mimic a Dark Matter signal. This document will review how radiogenic
surface backgrounds were reduced in-situ by removing 500 microns of acrylic
from the innermost part of the detector with a resurfacing robot. Furthermore,
it will review the transient cool-down process of the experiment, necessary to
reach cryogenic operating temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.04958</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.04958</id><created>2017-06-15</created><authors><author><keyname>D'Ascanio</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gilkey</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pisani</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>The geometry of locally symmetric affine surfaces</title><categories>math.DG gr-qc</categories><msc-class>53C21</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine the local geometry of affine surfaces which are locally symmetric.
There are 6 non-isomorphic local geometries. We realize these examples as Type
A, Type B, and Type C geometries using a result of Opozda and classify the
relevant geometries up to linear isomorphism. We examine the geodesic
structures in this context. Particular attention is paid to the Lorentzian
analogue of the hyperbolic plane and to the pseudosphere.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.04999</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.04999</id><created>2017-06-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Duif</keyname><forenames>Chris P.</forenames></author></authors><title>An improved method to measure microwave induced impulsive forces with a
  torsion balance or weighing scale</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>10 pages, 11 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A novel method is presented for measuring impulsive forces generated by
devices which are fed with medium power microwave signals. The forces are
measured with a torsion balance or weighing scale, as usual, but the microwave
signal is coupled directly to the device under test via a special coupling
cavity instead of being generated on the measurement device. The method was
verified at power levels up to 15 W, has a transmission of at least 75% (-1.3
dB attenuation) and is shown not to exert disturbing forces at this power level
(vertical forces smaller then 10 micronewton). The application of this way of
supplying microwave signals could significantly improve experiments which
otherwise suffer from heat dissipation and Lorentz forces by components present
on the force measurement device. A particular field of application, where
previous research has failed to prove or disprove the existence of certain
anomalous forces, is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05000</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05000</id><created>2017-06-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Sree</keyname><forenames>A. Sarada</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agravat</keyname><forenames>Hemang S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chauhan</keyname><forenames>Jignesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rajendrakumar</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Preliminary corrosion studies of IN-RAFM steel with stagnant Lead
  Lithium at 550 C</title><categories>physics.ins-det cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.app-ph physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 5 figures and 3 tables</comments><report-no>IPR/RR-741/2015</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Corrosion of Indian RAFMS (reduced activation ferritic martensitic steel)
material with liquid metal, Lead Lithium ( Pb-Li) has been studied under static
condition, maintaining Pb-Li at 550 C for different time durations, 2500, 5000
and 9000 hours. Corrosion rate was calculated from weight loss measurements.
Microstructure analysis was carried out using SEM and chemical composition by
SEM-EDX measurements. Micro Vickers hardness and tensile testing were also
carried out. Chromium was found leaching from the near surface regions and
surface hardness was found to decrease in all the three cases. Grain boundaries
were affected. Some grains got detached from the surface giving rise to pebble
like structures in the surface micrographs. There was no significant reduction
in the tensile strength, after exposure to liquid metal. This paper discusses
the experimental details and the results obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05035</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05035</id><created>2017-06-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Moffat</keyname><forenames>J. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Misaligned Spin Merging Black Holes in Modified Gravity (MOG)</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>4 pages, no figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A promising signature of coalescing black holes is their spin angular
distribution. We consider the aLIGO collaboration gravitational wave
measurements of the binary black hole spins and the predicted modified gravity
(MOG) preference for misaligned spins of the coalescing black holes. In MOG,
during the merger of two black holes, the enhanced strength of gravitation
reduces the effective spin parameter $\chi_{\rm eff}\sim 0$ in agreement with
the measured spin misalignment of the merging black holes observed in the
gravitational wave detections by the aLIGO collaboration.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05036</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05036</id><created>2017-06-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Tutusaus</keyname><forenames>Isaac</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamine</keyname><forenames>Brahim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dupays</keyname><forenames>Arnaud</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blanchard</keyname><forenames>Alain</forenames></author></authors><title>Is cosmic acceleration proven by local cosmological probes?</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>A&amp;A, 602 (2017) A73</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201630289</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Context: The cosmological concordance model ($\Lambda$CDM) matches the
cosmological observations exceedingly well. This model has become the standard
cosmological model with the evidence for an accelerated expansion provided by
the type Ia supernovae (SNIa) Hubble diagram. However, the robustness of this
evidence has been addressed recently with somewhat diverging conclusions. Aims:
The purpose of this paper is to assess the robustness of the conclusion that
the Universe is indeed accelerating if we rely only on low-redshift
(z$\lesssim$2) observations, that is to say with SNIa, baryonic acoustic
oscillations, measurements of the Hubble parameter at different redshifts, and
measurements of the growth of matter perturbations. Methods: We used the
standard statistical procedure of minimizing the $\chi^2$ function for the
different probes to quantify the goodness of fit of a model for both
$\Lambda$CDM and a simple nonaccelerated low-redshift power law model. In this
analysis, we do not assume that supernovae intrinsic luminosity is independent
of the redshift, which has been a fundamental assumption in most previous
studies that cannot be tested. Results: We have found that, when SNIa intrinsic
luminosity is not assumed to be redshift independent, a nonaccelerated
low-redshift power law model is able to fit the low-redshift background data as
well as, or even slightly better, than $\Lambda$CDM. When measurements of the
growth of structures are added, a nonaccelerated low-redshift power law model
still provides an excellent fit to the data for all the luminosity evolution
models considered. Conclusions: Without the standard assumption that supernovae
intrinsic luminosity is independent of the redshift, low-redshift probes are
consistent with a nonaccelerated universe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05049</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05049</id><created>2017-06-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Luszcz-Cook</keyname><forenames>S. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Kleer</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Pater</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adamkovics</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hammel</keyname><forenames>H. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Retrieving Neptune's aerosol properties from Keck OSIRIS observations.
  I. Dark regions</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Published in Icarus: 15 September 2016</comments><journal-ref>Icarus, Volume 276, p. 52-87 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.icarus.2016.04.032</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present and analyze three-dimensional data cubes of Neptune from the
OSIRIS integral-field spectrograph on the 10-m Keck telescope, from July 2009.
These data have a spatial resolution of 0.035&quot;/pixel and spectral resolution of
R~3800 in the H and K broad bands. We focus our analysis on regions of
Neptune's atmosphere that are near-infrared dark- that is, free of discrete
bright cloud features. We use a forward model coupled to a Markov chain Monte
Carlo algorithm to retrieve properties of Neptune's aerosol structure and
methane profile above ~4 bar in these near-infrared dark regions.
  Using a set of high signal-to-noise spectra in a cloud-free band from 2-12N,
we find that Neptune's cloud opacity is dominated by a compact, optically thick
cloud layer with a base near 3 bar and composed of low albedo, forward
scattering particles, with an assumed characteristic size of ~1$\mu$m. Above
this cloud, we require a vertically extended haze of smaller (~0.1 $\mu$m)
particles, which reaches from the upper troposphere (~0.6 bar) into the
stratosphere. The particles in this haze are brighter and more isotropically
scattering than those in the deep cloud. When we extend our analysis to 18
cloud-free locations from 20N to 87S, we observe that the optical depth in
aerosols above 0.5 bar decreases by a factor of 2-3 or more at mid- and
high-southern latitudes relative to low latitudes.
  We also consider Neptune's methane (CH$_4$) profile, and find that our
retrievals indicate a strong preference for a low methane relative humidity at
pressures where methane is expected to condense. Our preferred solution at most
locations is for a methane relative humidity below 10% near the tropopause in
addition to methane depletion down to 2.0-2.5 bar. We tentatively identify a
trend of lower CH$_4$ columns above 2.5 bar at mid- and high-southern latitudes
over low latitudes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05071</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05071</id><created>2017-06-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Latimer</keyname><forenames>David C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-photon interactions with Majorana fermions</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 093010 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.093010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Because Majorana fermions are their own antiparticles, their electric and
magnetic dipole moments must vanish, leaving the anapole moment as their only
static electromagnetic property. But the existence of induced dipole moments is
not necessarily prohibited. Through a study real Compton scattering, we explore
the constraints that the Majorana fermion's self-conjugate nature has on
induced moments. In terms of the Compton amplitude, we find no constraints if
the interactions are separately invariant under charge conjugation, parity, and
time reversal. However, if the interactions are odd under parity and even under
time reversal, then these contributions to the Compton amplitude must vanish.
We employ a simple model to confirm these general findings via explicit
calculation of the Majorana fermion's polarizabilities. We then use these
polarizabilities to estimate the cross-section for $s$-wave annihilation of two
Majorana fermions into photons. The cross-section is larger than a na\&quot;ive
estimate might suggest.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05072</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05072</id><created>2017-06-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruiz-Blanco</keyname><forenames>Yasser B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marrero-Ponce</keyname><forenames>Yovani</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sotomayor-Torres</keyname><forenames>C. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Orthotropic Piezoelectricity in 2D Nanocellulose</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.other physics.app-ph physics.atm-clus</categories><comments>5 figures included. Supp. Mat. available on the online version:
  https://www.nature.com/articles/srep34616, Others on:
  http://www.nanowerk.com/nanotechnology-news/newsid=44806.php</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, Article number: 34616 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep34616</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The control of electromechanical responses within bonding regions is
essential to face frontier challenges in nanotechnologies, such as molecular
electronics and biotechnology. Here, we present I\b{eta}-nanocellulose as a
potentially new orthotropic 2D piezoelectric crystal. The predicted in-layer
piezoelectricity is originated on a sui-generis hydrogen bonds pattern. Upon
this fact and by using a combination of ab-initio and ad-hoc models, we
introduce a description of electrical profiles along chemical bonds. Such
developments lead to obtain a rationale for modelling the extended
piezoelectric effect originated within bond scales. The order of magnitude
estimated for the 2D I\b{eta}-nanocellulose piezoelectric response, ~pm V-1,
ranks this material at the level of currently used piezoelectric energy
generators and new artificial 2D designs. Such finding would be crucial for
developing alternative materials to drive emerging nanotechnologies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05076</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05076</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Ceballos</keyname><forenames>E</forenames><affiliation>MECABOT</affiliation></author><author><keyname>D&#xed;az-Rodriguez</keyname><forenames>M</forenames><affiliation>MECABOT</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Paredes</keyname><forenames>P</forenames><affiliation>MECABOT</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Vargas</keyname><forenames>P</forenames><affiliation>MECABOT</affiliation></author></authors><title>Development of a passive Rehabilitation Robot for the wrist joint
  through the implementation of an Arduino UNO microcontroller</title><categories>cs.RO physics.med-ph</categories><comments>in Spanish</comments><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Revista UIS Ingenier{\'i}a, Universidad Industrial de Santander,
  2017, 16 (1), pp.57-67</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this research was implemented the use of an Arduino UNO R3 microcontroller
to control the movements of a prototype robotic functional developed to perform
rehabilitation exercises in the wrist joint; This device can be used to assist
the physiatrist to rehabilitate the tendinitis, synovitis, rheumatoid arthritis
and for pre-operative and post-operative therapy in this joint. During the
design stage of the functional prototype, the methodology of the industrial
design process was used from a concurrent engineering approach, through which
anthropometric studies could be performed related to the dimensions and angles
of movement of the wrist joint in the population Venezuelan from the
information collected, the design proposal was elaborated, and the use of CAD
programs defined the different forms, geometries and materials of the
components of the rehabilitation device, which were later analyzed using the
finite element method for the determination The tensional state of efforts and
safety factors through the use of CAE programs. In addition, a software was
developed for the acquisition, registration, reproduction and execution of the
different movements produced during the rehabilitation therapy. Through the
research developed, a device was designed that will help the rehabilitation of
the wrist joint allowing the combination of dorsal-palmar flexion and
ulnar-radial movements to recover the joint function of various pathologies
presented in the Venezuelan population.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05102</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05102</id><created>2017-06-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Bruzewicz</keyname><forenames>Colin</forenames></author><author><keyname>McConnell</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sedlacek</keyname><forenames>Jonathon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stuart</keyname><forenames>Jules</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loh</keyname><forenames>William</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sage</keyname><forenames>Jeremy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chiaverini</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author></authors><title>High-Fidelity, Single-Shot, Quantum-Logic-Assisted Readout in a
  Mixed-Species Ion Chain</title><categories>physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use a co-trapped ion ($^{88}\mathrm{Sr}^{+}$) to sympathetically cool and
measure the quantum state populations of a memory-qubit ion of a different
atomic species ($^{40}\mathrm{Ca}^{+}$) in a cryogenic, surface-electrode ion
trap. Due in part to the low motional heating rate demonstrated here, the state
populations of the memory ion can be transferred to the auxiliary ion by using
the shared motion as a quantum state bus and measured with an average accuracy
of 96(1)%. This scheme can be used in quantum information processors to reduce
photon-scattering-induced error in unmeasured memory qubits.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05107</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05107</id><created>2017-06-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Tricco</keyname><forenames>Terrence S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Price</keyname><forenames>Daniel J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laibe</keyname><forenames>Guillaume</forenames></author></authors><title>Is the dust-to-gas ratio constant in molecular clouds?</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, accepted for publication in MNRAS Letters, videos
  available at https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC7J6IDzQklFzKV3c6pBqxUg</comments><doi>10.1093/mnrasl/slx096</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We perform numerical simulations of dusty, supersonic turbulence in molecular
clouds. We model 0.1, 1 and 10 {\mu}m sized dust grains at an initial
dust-to-gas mass ratio of 1:100, solving the equations of combined gas and dust
dynamics where the dust is coupled to the gas through a drag term. We show
that, for 0.1 and 1 {\mu}m grains, the dust-to-gas ratio deviates by typically
10-20% from the mean, since the stopping time of the dust due to gas drag is
short compared to the dynamical time. Contrary to previous findings, we find no
evidence for orders of magnitude fluctuation in the dust-to-gas ratio for 0.1
{\mu}m grains. Larger, 10 {\mu}m dust grains may have dust-to-gas ratios
increased by up to an order of magnitude locally. Both small (0.1 {\mu}m) and
large ($\gtrsim$ 1 {\mu}m) grains trace the large-scale morphology of the gas,
however we find evidence for 'size-sorting' of grains, where turbulence
preferentially concentrates larger grains into dense regions. Size-sorting may
help to explain observations of 'coreshine' from dark clouds, and why
extinction laws differ along lines of sight through molecular clouds in the
Milky Way compared to the diffuse interstellar medium.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05113</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05113</id><created>2017-06-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Mu&#xf1;oz-Coreas</keyname><forenames>Edgard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thapliyal</keyname><forenames>Himanshu</forenames></author></authors><title>T-count Optimized Design of Quantum Integer Multiplication</title><categories>quant-ph cs.ET</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum circuits of many qubits are extremely difficult to realize; thus, the
number of qubits is an important metric in a quantum circuit design. Further,
scalable and reliable quantum circuits are based on Clifford + T gates. An
efficient quantum circuit saves quantum hardware resources by reducing the
number of T gates without substantially increasing the number of qubits.
Recently, the design of a quantum multiplier is presented by Babu [1] which
improves the existing works in terms of number of quantum gates, number of
qubits, and delay. However, the recent design is not based on fault-tolerant
Clifford + T gates. Also, it has large number of qubits and garbage outputs.
Therefore, this work presents a T-count optimized quantum circuit for integer
multiplication with only $4 \cdot n + 1$ qubits and no garbage outputs. The
proposed quantum multiplier design saves the T-count by using a novel quantum
conditional adder circuit. Also, where one operand to the controlled adder is
zero, the conditional adder is replaced with a Toffoli gate array to further
save the T gates. To have fair comparison with the recent design by Babu and
get an actual estimate of the T-count, it is made garbageless by using
Bennett's garbage removal scheme. The proposed design achieves an average
T-count savings of $47.55\%$ compared to the recent work by Babu. Further,
comparison is also performed with other recent works by Lin et. al. [2], and
Jayashree et. al.[3]. Average T-count savings of $62.71\%$ and $26.30\%$ are
achieved compared to the recent works by Lin et. al., and Jayashree et. al.,
respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05114</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05114</id><created>2017-06-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Mu&#xf1;oz-Coreas</keyname><forenames>Edgard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thapliyal</keyname><forenames>Himanshu</forenames></author></authors><title>Design of Quantum Circuits for Galois Field Squaring and Exponentiation</title><categories>quant-ph cs.ET</categories><comments>To appear in conference proceedings of the 2017 IEEE Computer Society
  Annual Symposium on VLSI (ISVLSI 2017)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work presents an algorithm to generate depth, quantum gate and qubit
optimized circuits for $GF(2^m)$ squaring in the polynomial basis. Further, to
the best of our knowledge the proposed quantum squaring circuit algorithm is
the only work that considers depth as a metric to be optimized. We compared
circuits generated by our proposed algorithm against the state of the art and
determine that they require $50 \%$ fewer qubits and offer gates savings that
range from $37 \%$ to $68 \%$. Further, existing quantum exponentiation are
based on either modular or integer arithmetic. However, Galois arithmetic is a
useful tool to design resource efficient quantum exponentiation circuit
applicable in quantum cryptanalysis. Therefore, we present the quantum circuit
implementation of Galois field exponentiation based on the proposed quantum
Galois field squaring circuit. We calculated a qubit savings ranging between
$44\%$ to $50\%$ and quantum gate savings ranging between $37 \%$ to $68 \%$
compared to identical quantum exponentiation circuit based on existing squaring
circuits.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05121</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05121</id><created>2017-06-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Stella</keyname><forenames>Massimo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Selakovic</keyname><forenames>Sanja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Antonioni</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andreazzi</keyname><forenames>Cecilia S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Community interactions determine role of species in parasite spread
  amplification: the ecomultiplex network model</title><categories>q-bio.QM physics.bio-ph physics.data-an q-bio.PE</categories><comments>11 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Most of zoonoses are multi-host parasites with multiple transmission routes
that are usually investigated separately despite their potential interplay. As
a unifying framework for modelling parasite spread through different paths of
infection, we suggest &quot;ecomultiplex&quot; networks, i.e. multiplex networks
representing interacting animal communities with (i) spatial structure and (ii)
metabolic scaling. We exploit this ecological framework for testing potential
control strategies for $T. cruzii$ spread in two real-world ecosystems. Our
investigation highlights two interesting results. Firstly, the ecomultiplex
topology can be as efficient as more data-demanding epidemiological measures in
identifying which species facilitate parasite spread. Secondly, the interplay
between predator-prey and host-parasite interactions leads to a phenomenon of
parasite amplification in which top predators facilitate $T. cruzii$ spread,
offering theoretical interpretation of previous empirical findings. Our
approach is broadly applicable and could provide novel insights in designing
immunisation strategies for pathogens with multiple transmission routes in
real-world ecosystems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05129</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05129</id><created>2017-06-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Phan</keyname><forenames>G. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakayama</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sugawara</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sato</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Urata</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanabe</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanigaki</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nabeshima</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Imai</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maeda</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takahashi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects of strain on the electronic structure, superconductivity, and
  nematicity in FeSe studied by angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 224507 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.224507</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One of central issues in iron-based superconductors is the role of structural
change to the superconducting transition temperature (T_c). It was found in
FeSe that the lattice strain leads to a drastic increase in T_c, accompanied by
suppression of nematic order. By angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy on
tensile- or compressive-strained and strain-free FeSe, we experimentally show
that the in-plane strain causes a marked change in the energy overlap
(DeltaE_{h-e}) between the hole and electron pockets in the normal state. The
change in DeltaE_{h-e} modifies the Fermi-surface volume, leading to a change
in T_c. Furthermore, the strength of nematicity is also found to be
characterized by DeltaE_{h-e}. These results suggest that the key to
understanding the phase diagram is the fermiology and interactions linked to
the semimetallic band overlap.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05154</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05154</id><created>2017-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Nakajima</keyname><forenames>Hiraku</forenames></author></authors><title>Introduction to a provisional mathematical definition of Coulomb
  branches of $3$-dimensional $\mathcal N=4$ gauge theories</title><categories>math.RT hep-th math-ph math.AG math.DG math.MP</categories><comments>18 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is an introduction to a provisional mathematical definition of Coulomb
branches of $3$-dimensional $\mathcal N=4$ supersymmetric gauge theories,
studied in arXiv:1503.03676, arXiv:1601.03586. This is an expanded version of
an article arXiv:1612.09014 appeared in the 61st DAISUUGAKU symposium
proceeding (2016), written originally in Japanese.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05175</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05175</id><created>2017-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Michael</keyname><affiliation>Misha</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bialy</keyname></author><author><keyname>Mironov</keyname><forenames>Andrey</forenames></author></authors><title>In search of periodic solutions for a reduction of the Benney chain</title><categories>math-ph math.DS math.MP</categories><comments>10 p</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We search for smooth periodic solutions for the system of quasi-linear PDEs
known as the Lax dispersionless reduction of the Benney moments chain. It is
naturally related to the existence of a polynomial in momenta integral for a
Classical Hamiltonian system with 1,5 degrees of freedom. For the solution in
question it is not known a-priori if the system is elliptic or hyperbolic or of
mixed type. We consider two possible regimes for the solution. The first is the
case of only one real eigenvalue, where we can completely classify the
solutions. The second case of strict Hyperbolicity is really a challenge. We
find a remarkable 2 by 2 reduction which is strictly Hyperbolic but violates
the condition of genuine non-linearity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05177</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05177</id><created>2017-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Hou</keyname><forenames>Zhipeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ren</keyname><forenames>Weijun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Bei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Guizhou</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yue</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Bing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Qiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Ying</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Enke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Wenhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Guangheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xi-xiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Baogen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Zhidong</forenames></author></authors><title>Observation of Various and Spontaneous Magnetic Skyrmionic Bubbles at
  Room-Temperature in a Frustrated Kagome Magnet with Uniaxial Magnetic
  Anisotropy</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Accept by Advanced Materials. Version of Record online : 7 JUN 2017
  DOI: 10.1002/adma.201701144</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Various and spontaneous magnetic skyrmionic bubbles are experimentally
observed for the first time, at room temperature in a frustrated kagome magnet
Fe3Sn2 with unixial magnetic anisotropy. The magnetization dynamics were
investigated using in-situ Lorentz transmission electron microscopy, revealing
that the transformation between different magnetic bubbles and domains are via
the motion of Bloch lines driven by applied external magnetic field. The
results demonstrate that Fe3Sn2 facilitates a unique magnetic control of
topological spin textures at room temperature, making it a promising candidate
for further skyrmion-based spintronic devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05184</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05184</id><created>2017-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Mori</keyname><forenames>Ryuhei</forenames></author></authors><title>Average Length of Cycles in Rectangular Lattice</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech math.CO</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the number of cycles and their average length in $L\times N$ lattice
by using classical method of transfer matrix. In this work, we derive a
bivariate generating function $G_3(y, z)$ in which a coefficient of $y^i z^j$
is the number of cycles of length $i$ in $3\times j$ lattice. By using the
bivariate generating function, we show that the average length of cycles in
$3\times N$ lattice is $\alpha N + \beta + o(1)$ where $\alpha$ and $\beta$ are
some algebraic numbers approximately equal to 3.166 and 0.961, respectively. We
argue generalizations of this method for $L\ge 4$, and obtain a generating
function of the number of cycles in $L\times N$ lattice for $L$ up to 7.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05189</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05189</id><created>2017-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Schmelz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zakosarenko</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xf6;nau</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anders</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kunert</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meyer</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meyer</keyname><forenames>H. -G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stolz</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>A new family of field-stable and highly sensitive SQUID current sensors
  based on sub-micrometer cross-type Josephson junctions</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Superconductor Science and Technology, 30, p. 074010 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6668/aa7216</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the development of a new family of SQUID current sensors based
on sub-micron cross-type Josephson tunnel junctions. Their low total junction
capacitance permit high usable voltage swings of more than 100 {\mu}V and
exceptional low noise of the SQUIDs at 4.2 K. Integrated rf-filter as well as
high tolerable background fields during cool-down of up to 9.6 mT enable their
highly reliable and easy use. With input coil inductances ranging from 10 nH to
2.8 {\mu}H and current sensitivities and coupled energy resolution down to 65
fA/Hz^{1/2} and below 10 h, respectively, they are a versatile tool for
numerous applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05195</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05195</id><created>2017-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Naze</keyname><forenames>Yael</forenames><affiliation>ULg</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Rauw</keyname><forenames>Gregor</forenames><affiliation>ULg</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Cazorla</keyname><forenames>Constantin</forenames><affiliation>ULg</affiliation></author></authors><title>pi Aqr is another gamma-Cas object</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>5 pages, letter accepted by A&amp;A</comments><journal-ref>A&amp;A, 602, L5 (5p, 2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201731135</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The gamma-Cas category is a subgroup of Be stars displaying a strong, hard,
and variable thermal X-ray emission. An XMM-Newton observation of pi Aqr
reveals spectral and temporal characteristics that clearly make this Be star
another member of the gamma-Cas category. Furthermore, pi Aqr is a binary but,
contrary to gamma-Cas, the nature of the companion to the Be star is known; it
is a non-degenerate (stellar) object and its small separation from the Be star
does not leave much room for a putative compact object close to the Be disk.
This renders the accretion scenario difficult to apply in this system, and,
hence, this discovery favors a disk-related origin for the gamma-Cas
phenomenon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05207</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05207</id><created>2017-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Davy</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gnatiuk</keyname><forenames>Natalia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pettersson</keyname><forenames>Lasse</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bobylev</keyname><forenames>Leonid</forenames></author></authors><title>Climate change impacts on wind energy potential in the European domain</title><categories>physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>15 pages. 9 Figures</comments><doi>10.1016/j.rser.2017.05.253</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  We may anticipate that climate change will bring changes to the intensity and
variability of near surface winds, either through local effects or by altering
the large-scale flow. The impact of climate change on European wind resources
has been assessed using a single-model-ensemble of the latest regional climate
model from the Rossby Centre, RCA4. These simulations used data from five of
the global climate models in the contemporary Climate Model Intercomparison
Project (CMIP5) as boundary conditions, and the results are publicly available
under the COordinated Regional climate Downscaling EXperiment (CORDEX) project.
Overall we find a consistent pattern of a decrease in the wind resources over
the European domain under both the RCP 4.5 and RCP 8.5 scenarios, although
there are some regions, principally North Africa and the Barents Sea, with
projected increases in wind resources. The pattern of change is both robust
across the choice of scenario, and persistent: there is a very similar pattern
of change found in the latter part of the 21st century as in the earlier. A
case study was chosen to assess the potential for offshore wind-farms in the
Black Sea region. We developed a realistic methodology for extrapolating
near-surface wind speeds up to hub-height using a time-varying roughness
length, and determined the extractable wind power at hub-height using a
realistic model of contemporary wind-turbine energy production. We demonstrate
that, unlike much of the Mediterranean basin, there is no robust pattern of a
negative climate change impact on wind resources in the studied regions of the
Black Sea. Furthermore, the seasonality of wind resources, with a strong peak
in the winter, matches well to the seasonality of energy-demand in the region,
making offshore wind-farms in the Black Sea region a viable source of energy
for neighbouring countries.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05217</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05217</id><created>2017-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Gharti</keyname><forenames>Hom Nath</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oye</keyname><forenames>Volker</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roth</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuehn</keyname><forenames>Daniela</forenames></author></authors><title>Wave propagation modelling in various microearthquake environments using
  a spectral-element method</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 19 figures, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Simulation of wave propagation in a microearthquake environment is often
challenging due to small-scale structural and material heterogeneities. We
simulate wave propagation in three different real microearthquake environments
using a spectral-element method. In the first example, we compute the full
wavefield in 2D and 3D models of an underground ore mine, namely the Pyhaesalmi
mine in Finland. In the second example, we simulate wave propagation in a
homogeneous velocity model including the actual topography of an unstable rock
slope at Aaknes in western Norway. Finally, we compute the full wavefield for a
weakly anisotropic cylindrical sample at laboratory scale, which was used for
an acoustic emission experiment under triaxial loading. We investigate the
characteristic features of wave propagation in those models and compare
synthetic waveforms with observed waveforms wherever possible. We illustrate
the challenges associated with the spectral-element simulation in those models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05223</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05223</id><created>2017-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Norman</keyname><forenames>Jaime</forenames><affiliation>for the ALICE collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>Open heavy-flavour measurements in pp and p--Pb collisions with ALICE at
  the LHC</title><categories>hep-ex nucl-ex</categories><comments>Proceedings of 55th International Winter Meeting on Nuclear Physics,
  Bormio, Italy, 23-27 January 2017. 10 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ALICE detector is well suited to measure heavy-flavour (charm and beauty)
production via hadronic and semi-leptonic decay channels of heavy-flavour
particles. Here an overview of heavy-flavour measurements made with the ALICE
detector during Run 1 in pp and p--Pb collisions is presented and discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05229</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05229</id><created>2017-06-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Neznamov</keyname><forenames>V. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shemarulin</keyname><forenames>V. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Motion of half-spin particles in the axially symmetric field of naked
  singularities of static q-metric</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>22 pages, 5 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>Gravitation and Cosmology, 2017, Vol. 23, No. 2, pp. 149-161</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S0202289317020050</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum-mechanical motion of a half-spin particle was examined in the axially
symmetric field of static naked singularities formed by mass distribution with
quadrupole moment (q-metric). The analysis was performed by means of the method
of effective potentials of the Dirac equation generalized for the case when
radial and angular variables are not separated. As $-1&lt;q&lt;q_{lim}, |q_{lim}|&lt;&lt;1
$ the naked singularities do not except the existence of stationary bound
states of Dirac particles for a prolate mass distribution in the q-metric along
the axial axis. For the oblate mass distribution, the naked singularities of
the q-metric are separated from the Dirac particle by infinitely large
repulsive barriers with the subsequent potential well deepening while moving
along the angle from the equator (or from $\theta=\theta_{min},
\theta=\pi-\theta_{min}$) towards poles. The exception are the poles and, as
$0&lt;q&lt;q*$, some points $\theta_{i}$ for the states of the particle with j&gt;=3/2.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05236</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05236</id><created>2017-06-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Weyburne</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Does the Outer Region of the Turbulent Boundary Layer Display Similar
  Behavior?</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>27 pages, 16 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent theoretical results together with established theory have identified
the displacement thickness and the velocity at the boundary layer edge as
similarity scaling parameter candidates for the wall-bounded turbulent boundary
layer. In the work described herein, we examine these scaling parameters along
with the Prandtl Plus scaling's and the Zagarola and Smits scaling's to search
for similarity in the outer region of experimental turbulent boundary layer
velocity profile datasets. A new integral area method combined with the
traditional chi-by-eye method is used to search for similar velocity profiles.
The results indicate that strict whole profile similarity is not evident in any
of the datasets we searched. However, ten datasets are found that display
&quot;similar-like&quot; behavior using the ratio of the inner to outer thickness ratio
as a search criterion. In alignment with theory, the preferred similarity
scaling parameters for the similar-like behavior case are the displacement
thickness and the velocity at the boundary layer edge. It was found that there
are a few datasets for which the Prandtl Plus scaling and the Zagarola and
Smits scaling also work.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05237</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05237</id><created>2017-06-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Hayasaki</keyname><forenames>Yoshio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fukuda</keyname><forenames>Shin-ichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hasegawa</keyname><forenames>Satoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Juodkazis</keyname><forenames>Saulius</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-color pump-probe interferometry of ultra-fast light-matter
  interaction</title><categories>physics.optics physics.app-ph</categories><comments>6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two-color side-view probing of light-matter interaction from minute focal
volume of a tightly focused fs-laser pump pulse reveals charge dynamics with
high 0.9 micrometers optical resolution and approximately ~20 fs temporal
resolution in coincidence between pump and probe pulses. Use of two colors is
advantageous for probing optically excited plasma regions with different
density. Holographical digital focusing and spatial filtering were implemented
to obtain the same resolution images for subsequent Fourier analysis. Fast
electron removal with time constant ~150 fs was resolved and is consistent with
self-trapping. Potential applications of an optical control over a
light-induced defect placement with deep-sub-wavelength resolution is
discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05240</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05240</id><created>2017-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Diller</keyname><forenames>Katharina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maurer</keyname><forenames>Reinhard J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>Moritz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reuter</keyname><forenames>Karsten</forenames></author></authors><title>Interpretation of X-ray Absorption Spectroscopy in the Presence of
  Surface Hybridization</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>The Journal of Chemical Physics 146, 214701 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4984072</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  X-ray absorption spectroscopy yields direct access to the electronic and
geometric structure of hybrid inorganic-organic interfaces formed upon
adsorption of complex molecules at metal surfaces. The unambiguous
interpretation of corresponding spectra is challenged by the intrinsic
geometric flexibility of the adsorbates and the chemical interactions with the
interface. Density-functional theory (DFT) calculations of the extended
adsorbate-substrate system are an established tool to guide peak assignment in
X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) of complex interfaces. We extend this to
the simulation and interpretation of X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) data
in the context of functional organic molecules on metal surfaces using
dispersion-corrected DFT calculations within the transition potential approach.
On the example of X-ray absorption signatures for the prototypical case of
2H-porphine adsorbed on Ag(111) and Cu(111) substrates, we follow the two main
effects of the molecule/surface interaction on XAS: (1) the substrate-induced
chemical shift of the 1s core levels that dominates in physisorbed systems and
(2) the hybridization-induced broadening and loss of distinct resonances that
dominates in more chemisorbed systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05252</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05252</id><created>2017-06-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Donald C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Is there a resting frame in the universe? A proposed experimental test
  based on a precise measurement of particle mass</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. Plus (2017) 132: 140</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjp/i2017-11402-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  According to the Special Theory of Relativity, there should be no resting
frame in our universe. Such an assumption, however, could be in conflict with
the Standard Model of cosmology today, which regards the vacuum not as an empty
space. Thus, there is a strong need to experimentally test whether there is a
resting frame in our universe or not. We propose that this can be done by
precisely measuring the masses of two charged particles moving in opposite
directions. If all inertial frames are equivalent, there should be no
detectable mass difference between these two particles. If there is a resting
frame in the universe, one will observe a mass difference that is dependent on
the orientation of the laboratory frame. The detailed experimental setup is
discussed in this paper.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05254</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05254</id><created>2017-06-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Gansterer</keyname><forenames>Margaretha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hartl</keyname><forenames>Richard F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Collaborative vehicle routing: a survey</title><categories>cs.MA cs.AI cs.CY math.OC physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In horizontal collaborations, carriers form coalitions in order to perform
parts of their logistics operations jointly. By exchanging transportation
requests among each other, they can operate more efficiently and in a more
sustainable way. Collaborative vehicle routing has been extensively discussed
in the literature. We identify three major streams of research: (i) centralized
collaborative planning, (ii) decentralized planning without auctions, and (ii)
auction-based decentralized planning. For each of them we give a structured
overview on the state of knowledge and discuss future research directions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05276</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05276</id><created>2017-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Lau</keyname><forenames>August</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yin</keyname><forenames>Chuan</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantitative and Qualitative Seismic Imaging and Seismic Inversion</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 13 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider seismic imaging to include seismic inversion. Imaging could use
approximate operator or time instead of depth. Processing in time is an
important part of seismic imaging as well as processing in depth. We can
classify seismic imaging as quantitative versus qualitative methods.
Quantitative method uses numerical methods to find the solution whose modeled
seismic data approximates the input seismic records. Then we will progress to
qualitative methods which have three aspects. The first aspect will be topology
and geometry. The second aspect is semigroup method. The third aspect is to use
non-differentiable solution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05307</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05307</id><created>2017-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Gelagutashvili</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bagdavadze</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rcheulishvili</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Biosorption of Cr(III), Cr(VI), Cu(II) ions by intact cells of Spirulina
  platensis</title><categories>physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>8 pages,0 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The absorption characteristics of Cr(III), Cr(VI), Cu(II) ions on intact
living cells Spirulina platensis (pH9.6) were studied by using a UV-VIS
spectrophotometer. Also biosorption of these ions with cyanobacteria Spirulina
platensis were studied using equilibrium dialysis and atomic absorption
analysis.It was shown, that the absorption intensity of Spirulina platensis
decreases, when Cr(III), Cr(VI), Cu(II) ions are added. Significant difference
between the absorption intensity for Cu(II) Spirulina platensis and Cr(VI),
Cr(III) Spirulina platensis were observed. Cu(II) was more effectively adsorbed
by cyanobacterium than Cr(VI) and Cr(III). The biosorption constants for Cu(II)
Spirulina platensis is higher than for Cr(VI) and Cr(III) Spirulina platensis
2.69 and 10.15- fold respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05312</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05312</id><created>2017-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Ahmed</keyname><forenames>Muhammad Arslan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>Ati</forenames></author></authors><title>New equilibrium solution branches of plane Couette flow discovered using
  a project-then-search method</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>31 pages, 14 figures. To be submitted to the Journal of Fluid
  Mechanics</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  New equilibrium solution branches for plane Couette flow are reported which
add to the inventory of known solution branches. The exact solutions are found
by projecting known equilibria onto the resolvent modes of McKeon &amp; Sharma (J.
Fl. Mech., vol. 658, 2010, pp. 336-382) to generate approximate solutions that
are subsequently used as seeds in a Newton-Krylov-hookstep search. Searches
initialised with these projections have a convergence rate of 96%, leading to
the discovery of 16 new equilibria. The low-dimensional nature of the resulting
equilibria is attributed to the projection generated by the resolvent model;
resolvent modes for a given equilibrium solution span a low-dimensional space
which the solution approximately inhabits. This property is exploited to
generate new branches of equilibria in plane Couette flow, and to jump to known
branches. The new branches include bifurcations from previously known
bifurcation curves and a disconnected bifurcation curve which displays
interesting behaviour when continued in Reynolds number. The unstable manifolds
of the new exact coherent states are also computed to expand the known state
space structure of plane Couette flow.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05315</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05315</id><created>2017-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Moayed</keyname><forenames>Mohammad Mehdi Ramin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bielewicz</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zollner</keyname><forenames>Martin Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herrmann</keyname><forenames>Carmen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klinke</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author></authors><title>Towards colloidal spintronics through Rashba spin-orbit interaction in
  lead sulphide nanosheets</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>25 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 8 (2017) 15721</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms15721</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Employing the spin degree of freedom of charge carriers offers the
possibility to extend the functionality of conventional electronic devices,
while colloidal chemistry can be used to synthesize inexpensive and tuneable
nanomaterials. In order to benefit from both concepts, Rashba spin-orbit
interaction has been investigated in colloidal lead sulphide nanosheets by
electrical measurements on the circular photo-galvanic effect. Lead sulphide
nanosheets possess rock salt crystal structure, which is centrosymmetric. The
symmetry can be broken by quantum confinement, asymmetric vertical interfaces
and a gate electric field leading to Rashba-type band splitting in momentum
space at the M points, which results in an unconventional selection mechanism
for the excitation of the carriers. The effect, which is supported by
simulations of the band structure using density functional theory, can be tuned
by the gate electric field and by the thickness of the sheets. Spin-related
electrical transport phenomena in colloidal materials open a promising pathway
towards future inexpensive spintronic devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05334</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05334</id><created>2017-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Steffen</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koning</keyname><forenames>Nico</forenames></author></authors><title>Hybrid polygon and hydrodynamic nebula modeling with multi-waveband
  radiation transfer in astrophysics</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>Astronomy and Computing, 13 pages, 7 figures, in press</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate the potential for research and outreach of mixed polygon and
hydrodynamic modeling and multi-waveband rendering in the interactive 3-D
astrophysical virtual laboratory Shape. In 3-D special effects and animation
software for the mass media, computer graphics techniques that mix polygon and
numerical hydrodynamics have become common place. In astrophysics, however,
interactive modeling with polygon structures has only become available with the
software Shape. Numerical hydrodynamic simulations and their visualization are
usually separate, while in Shape it is integrated with the polygon modeling
approach that requires no programming by the user. With two generic examples,
we demonstrate that research and outreach modeling can be achieved with
techniques similar to those used in the media industry with the added
capability for physical rendering at any wavelength band, yielding more
realistic radiation modeling. Furthermore, we show how the hydrodynamics and
the polygon mesh modeling can be mixed to achieve results that are superior to
those obtained using either one of these modeling techniques alone.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05336</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05336</id><created>2017-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Majumdar</keyname><forenames>Sayantan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Foucard</keyname><forenames>Louis C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levine</keyname><forenames>Alex J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gardel</keyname><forenames>Margaret L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Encoding Mechano-Memories in Actin Networks</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.bio-ph physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>18 pages, under review</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Understanding the response of complex materials to external force is central
to fields ranging from materials science to biology. Here, we describe a novel
type of mechanical adaptation in cross-linked networks of F-actin, a
ubuiquitous protein found in eukaryotic cells. We show that shear stress
changes its nonlinear mechanical response even long after that stress is
removed. The duration, magnitude and direction of forcing history all impact
changes in mechanical response. The `memory' of the forcing history is
long-lived, but can be erased by force application in the opposite direction.
We further show that the observed mechanical adaptation is consistent with
stress-dependent changes in the nematic order of the constituent filaments.
Thus, this mechano-memory is a type of nonlinear hysteretic response in which
an applied, &quot;training&quot; strain modifies the nonlinear elasticity. This
demonstrates that F-actin networks can encode analog read-write
mechano-memories, which can be used for adaptation to mechanical stimuli.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05359</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05359</id><created>2017-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Barick</keyname><forenames>B. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dhar</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Photoinduced electromotive force on the surface of InN epitaxial layers</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the generation of photo-induced electromotive force (EMF) on the
surface of c-axis oriented InN epitaxial films grown on sapphire substrates. It
has been found that under the illumination of above band gap light, EMFs of
different magnitudes and polarities are developed on different parts of the
surface of these layers. The effect is not the same as the surface photovoltaic
or Dember potential effects, both of which result in the development of EMF
across the layer thickness, not between different contacts on the surface.
These layers are also found to show negative photoconductivity effect.
Interplay between surface photo-EMF and negative photoconductivity result in a
unique scenario, where the magnitude as well as the sign of the photo-induced
change in conductivity become bias dependent. A theoretical model is developed,
where both the effects are attributed to the 2D electron gas (2DEG) channel
formed just below the film surface as a result of the transfer of electrons
from certain donor-like-surfacestates, which are likely to be resulting due to
the adsorption of certain groups/adatoms on the film surface. In the model, the
photo-EMF effect is explained in terms of a spatially inhomogeneous
distribution of these groups/adatoms over the surface resulting in a lateral
non-uniformity in the depth distribution of the potential profile confining the
2DEG. Existence of such an inhomogeneity in the distribution of surface
potential has indeed been experimentally found for these layers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05369</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05369</id><created>2017-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Biktemerova</keyname><forenames>S. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Botvinko</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chirskaya</keyname><forenames>N. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eremeev</keyname><forenames>V. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garipov</keyname><forenames>G. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grebenyuk</keyname><forenames>V. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grinyuk</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jeong</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalmykov</keyname><forenames>N. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaznacheeva</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khrenov</keyname><forenames>B. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klimov</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lavrova</keyname><forenames>M. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martinez</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panasyuk</keyname><forenames>M. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>I. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrov</keyname><forenames>V. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ponce</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Puchkov</keyname><forenames>A. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salazar</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saprykin</keyname><forenames>O. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Senkovsky</keyname><forenames>A. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharakin</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shirokov</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tkachenko</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tkachev</keyname><forenames>L. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yashin</keyname><forenames>I. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zotov</keyname><forenames>M. Yu.</forenames></author></authors><title>Search for extreme energy cosmic ray candidates in the TUS orbital
  experiment data</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>13 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  TUS (Track Ultraviolet Setup) is the first space experiment aimed to check
the possibility of registering extreme energy cosmic rays (EECRs) at E&gt;50 EeV
by measuring the fluorescence signal of extensive air showers in the
atmosphere. The detector operates as a part of the scientific payload of the
Lomonosov satellite for more than a year. We describe an algorithm of searching
for EECR events in the TUS data and briefly discuss a number of candidates
selected by formal criteria.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
