<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T22:01:19Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-04-02" from="2016-04-01" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1206.0668</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1206.0668</id><created>2012-06-04</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bertolini</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eeg</keyname><forenames>Jan O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maiezza</keyname><forenames>Alessio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nesti</keyname><forenames>Fabrizio</forenames></author></authors><title>New physics in \epsilon' from chromomagnetic contributions and limits on
  Left-Right symmetry</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, Eq. 12 and related numerics amended</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.86.095013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  New physics in the chromomagnetic flavor changing transition s-&gt;dg* can avoid
the strong GIM suppression of the Standard Model and lead to large
contributions to CP-violating observables, in particular to the epsilon'
parameter, that we address here. We discuss the case of the Left-Right
symmetric models, where this contribution implies bounds on the phases of the
right-handed quark mixing matrix, or in generic models with large phases a
strong bound on the Left-Right symmetry scale. To the leading order, a numeric
formula for epsilon' as a function of the short-distance coefficients for a
wide class of models of new physics is given.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1207.1492</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1207.1492</id><created>2012-07-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Chimento</keyname><forenames>Luis P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richarte</keyname><forenames>Mart&#xed;n G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Interacting dark matter and modified holographic Ricci dark energy plus
  a noninteracting cosmic component</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures, Revtex 4.0. Phys. Rev. D 85, 127301 (2012)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 85, 127301 (2012)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.85.127301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate a spatially flat Friedmann-Robertson-Walker universe that has
an interacting dark matter, a modified holographic Ricci dark energy (MHRDE),
plus a third, decoupled component that behaves as a radiation term. We consider
a nonlinear interaction in the dark component densities and their derivatives
up to second order. We apply the $\chi^{2}$ method to the observational Hubble
data for constraining the cosmological parameters and analyze the amount of
dark energy in the radiation era for both MHRDE and holographic Ricci dark
energy models. The former is consistent with the bound $\Omega_{x}(z\simeq
1100)&lt;0.1$ reported for the behavior of dark energy at early times while the
latter does not fulfill it.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1208.1684</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1208.1684</id><created>2012-08-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Merz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schweiss</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolf</keyname><forenames>Th.</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xf6;hneysen</keyname><forenames>H. v.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schuppler</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electronic structure of single-crystalline Mg$_x$Al$_{1-x}$B$_2$ probed
  by x-ray diffraction multipole refinements and polarization-dependent x-ray
  absorption spectroscopy</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 83, 024714 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.83.024714</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  X-ray diffraction multipole refinements of single-crystalline
Mg$_x$Al$_{1-x}$B$_2$ and polarization-dependent near-edge x-ray absorption
fine structure at the B 1$s$ edge reveal a strongly anisotropic electronic
structure. Comparing the data for superconducting compounds ($x= 0.8$, 1.0)
with those for the non-superconductor ($x=0$) gives direct evidence for a
rearrangement of the hybridizations of the boron $p_z$ bonds and underline the
importance of holes in the $\sigma$-bonded covalent $sp^2$ states for the
superconducting properties of the diborides. The data indicate that Mg is
approximately divalent in MgB$_2$ and suggest predominantly ionic bonds between
the Mg ions and the two-dimensional B rings. For AlB$_2$ ($x=0$), on the other
hand, about 1.5 electrons per Al atom are transferred to the B sheets while the
residual 1.5 electrons remain at the Al site which suggests significant
covalent bonding between the Al ions and the B sheets. This finding together
with the static electron deformation density points to almost equivalent
electron counts on B sheets of MgB$_2$ and AlB$_2$\@, yet with a completely
different electron/hole distribution between the $\sigma$ and $\pi$ bonds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1310.5335</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1310.5335</id><created>2013-10-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Chimento</keyname><forenames>Luis P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richarte</keyname><forenames>Mart&#xed;n G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>Iv&#xe1;n E. S&#xe1;nchez</forenames></author></authors><title>Interacting dark sector with variable vacuum energy</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages,3 figures, 2 tables.
  (http://prd.aps.org/abstract/PRD/v88/i8/e087301)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 88, 087301 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.88.087301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine a cosmological scenario where dark matter is coupled to a variable
vacuum energy while baryons and photons are two decoupled components for a
spatially flat Friedmann-Robertson-Walker spacetime. We apply the $\chi^{2}$
method to the updated observational Hubble data for constraining the
cosmological parameters and analyze the amount of dark energy in the radiation
era. We show that our model fulfills the severe bound of $\Omega_{x}(z\simeq
1100)&lt;0.009$ at the $2\sigma$ level, so it is consistent with the recent
analysis that includes cosmic microwave background anisotropy measurements from
the Planck survey, the Atacama Cosmology Telescope, and the South Pole
Telescope along with the future constraints achievable by the Euclid and CMBPol
experiments, and fulfills the stringent bound $\Omega_{x}(z\simeq
10^{10})&lt;0.04$ at the $2\sigma$ level in the big-bang nucleosynthesis epoch.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1311.6321</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1311.6321</id><created>2013-11-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Shang-Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goan</keyname><forenames>Hsi-Sheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Xin-Qi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Milburn</keyname><forenames>G. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Generation and stabilization of a three-qubit entangled W state in
  circuit QED via quantum feedback control</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Accepted by Phys. Rev. A (single-column 20 pages, 6 figures)</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review A 88, 062311 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.88.062311</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Circuit cavity quantum electrodynamics (QED) is proving to be a powerful
platform to implement quantum feedback control schemes due to the ability to
control superconducting qubits and microwaves in a circuit. Here, we present a
simple and promising quantum feedback control scheme for deterministic
generation and stabilization of a three-qubit $W$ state in the superconducting
circuit QED system. The control scheme is based on continuous joint Zeno
measurements of multiple qubits in a dispersive regime, which enables us not
only to infer the state of the qubits for further information processing but
also to create and stabilize the target $W$ state through adaptive quantum
feedback control. We simulate the dynamics of the proposed quantum feedback
control scheme using the quantum trajectory approach with an effective
stochastic maser equation obtained by a polaron-type transformation method and
demonstrate that in the presence of moderate environmental decoherence, the
average state fidelity higher than $0.9$ can be achieved and maintained for a
considerable long time (much longer than the single-qubit decoherence time).
This control scheme is also shown to be robust against measurement inefficiency
and individual qubit decay rate differences. Finally, the comparison of the
polaron-type transformation method to the commonly used adiabatic elimination
method to eliminate the cavity mode is presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1401.5991</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1401.5991</id><created>2014-01-23</created><updated>2014-11-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bothe</keyname><forenames>Dieter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dreyer</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames></author></authors><title>Continuum thermodynamics of chemically reacting fluid mixtures</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><msc-class>Primary 76T10, Secondary 35Q35, 35Q80, 76A02, 80A17, 80A32, 92E20</msc-class><journal-ref>Acta Mechanica 226, 1757-1805 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00707-014-1275-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider viscous, heat conducting mixtures of molecularly miscible
chemical species forming a fluid in which the constituents can undergo chemical
reactions. Assuming a common temperature for all components, we derive a closed
system of partial mass and partial momentum balances plus a mixture balance of
internal energy. This is achieved by careful exploitation of the entropy
principle and requires appropriate definitions of absolute temperature and
chemical potentials, based on an adequate definition of thermal energy
excluding diffusive contributions. The resulting interaction forces split into
a thermo-mechanical and a chemical part, where the former turns out to be
symmetric in case of binary interactions. For chemically reacting systems and
as a new result, the chemical interaction force is a contribution being
non-symmetric outside of chemical equilibrium. The theory also provides a
rigorous derivation of the so-called generalized thermodynamic driving forces,
avoiding the use of approximate solutions to the Boltzmann equations. Moreover,
using an appropriately extended version of the entropy principle and
introducing cross-effects already before closure as entropy invariant couplings
between principal dissipative mechanisms, the Onsager symmetry relations become
a strict consequence. With a classification of the factors in the binary
products of the entropy production according to their parity--instead of the
classical partition into so-called fluxes and driving forces--the apparent
anti-symmetry of certain couplings is thereby also revealed. If the diffusion
velocities are small compared to the speed of sound, the Maxwell-Stefan
equations follow in the case without chemistry, thereby neglecting wave
phenomena in the diffusive motion. This results in a reduced model with only
mass being balanced individually. In the reactive case ...
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1402.0197</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1402.0197</id><created>2014-02-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Zubillaga</keyname><forenames>Dario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cruz</keyname><forenames>Geovany</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aguilar</keyname><forenames>Luis Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zapotecatl</keyname><forenames>Jorge</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fernandez</keyname><forenames>Nelson</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aguilar</keyname><forenames>Jose</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosenblueth</keyname><forenames>David A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gershenson</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author></authors><title>Measuring the Complexity of Self-organizing Traffic Lights</title><categories>nlin.AO cs.IT cs.SY math.IT nlin.CG physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 11 figures</comments><acm-class>F.1.1; D.2.8; F.1.3; J.2; H.1.1</acm-class><journal-ref>Entropy, 16(5):2384-2407. 2014</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/e16052384</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We apply measures of complexity, emergence and self-organization to an
abstract city traffic model for comparing a traditional traffic coordination
method with a self-organizing method in two scenarios: cyclic boundaries and
non-orientable boundaries. We show that the measures are useful to identify and
characterize different dynamical phases. It becomes clear that different
operation regimes are required for different traffic demands. Thus, not only
traffic is a non-stationary problem, which requires controllers to adapt
constantly. Controllers must also change drastically the complexity of their
behavior depending on the demand. Based on our measures, we can say that the
self-organizing method achieves an adaptability level comparable to a living
system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.0990</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.0990</id><created>2014-07-03</created><updated>2014-11-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Zeng-Qiang</forenames></author></authors><title>Equation of state and phase transition in spin-orbit-coupled Bose gases
  at finite temperature: A perturbation approach</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures; published in Phys. Rev. A</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 90, 053608 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.90.053608</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study two-component Bose gases with Raman induced spin-orbit coupling via
a perturbation approach at finite temperature. For weak coupling, free energy
is expanded in terms of Raman coupling strength up to the second order, where
the coefficient (referred to as Raman susceptibility) is determined according
to linear response theory. The equation of state for the stripe phase and the
plane-wave phase are obtained in Popov approximation, and the first order
transition between these two phases is investigated. As temperature increases,
we find the phase boundary bends toward the stripe phase side in most
temperature regions, which implies the ferromagnetic order is more robust than
the crystalline order in presence of thermal fluctuations. Our results
qualitatively agree with the recent experimental observation in rubidium atomic
gases. A method to measure the Raman susceptibility through the two-photon
Bragg scattering experiment is also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1408.6201</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1408.6201</id><created>2014-08-23</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Akama</keyname><forenames>Keiichi</forenames></author></authors><title>A Universal Origin of Information Accumulation in Nature</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, This is not a mere revision of v1 but a new paper to
  advocate a new physical law complementary to the entropy-increase law with
  new formulations and calculations. An endnote is added to expound it</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To account for the origin of information accumulation in nature despite the
entropy-increase law, we advocate a universal mechanism due to
competition/selection of general composite entities, from simple to complex. To
confirm its universality, we show that even simplest composites such as an
atom, a molecule etc. are subject to this mechanism and accumulate information.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.0215</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.0215</id><created>2014-08-31</created><updated>2015-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>B&#xe9;daride</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fernique</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>No Weak Local Rules for the 4p-Fold Tilings</title><categories>math.DS cs.DM math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>14 pages, 6 figures</comments><msc-class>37B50, 52C23</msc-class><journal-ref>Discrete and Computational Geometry 54 (2015), pp. 980--992</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00454-015-9740-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  On the one hand, Socolar showed in 1990 that the n-fold planar tilings admit
weak local rules when n is not divisible by 4 (the n=10 case corresponds to the
Penrose tilings and is known since 1974). On the other hand, Burkov showed in
1988 that the 8-fold tilings do not admit weak local rules, and Le showed the
same for the 12-fold tilings (unpublished). We here show that this is actually
the case for all the 4p-fold tilings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.7475</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.7475</id><created>2014-09-26</created><updated>2014-11-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gershenson</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author></authors><title>Requisite Variety, Autopoiesis, and Self-organization</title><categories>nlin.AO cs.OH</categories><comments>Invited keynote at WOSC 2014</comments><journal-ref>Kybernetes, 44(6-7):866-873. 2015</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ashby's law of requisite variety states that a controller must have at least
as much variety (complexity) as the controlled. Maturana and Varela proposed
autopoiesis (self-production) to define living systems. Living systems also
require to fulfill the law of requisite variety. A measure of autopoiesis has
been proposed as the ratio between the complexity of a system and the
complexity of its environment. Self-organization can be used as a concept to
guide the design of systems towards higher values of autopoiesis, with the
potential of making technology more &quot;living&quot;, i.e. adaptive and robust.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.3477</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.3477</id><created>2014-10-13</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pearson</keyname><forenames>Sarah</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xfc;pper</keyname><forenames>Andreas H. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnston</keyname><forenames>Kathryn V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Price-Whelan</keyname><forenames>Adrian M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Tidal Stream Morphology as an Indicator of Dark Matter Halo Geometry:
  the Case of Palomar 5</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 Figures, accepted by ApJ, minor edits to match the
  published version</comments><doi>10.1088/0004-637X/799/1/28</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents an example where the morphology of a single stellar
stream can be used to rule out a specific galactic potential form without the
need for velocity information. We investigate the globular cluster Palomar5
(Pal 5), which is tidally disrupting into a cold, thin stream mapped over 22
degrees on the sky with a typical width of 0.7 degrees. We generate models of
this stream by fixing Pal 5's present-day position, distance and radial
velocity via observations, while allowing its proper motion to vary. In a
spherical dark matter halo we easily find models that fit the observed
morphology. However, no plausible Pal 5 model could be found in the triaxial
potential of Law &amp; Majewski (2010), which has been proposed to explain the
properties of the Sagittarius stream. In this case, the long, thin and curved
morphology of the Pal5 stream alone can be used to rule out such a potential
configuration. Pal 5 like streams in this potential are either too straight,
missing the curvature of the observations, or show an unusual morphology which
we dub stream-fanning: a signature sensitive to the triaxiality of a potential.
We conclude that the mere existence of other thin tidal streams must provide
broad constraints on the orientation and shape of the dark matter halo they
inhabit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.4486</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.4486</id><created>2014-11-17</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Salnikov</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author></authors><title>Graded geometry in gauge theories and beyond</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.DG math.MP</categories><comments>version accepted to Journal of Geometry and Physics, updated
  references</comments><msc-class>58A50, 53D17, 70S15, 55N91</msc-class><doi>10.1016/j.geomphys.2014.07.001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study some graded geometric constructions appearing naturally in the
context of gauge theories. Inspired by a known relation of gauging with
equivariant cohomology we generalize the latter notion to the case of arbitrary
Q-manifolds introducing thus the concept of equivariant Q-cohomology. Using
this concept we describe a procedure for analysis of gauge symmetries of given
functionals as well as for constructing functionals (sigma models) invariant
under an action of some gauge group.
  As the main example of application of these constructions we consider the
twisted Poisson sigma model. We obtain it by a gauging-type procedure of the
action of an essentially infinite dimensional group and describe its symmetries
in terms of classical differential geometry.
  We comment on other possible applications of the described concept including
the analysis of supersymmetric gauge theories and higher structures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.6044</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.6044</id><created>2014-12-18</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Iles-Smith</keyname><forenames>Jake</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nazir</keyname><forenames>Ahsan</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum correlations of light and matter through environmental
  transitions</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 7 figures. v2 - minor edits. v3 - more substantial edits to
  the text. Title changed and new results on correlations added in Fig. 3. v4 -
  close to published version, presentation clarified</comments><journal-ref>Optica 3, 207 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OPTICA.3.000207</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One aspect of solid-state photonic devices that distinguishes them from their
atomic counterparts is the unavoidable interaction between system excitations
and lattice vibrations of the host material. This coupling may lead to
surprising departures in emission properties between solid-state and atomic
systems. Here we predict a striking and important example of such an effect. We
show that in solid-state cavity quantum electrodynamics, interactions with the
host vibrational environment can generate quantum cavity-emitter correlations
in regimes that are semiclassical for atomic systems. This behaviour, which can
be probed experimentally through the cavity emission properties, heralds a
failure of the semiclassical approach in the solid-state, and challenges the
notion that coupling to a thermal bath supports a more classical description of
the system. Furthermore, it does not rely on the spectral details of the host
environment under consideration and is robust to changes in temperature. It
should thus be of relevance to a wide variety of photonic devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.7901</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.7901</id><created>2014-12-26</created><updated>2015-03-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kariyado</keyname><forenames>Toshikaze</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hatsugai</keyname><forenames>Yasuhiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological Order Parameters of the Spin-1/2 Dimerized Heisenberg Ladder
  in Magnetic Field</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>Revised. 10 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 91, 214410 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.91.214410</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Topological properties of the spin-1/2 dimerized Heisenberg ladder are
investigated focusing on the plateau phase in the magnetic field whose
magnetization is half of the saturation value. Although the applied magnetic
field removes most of the symmetries of the system, there is a symmetry
protected topological phase supported by the spatial inversion symmetry. The
Z_2 Berry phase associated with a symmetry respecting boundary and quantized
into 0 and \pi is used as a symmetry protected topological order parameter.
Edge states are also analyzed to confirm the bulk-edge correspondence. In
addition, a symmetry breaking boundary is considered. Then, we observe a unique
type of quantization of the Berry phase, a quantization into +-\pi/2 of the
Berry phase. In this case, the bulk-edge correspondence is also unique, namely,
there emerge &quot;polarized&quot; edge states for the case with +-\pi/2 quantization. We
also evaluate the entanglement entropy by the infinite time-evolving block
decimation (iTEBD) to complement the Berry phase based arguments. Further, a
different type of the topological order parameter is extracted from the matrix
product state representation of the ground state given by the iTEBD.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.00234</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.00234</id><created>2014-12-31</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ojima</keyname><forenames>Izumi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okamura</keyname><forenames>Kazuya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saigo</keyname><forenames>Hayato</forenames></author></authors><title>Local state and sector theory in local quantum physics</title><categories>math-ph math.MP math.OA quant-ph</categories><comments>v2: 20 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We define a new concept of local states in the framework of algebraic quantum
field theory (AQFT). Local states are a natural generalization of states and
give a clear vision of localization in the context of QFT. In terms of them, we
can find a condition from which follows automatically the famous DHR selection
criterion in DHR-DR theory. As a result, we can understand the condition as
consequences of physically natural state preparations in vacuum backgrounds.
Furthermore, a theory of orthogonal decomposition of completely positive (CP)
maps is developed. It unifies a theory of orthogonal decomposition of states
and order structure theory of CP maps. By using it, localized version of
sectors is formulated, which gives sector theory for local states with respect
to general reference representations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.02857</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.02857</id><created>2015-02-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Wunderlich</keyname><forenames>Falk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kampfer</keyname><forenames>Burkhard</forenames></author></authors><title>Photon emission rates near the critical point in the linear sigma model</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>9th International Workshop on Critical Point and Onset of
  Deconfinement - CPOD2014 17-21 November 2014</comments><journal-ref>PoS CPOD 2014: 027 (2015)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Employing the linear sigma model, the effective masses of quasi-particle
excitations are found to exhibit significant variations within the phase
diagram, which has a critical point at non-zero chemical potential, where a
first-order phase transition sets in. Soft-photon emission rates in lowest
order display, for selected channels, a sensible dependence on the effective
masses of the involved excitations and let us argue that they could map out the
phase diagram.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.07724</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.07724</id><created>2015-03-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Ayral</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parcollet</keyname><forenames>Olivier</forenames></author></authors><title>Mott physics and spin fluctuations: a unified framework</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>7 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 92, 115109 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.92.115109</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a formalism for strongly correlated electrons systems which
consists in a local approximation of the dynamical three-leg interaction
vertex. This vertex is self-consistently computed with a quantum impurity model
with dynamical interactions in the charge and spin channels, similar to
dynamical mean field theory (DMFT) approaches. The electronic self-energy and
the polarization are both frequency and momentum dependent. The method
interpolates between the spin-fluctuation or GW approximations at weak coupling
and the atomic limit at strong coupling. We apply the formalism to the Hubbard
model on a two-dimensional square lattice and show that as interactions are
increased towards the Mott insulating state, the local vertex acquires a strong
frequency dependence, driving the system to a Mott transition, while at low
enough temperatures the momentum-dependence of the self-energy is enhanced due
to large spin fluctuations. Upon doping, we find a Fermi arc in the
one-particle spectral function, which is one signature of the pseudo-gap state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.02476</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.02476</id><created>2015-04-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Alicea</keyname><forenames>Jason</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fendley</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological phases with parafermions: theory and blueprints</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el quant-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 4 figures; slated for Annual Reviews of Condensed Matter
  Physics</comments><journal-ref>Annual Review of Condensed Matter Physics 7, 119-139 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1146/annurev-conmatphys-031115-011336</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We concisely review the recent evolution in the study of parafermions --
exotic emergent excitations that generalize Majorana fermions and similarly
underpin a host of novel phenomena. First we illustrate the intimate connection
between Z_3-symmetric &quot;spin&quot; chains and one-dimensional parafermion lattice
models, highlighting how the latter host a topological phase featuring
protected edge zero modes. We then tour several blueprints for the laboratory
realization of parafermion zero modes -- focusing on quantum
Hall/superconductor hybrids, quantum Hall bilayers, and two-dimensional
topological insulators -- and describe striking experimental fingerprints that
they provide. Finally, we discuss how coupled parafermion arrays in quantum
Hall architectures yield topological phases that potentially furnish hardware
for a universal, intrinsically decoherence-free quantum computer.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.04158</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.04158</id><created>2015-04-16</created><updated>2016-03-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Benton</keyname><forenames>Owen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sikora</keyname><forenames>Olga</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shannon</keyname><forenames>Nic</forenames></author></authors><title>Classical and quantum theories of proton disorder in hexagonal water ice</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>33 pages (21 in main text), 13 figures (9 in main text), expanded
  discussion of experiment with new subsection on thermodynamics</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 125143 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.125143</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It has been known since the pioneering work of Bernal, Fowler and Pauling
that common, hexagonal (Ih) water ice is the archetype of a frustrated material
: a proton-bonded network in which protons satisfy strong local constraints -
the &quot;ice rules&quot; - but do not order. While this proton disorder is well
established, there is now a growing body of evidence that quantum effects may
also have a role to play in the physics of ice at low temperatures. In this
Article we use a combination of numerical and analytic techniques to explore
the nature of proton correlations in both classical and quantum models of ice
Ih. In the case of classical ice Ih, we find that the ice rules have two,
distinct, consequences for scattering experiments - singular &quot;pinch points&quot;,
reflecting a zero-divergence condition on the uniform polarization of the
crystal, and broad, asymmetric features, coming from its staggered
polarisation. In the case of the quantum model, we find that the collective
quantum tunnelling of groups of protons can convert states obeying the ice
rules into a quantum liquid, whose excitations are birefringent, emergent
photons. We make explicit predictions for scattering experiments on both
classical and quantum ice Ih, and show how the quantum theory can explain the
&quot;wings&quot; of incoherent inelastic scattering observed in recent neutron
scattering experiments [Bove et al., Phys. Rev. Lett. 103, 165901 (2009)].
These results raise the intriguing possibility that the protons in ice Ih could
form a quantum liquid at low temperatures, in which protons are not merely
disordered, but continually fluctuate between different configurations obeying
the ice rules.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.04197</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.04197</id><created>2015-04-16</created><updated>2016-02-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tanaka</keyname><forenames>Masashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yanagisawa</keyname><forenames>Yusuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujioka</keyname><forenames>Masaya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Denholme</keyname><forenames>Saleem J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Funahashi</keyname><forenames>Shiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsushita</keyname><forenames>Yoshitaka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishizawa</keyname><forenames>Nobuo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamaguchi</keyname><forenames>Takahide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takeya</keyname><forenames>Hiroyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takano</keyname><forenames>Yoshihiko</forenames></author></authors><title>Origin of the Higher-$T_\rm{c}$ Phase in the K$_x$Fe$_{2-y}$Se$_2$
  System</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>14 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 85, 044710 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.85.044710</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Single crystals of K$_x$Fe$_{2-y}$Se$_2$ are prepared by quenching at various
temperatures. The crystals obtained at higher quenching temperatures have a
surface morphology with mesh-like texture. They show a sharp superconducting
transition at $T_\rm{c}$ ~32 K with a large shielding volume fraction. On the
other hand, the crystals prepared without quenching show an onset
superconducting transition at ~44 K and a zero resistivity around ~33 K, and
they possess island-like regions on the surface with a larger amount of Fe
incorporation. In-situ high-temperature single crystal X-ray diffraction
measurements tell us the Fe-vacancy ordered phase is generated at a temperature
region around 270 {\deg}C via iron diffusion. The creation of this Fe-vacancy
ordered phase may become a driving force of the growth of the higher $T_\rm{c}$
phase. The superconductivity at ~44 K is attributed to a metallic phase with no
Fe-vacancy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.04947</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.04947</id><created>2015-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>Ziliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Ying</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Hanyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xiang</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical Selection Rule based on Valley-Exciton Locking for 2D
  Valleytronics</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Light: Science &amp; Applications (2015) 4, e366</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/lsa.2015.139</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Optical selection rule fundamentally determines the optical transition
between energy states in a variety of physical systems from hydrogen atoms to
bulk crystals such as GaAs. It is important for optoelectronic applications
such as lasers, energy-dispersive X-ray spectroscopy and quantum computation.
Recently, single layer transition metal dichalcogenide (TMDC) exhibits valleys
in momentum space with nontrivial Berry curvature and excitons with large
binding energy. However, it is unclear how the unique valley degree of freedom
combined with the strong excitonic effect influences the optical excitation.
Here we discover a new set of optical selection rules in monolayer WS2,imposed
by valley and exciton angular momentum. We experimentally demonstrated such a
principle for second harmonic generation (SHG) and two-photon luminescence
(TPL). Moreover, the two-photon induced valley populations yield net circular
polarized photoluminescence after a sub-ps interexciton relaxation (2p-&gt;1s) and
last for 8 ps. The discovery of this new optical selection rule in valleytronic
2D system not only largely extend information degrees but sets a foundation in
control of optical transitions that is crucial to valley optoeletronic device
applications such as 2D valley-polarized light emitting diodes (LED), optical
switches and coherent control for quantum computing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.02041</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.02041</id><created>2015-05-08</created><updated>2016-02-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kazakov</keyname><forenames>D. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sperling</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>SUSY Production at the LHC without Missing P_T</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Paper is withdrawn by the author due to numerical errors</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider relatively rare events of SUSY production at the LHC without
missing $p_T$. Namely, we discuss the chargino production with further decay
into the W-boson and the neutralino when the masses of chargino and neutralino
differ by 80-90 GeV. In this case, in the final state one has two Ws and
missing $E_T$ but no missing $P_T$. The produced neutralinos are just busted
along Ws. Within the MSSM such events are quite probable in the region of
parameter space close to the EWSB border line. The excess in the W production
cross-section may achieve a few \%.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.07984</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.07984</id><created>2015-05-29</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lanotte</keyname><forenames>Alessandra Sabina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benzi</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malapaka</keyname><forenames>Shiva Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toschi</keyname><forenames>Federico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Biferale</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author></authors><title>Turbulence on a Fractal Fourier set</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn nlin.CD</categories><journal-ref>Open Access Phys. Rev. Lett. 115, 264502 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.115.264502</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A novel investigation of the nature of intermittency in incompressible,
homogeneous and isotropic turbulence is performed by a numerical study of the
Navier-Stokes equations constrained on a fractal Fourier set. The robustness of
the energy transfer and of the vortex stretching mechanisms is tested by
changing the fractal dimension, D, from the original three dimensional case to
a strongly decimated system with D=2.5, where only about $3\%$ of the Fourier
modes interact. This is a unique methodology to probe the statistical
properties of the turbulent energy cascade, without breaking any of the
original symmetries of the equations. While the direct energy cascade persists,
deviations from the Kolmogorov scaling are observed in the kinetic energy
spectra. A model in terms of a correction with a linear dependency on the
co-dimension of the fractal set, $E(k) \sim k^{-5/3 + 3-D}$, explains the
results. At small scales, the intermittency of the vorticity field is observed
to be quasi-singular as a function of the fractal mode reduction, leading to an
almost Gaussian statistics already at $D \sim 2.98$. These effects must be
connected to a genuine modification in the triad-to-triad nonlinear energy
transfer mechanism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.08087</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.08087</id><created>2015-05-29</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Souslov</keyname><forenames>Anton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldbart</keyname><forenames>Paul M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Emergent collective properties of many-motor systems in one dimension</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>Withdrawn from publication for further revisions. 5 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Along a microtubule, certain active motors propel themselves in one direction
whereas others propel themselves in the opposite direction. For example, the
cargo transporting motor proteins dynein and kinesin propel themselves towards
the so-called plus- and minus-ends of the microtubule, respectively, and in so
doing are able to pass one another, but not without interacting. We address the
emergent collective behavior of systems composed of many motors, some
propelling towards the plus-end and others propelling towards the minus-end. To
do this, we used an analogy between this strongly interacting,
far-from-equilibrium, classical stochastic many-motor system and a certain
quantum-mechanical many-body system evolving in imaginary time. We apply
well-known methods from quantum many-body theory, including self-consistent
mean-field theory and bosonization, to shed light on phenomena exhibited by the
many-motor system such as structure formation and the dynamics of collective
modes at low-frequencies and long-wavelengths. In particular, via the bosonized
description we find analogs of chiral Luttinger liquids, as well as a
qualitative transition in the nature of the low-frequency modes---from
propagating to purely dissipative---controlled by density and interaction
strength.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.03259</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.03259</id><created>2015-06-10</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dusuel</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vidal</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Mean-field ansatz for topological phases with string tension</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el hep-lat hep-th quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 4 figures, typos in Table I corrected</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 92, 125150 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.92.125150</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a simple mean-field ansatz to study phase transitions from a
topological phase to a trivial phase. We probe the efficiency of this approach
by considering the string-net model in the presence of a string tension for any
anyon theory. Such a perturbation is known to be responsible for a
deconfinement-confinement phase transition which is well described by the
present variational setup. We argue that mean-field results become exact in the
limit of large total quantum dimension.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.04952</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.04952</id><created>2015-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Dantas</keyname><forenames>Christine Cordula</forenames></author></authors><title>The ultimate tactics of self-referential systems</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>9 pages. This essay received the 4th. Prize in the 2015 FQXi essay
  contest: &quot;Trick or Truth: the Mysterious Connection Between Physics and
  Mathematics&quot;</comments><doi>10.1007/978-3-319-27495-9_17</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Mathematics is usually regarded as a kind of language. The essential behavior
of physical phenomena can be expressed by mathematical laws, providing
descriptions and predictions. In the present essay I argue that, although
mathematics can be seen, in a first approach, as a language, it goes beyond
this concept. I conjecture that mathematics presents two extreme features,
denoted here by {\sl irreducibility} and {\sl insaturation}, representing
delimiters for self-referentiality. These features are then related to physical
laws by realizing that nature is a self-referential system obeying bounds
similar to those respected by mathematics. Self-referential systems can only be
autonomous entities by a kind of metabolism that provides and sustains such an
autonomy. A rational mind, able of consciousness, is a manifestation of the
self-referentiality of the Universe. Hence mathematics is here proposed to go
beyond language by actually representing the most fundamental existence
condition for self-referentiality. This idea is synthesized in the form of a
principle, namely, that {\sl mathematics is the ultimate tactics of
self-referential systems to mimic themselves}. That is, well beyond an
effective language to express the physical world, mathematics uncovers a deep
manifestation of the autonomous nature of the Universe, wherein the human brain
is but an instance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.06796</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.06796</id><created>2015-06-22</created><updated>2015-10-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gershenson</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Helbing</keyname><forenames>Dirk</forenames></author></authors><title>When slower is faster</title><categories>nlin.AO cond-mat.dis-nn cs.NE physics.soc-ph q-bio.QM</categories><journal-ref>Complexity, 21(2):9-15. 2015</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/cplx.21736</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The slower is faster (SIF) effect occurs when a system performs worse as its
components try to do better. Thus, a moderate individual efficiency actually
leads to a better systemic performance. The SIF effect takes place in a variety
of phenomena. We review studies and examples of the SIF effect in pedestrian
dynamics, vehicle traffic, traffic light control, logistics, public transport,
social dynamics, ecological systems, and adaptation. Drawing on these examples,
we generalize common features of the SIF effect and suggest possible future
lines of research.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.07451</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.07451</id><created>2015-06-24</created><updated>2016-03-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Caponio</keyname><forenames>Erasmo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stancarone</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author></authors><title>Standard static Finsler spacetimes</title><categories>math.DG gr-qc</categories><comments>AMS-LaTeX, 22 pages, 1 figure. v2 matches the published version</comments><journal-ref>International Journal of Geometric Methods in Modern Physics, 30
  (2016), 1650040</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0219887816500407</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce the notion of a standard static Finsler spacetime where the base
is a Finsler manifold. We prove some results which connect causality with the
Finslerian geometry of the base extending analogous ones for static and
stationary Lorentzian spacetimes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.08024</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.08024</id><created>2015-06-26</created><updated>2016-03-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Datta</keyname><forenames>Anindya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shaw</keyname><forenames>Avirup</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-minimal UED confronts $B_{s}\rightarrow\mu^{+}\mu^{-}$</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>31 pages, 8 figures, 2 tables: Several changes made in text and
  figures. Version accepted for publication in PRD</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 055048 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.055048</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Addition of boundary localised kinetic and Yukawa terms to the action of a
5-dimensional Standard Model would non-trivially modify the Kaluza-Klein
spectra and some of the interactions among the Kaluza-Klein excitations
compared to the minimal version of this model, in which, these boundary terms
are not present. In the minimal version of this framework known as Universal
Extra Dimensional model, special assumptions are made about these unknown,
beyond the cut-off contributions to restrict the number of unknown parameters
of the theory to a minimal. We estimate the contribution of Kaluza-Klein modes
to the branching ratios of $B_{s(d)}\rightarrow\mu^{+}\mu^{-}$ in the framework
of non-minimal Universal Extra Dimensional, at one loop level. The results have
been compared to the experimental data to constrain the parameters of this
model. From the measured decay branching ratio of $B_s \rightarrow \mu^+ \mu^-$
(depending on the values of boundary localised parameters) lower limit on
$R^{-1}$ can be as high as 800 GeV. We have briefly reviewed the bounds on
nmUED parameter space coming from electroweak precision observables. The
present analysis ($B_s \rightarrow \mu^+ \mu^-$) has ruled out new regions of
parameter space in comparison to the analysis of electroweak data. We have
revisited the bound on $R^{-1}$ in Universal Extra Dimensional model, which
came out to be 454 GeV. This limit on $R^{-1}$ in Universal Extra Dimensional
framework is not as competitive as the limits derived from the consideration of
relic density or Standard Model Higgs boson production and decay to $W^+ W^-$.
Unfortunately, $B_{d}\rightarrow\mu^{+}\mu^{-}$ decay branching ratio would not
set any significant limit on $R^{-1}$ in a minimal or non-minimal Universal
Extra Dimensional model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.03265</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.03265</id><created>2015-07-12</created><updated>2016-03-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Abebe</keyname><forenames>Amare</forenames></author><author><keyname>Momeni</keyname><forenames>Davood</forenames></author><author><keyname>Myrzakulov</keyname><forenames>Ratbay</forenames></author></authors><title>Shear-free Anisotropic Cosmological Models in f(R) Gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>18 pages, 4 figures, comments and references added to match accepted
  version; to appear in General Relativity and Gravitation</comments><journal-ref>Gen Relativ Gravit (2016) 48:49</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10714-016-2046-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a class of shear-free, homogeneous but anisotropic cosmological
models with imperfect matter sources in the context of f(R) gravity. We show
that the anisotropic stresses are related to the electric part of the Weyl
tensor in such a way that they balance each other. We also show that within the
class of orthogonal f(R) models, small perturbations of shear are damped, and
that the electric part of the Weyl tensor and the anisotropic stress tensor
decay with the expansion as well as the heat flux of the curvature fluid.
Specializing in locally rotationally symmetric spacetimes in orthonormal
frames, we examine the late-time behaviour of the de Sitter universe in $f(R)$
gravity. For the Starobinsky model of f(R), we study the evolutionary behavior
of the Universe by numerically integrating the Friedmann equation, where the
initial conditions for the expansion, acceleration and jerk parameters are
taken from observational data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.08580</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.08580</id><created>2015-07-30</created><updated>2016-02-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Singal</keyname><forenames>Ashok K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Radiation reaction and the pitch angle changes for a charge undergoing
  synchrotron losses</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>4 pages, To appear in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS 458, 2303 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw349</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the derivation of synchrotron radiation formulas it has been assumed that
the pitch angle of a charge remains constant during the radiation process.
However from the radiation reaction formula, while the component of the
velocity vector perpendicular to the magnetic field reduces in magnitude due to
radiative losses, the parallel component does not undergo any change during
radiation. Therefore there is a change in the ratio of the two components,
implying a change in the pitch angle. We derive the exact formula for the
change in energy of radiating electrons by taking into account the change of
the pitch angle due to radiative losses. From this we derive the characteristic
decay time of synchrotron electrons over which they turn from highly
relativistic into mildly relativistic ones.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.00811</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.00811</id><created>2015-08-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Coser</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tonni</keyname><forenames>Erik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calabrese</keyname><forenames>Pasquale</forenames></author></authors><title>Towards entanglement negativity of two disjoint intervals for a one
  dimensional free fermion</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th quant-ph</categories><comments>29 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2016) 033116</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/03/033116</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the moments of the partial transpose of the reduced density matrix
of two intervals for the free massless Dirac fermion. By means of a direct
calculation based on coherent state path integral, we find an analytic form for
these moments in terms of the Riemann theta function. We show that the moments
of arbitrary order are equal to the same quantities for the compactified boson
at the self-dual point. These equalities imply the non trivial result that also
the negativity of the free fermion and the self-dual boson are equal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.06946</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.06946</id><created>2015-08-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Kariyado</keyname><forenames>Toshikaze</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hatsugai</keyname><forenames>Yasuhiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Hannay Angle: Yet Another Symmetry Protected Topological Order Parameter
  in Classical Mechanics</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.class-ph</categories><comments>5 pages</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 85, 043001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.85.043001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Topological way of thinking now goes beyond conventional solid materials, and
topological characterization of classical mechanical systems governed by
Newton's equation of motion begins to attract much attention. To have a deeper
insight on physical meaning of topological numbers in mechanical systems, we
demonstrate the use of the Hannay angle, a classical counterpart of the Berry
phase, as a symmetry protected topological order parameter. We first derive the
Hannay angle using a canonical transformation that maps the Newton's equation
to the Schr\&quot;{o}dinger type equation. The Hannay angle is then used to
characterize a simple spring-mass model topologically with a particular focus
on the bulk-edge correspondence and new aspects of the symmetry in a classical
system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.06164</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.06164</id><created>2015-09-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Wehinger</keyname><forenames>Bj&#xf6;rn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bosak</keyname><forenames>Alexe&#xef;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nazzareni</keyname><forenames>Sabrina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Antonangeli</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mirone</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chaplot</keyname><forenames>Samrath Lal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mittal</keyname><forenames>Ranjan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohtani</keyname><forenames>Eiji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shatskiy</keyname><forenames>Anton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Surendra</keyname><forenames>Saxena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghose</keyname><forenames>Subrata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krisch</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Lattice dynamics of MgSiO$_3$ perovskite (bridgmanite) studied by
  inelastic x-ray scattering and ab initio calculations</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1002/2016GL067970</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have determined the lattice dynamics of MgSiO$_3$ perovskite (bridgmanite)
by a combination of single-crystal inelastic x-ray scattering and ab initio
calculations. We observe a remarkable agreement between experiment and theory,
and provide accurate results for phonon dispersion relations, phonon density of
states and the full elasticity tensor. The present work constitutes an
important milestone to extend this kind of combined studies to extreme
conditions of pressure and temperature, directly relevant for the physics and
the chemistry of Earth's lower mantle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.06368</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.06368</id><created>2015-09-21</created><updated>2015-11-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Poland</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stergiou</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author></authors><title>Exploring the Minimal 4D $\mathcal{N}=1$ SCFT</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>9 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1512 (2015) 121</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP12(2015)121</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the conformal bootstrap constraints for 4D $\mathcal{N}=1$
superconformal field theories containing a chiral operator $\phi$ and the
chiral ring relation $\phi^2=0$. Hints for a minimal interacting SCFT in this
class have appeared in previous numerical bootstrap studies. We perform a
detailed study of the properties of this conjectured theory, establishing that
the corresponding solution to the bootstrap constraints contains a
$\text{U}(1)_R$ current multiplet and estimating the central charge and
low-lying operator spectrum of this theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.08256</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.08256</id><created>2015-09-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>Priti</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rahman</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Subramanian</keyname><forenames>Shruti</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>Shalini</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thamizhavel</keyname><forenames>Arumugam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orlova</keyname><forenames>Tatyana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rouvimov</keyname><forenames>Sergei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vishwanath</keyname><forenames>Suresh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Protasenko</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laskar</keyname><forenames>Masihhur R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xing</keyname><forenames>Huili Grace</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jena</keyname><forenames>Debdeep</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattacharya</keyname><forenames>Arnab</forenames></author></authors><title>Layered transition metal dichalcogenides: promising near-lattice-matched
  substrates for GaN growth</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>main manuscript: page 1-15, 5 figures; supplementary: page 16-23</comments><report-no>Scientific Reports 6, Article number: 23708 (2016)</report-no><doi>10.1038/srep23708</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Most III-nitride semiconductors are grown on non-lattice-matched substrates
like sapphire or silicon due to the extreme difficulty of obtaining a native
GaN substrate. We show that several layered transition-metal dichalcogenides
are closely lattice matched to GaN and report the growth of GaN on a range of
such layered materials. We report detailed studies of the growth of GaN on
mechanically-exfoliated flakes WS$_2$ and MoS$_2$ by metalorganic vapour phase
epitaxy. Structural and optical characterization show that strain-free,
single-crystal islands of GaN are obtained on the underlying chalcogenide
flakes. We obtain strong near-band-edge emission from these layers, and analyse
their temperature-dependent photoluminescence properties. We also report a
proof-of-concept demonstration of large-area epitaxial growth of GaN on CVD
MoS$_2$. Our results show that the transition-metal dichalcogenides can serve
as novel near-lattice-matched substrates for nitride growth.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.03138</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.03138</id><created>2015-10-12</created><updated>2015-11-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xiao-Min</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Hong-Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chu</keyname><forenames>Peng-Cheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Jun-Ting</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Jian-Yang</forenames></author></authors><title>Primordial non-Gaussianity in warm inflation using $\delta N$ formalism</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Cosmol. Astropart. Phys. 03(2016)059</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/03/059</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A $\delta N$ formalism is used to study the non-Gaussianity of the primordial
curvature perturbation on an uniform density hypersurfaces generated by the
warm inflation for the first time. After introducing the framework of the warm
inflation and the $\delta N$ formalism, we obtain an analytic expression for
the nonlinear parameter $f_{NL}$ that describes the non-Gaussianity in slow
roll approximation, and find that the $\delta N$ formalism gives a very good
result. We analyse the magnitude of $f_{NL}$ and compare our result with those
of the standard inflation. Then we discuss two concrete examples: the quartic
chaotic model and the hilltop model. The quartic potential model can again be
in very good agreement with the Planck results in the warm inflationary
scenario, and we give out the concrete results of how the nonlinear parameter
depends on the dissipation strength of the warm inflation and the amounts of
expansion. We find that the range of the nonlinear parameters in these two
cases are both well inside of the allowed region of Planck.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.03619</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.03619</id><created>2015-10-13</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zinner</keyname><forenames>Nikolaj Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Exploring the few- to many-body crossover using cold atoms in one
  dimension</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>7 pages, short review contribution to proceedings of FB21 Chicago May
  18-22 2015. Revised version</comments><journal-ref>EPJ Web of Conferences 113, 01002 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201611301002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cold atomic gases have provided us with a great number of opportunities for
studying various physical systems under controlled conditions that are seldom
offered in other fields. We are thus at the point where one can truly do
quantum simulation of models that are relevant for instance in condensed-matter
or high-energy physics, i.e. we are on the verge of a 'cool' quantum simulator
as envisioned by Feynman. One of the avenues under exploration is the physics
of one-dimensional systems. Until recently this was mostly in the many-body
limit but now experiments can be performed with controllable particle numbers
all the way down to the few-body regime. After a brief introduction to some of
the relevant experiments, I will review recent theoretical work on
one-dimensional quantum systems containing bosons, fermions, or mixtures of the
two, with a particular emphasis on the case where the particles are held by an
external trap.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.05365</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.05365</id><created>2015-10-19</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tsekov</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum mechanics emerging from stochastic dynamics of virtual particles</title><categories>quant-ph physics.class-ph</categories><comments>Presented at EmQM15, Vienna, Austria</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Conf. Ser. 701 (2016) 012034</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/701/1/012034</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is demonstrated how quantum mechanics emerges from the stochastic dynamics
of force-carriers. It is shown that the quantum Moyal equation corresponds to
some dynamic correlations between the momentum of a real particle and the
position of a virtual particle, which are not present in classical mechanics.
The new concept throws light on the physical meaning of quantum theory, showing
that the Planck constant square is a second-second cross-cumulant.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.07044</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.07044</id><created>2015-10-23</created><updated>2016-02-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Daliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meltzer</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poland</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-Abelian Binding Energies from the Lightcone Bootstrap</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph</categories><comments>Added comments on the weak gravity conjecture</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1602 (2016) 149</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP02(2016)149</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analytically study the lightcone limit of the conformal bootstrap for
4-point functions containing scalars charged under global symmetries. We show
the existence of large spin double-twist operators in various representations
of the global symmetry group. We then compute their anomalous dimensions in
terms of the central charge $C_T$, current central charge $C_J$, and the OPE
coefficients of low dimension scalars. In AdS, these results correspond to the
binding energy of two-particle states arising from the exchange of gravitons,
gauge bosons, and light scalar fields. Using unitarity and crossing symmetry,
we show that gravity is universal and attractive among different types of
two-particle states, while the gauge binding energy can have either sign as
determined by the representation of the two-particle state, with universal
ratios fixed by the symmetry group. We apply our results to 4D $\mathcal{N}=1$
SQCD and the 3D O(N) vector models. We also show that in a unitary CFT, if the
current central charge $C_J$ stays finite when the global symmetry group
becomes infinitely large, such as the $N\rightarrow\infty$ limit of the O(N)
vector model, then the theory must contain an infinite number of higher spin
currents.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.07351</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.07351</id><created>2015-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Rubo</keyname><forenames>Yuri G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheremet</keyname><forenames>Alexandra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kavokin</keyname><forenames>Alexey</forenames></author></authors><title>Second-order correlations in an exciton-polariton Rabi oscillator</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>4 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 115315 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.115315</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop the theoretical formalism to calculate second-order correlations
in dissipative exciton-polariton system and we propose intensity-intensity
correlation experiments to reveal the physics of exciton-light coupling in
semiconductor microcavities in the Rabi oscillation regime. We predict a
counter intuitive behaviour of the correlator between upper and lower polariton
branches: due to the decoherence caused by stochastic exciton-photon
conversions this correlator is expected to decrease below 1, while the
individual second-order coherence of upper and lower polaritons exhibits
non-monotonous bunching.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.00529</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.00529</id><created>2015-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Santamar&#xed;a-Bonfil</keyname><forenames>Guillermo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fern&#xe1;ndez</keyname><forenames>Nelson</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gershenson</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author></authors><title>Measuring the Complexity of Continuous Distributions</title><categories>nlin.AO cond-mat.stat-mech cs.CC</categories><comments>21 pages, 5 Tables, 4 Figures</comments><journal-ref>Entropy, 18(3):72. 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/e18030072</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We extend previously proposed measures of complexity, emergence, and
self-organization to continuous distributions using differential entropy. This
allows us to calculate the complexity of phenomena for which distributions are
known. We find that a broad range of common parameters found in Gaussian and
scale-free distributions present high complexity values. We also explore the
relationship between our measure of complexity and information adaptation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.00701</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.00701</id><created>2015-10-30</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fewster</keyname><forenames>Christopher J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ju&#xe1;rez-Aubry</keyname><forenames>Benito A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Louko</keyname><forenames>Jorma</forenames></author></authors><title>Asymptotically thermal responses for smoothly switched detectors</title><categories>math-ph gr-qc hep-th math.MP</categories><comments>v.2.0. 6 pages. Contributed talk by B.A.J.-A. in the QF2-B session on
  Quantum Field Theory to the Proceedings of the Fourteenth Marcel Grossmann
  Meeting</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Thermal phenomena in quantum field theory can be detected with the aid of
particle detectors coupled to quantum fields along stationary worldlines, by
testing whether the response of such a detector satisfies the detailed balance
version of the KMS condition at a constant temperature. This relation holds
when the interaction between the field and the detector has infinite time
duration. Operationally, however, detectors interact with fields for a finite
amount of time, controlled by a switching function of compact support, and the
KMS detailed balance condition cannot hold exactly for finite time interactions
at arbitrarily large detector energy gap. In this large energy gap regime, we
show that, for an adiabatically switched Rindler detector, the Unruh
temperature emerges asymptotically after the detector and the field have
interacted for a time that is polynomially long in the large energy. We comment
on the significance of the adiabaticity assumption in this result.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.01982</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.01982</id><created>2015-11-05</created><updated>2016-03-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zidong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grimson</keyname><forenames>Malcolm J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamic Response in a Finite Size Composite Multiferroic Thin Film</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Appl. Phys. 119, 124105 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4944604</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Composite multiferroics, heterostructures of ferromagnetic (FM) and
ferroelectric (FE) materials, are characterized by a remarkable magnetoelectric
effect at the interface. Previous work has supported the ferromagnetic
structure with magnetic spins and the ferroelectric with pseudospins which act
as electric dipoles in a microscopic model, coupled with a magnetoelectric
interaction [J. Appl. Phys. 118, 124109 (2015)]. In this work, by solving the
stochastic Landau-Lifshitz-Gilbert equation, the electric-field-induced
magnetization switching in a twisted boundary condition has been studied, and a
behavior of domain wall in the ferromagnetic structure is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.07660</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.07660</id><created>2015-11-24</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jansen</keyname><forenames>Martin J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>Carsten</forenames></author></authors><title>Strong-Field Breit-Wheeler Pair Production in Short Laser Pulses:
  Identifying Multiphoton Interference and Carrier-Envelope-Phase Effects</title><categories>hep-ph physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 053011 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.053011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The creation of electron-positron pairs by the strong-field Breit-Wheeler
process in intense short laser pulses is investigated in the framework of
laser-dressed quantum electrodynamics. Regarding laser field parameters in the
multiphoton regime, special attention is brought to the energy spectrum of the
created particles, which can be reproduced and explained by means of an
intuitive model. The model is based on the probabilities of multiphoton events
driven by the spectral components of the laser pulse. It allows, in particular,
to identify interferences between different pair production channels which
exhibit a characteristic dependence on the laser carrier-envelope phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.08025</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.08025</id><created>2015-11-25</created><updated>2016-02-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Daliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meltzer</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poland</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Conformal Collider Physics from the Lightcone Bootstrap</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph</categories><comments>56 pages, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1602 (2016) 143</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP02(2016)143</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analytically study the lightcone limit of the conformal bootstrap
equations for 4-point functions containing global symmetry currents and the
stress tensor in 3d CFTs. We show that the contribution of the stress tensor to
the anomalous dimensions of large spin double-twist states is negative if and
only if the conformal collider physics bounds are satisfied. In the context of
AdS/CFT these results indicate a relation between the attractiveness of AdS
gravity and positivity of the CFT energy flux. We also study the contribution
of non-Abelian conserved currents to the anomalous dimensions of double-twist
operators, corresponding to the gauge binding energy of 2-particle states in
AdS. We show that the representation of the double-twist state determines the
sign of the gauge binding energy if and only if the coefficient appearing in
the current 3-point function satisfies a similar bound, which is equivalent to
an upper bound on the charge flux asymmetry of the CFT.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.08819</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.08819</id><created>2015-11-27</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Eisler</keyname><forenames>Viktor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zimbor&#xe1;s</keyname><forenames>Zolt&#xe1;n</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement negativity in two-dimensional free lattice models</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 6 figures, published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 115148 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.115148</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the scaling properties of the ground-state entanglement between
finite subsystems of infinite two-dimensional free lattice models, as measured
by the logarithmic negativity. For adjacent regions with a common boundary, we
observe that the negativity follows a strict area law for a lattice of harmonic
oscillators, whereas for fermionic hopping models the numerical results
indicate a multiplicative logarithmic correction. In this latter case, we
conjecture a formula for the prefactor of the area-law violating term, which is
entirely determined by the geometries of the Fermi surface and the boundary
between the subsystems. The conjecture is tested against numerical results and
a good agreement is found.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.01235</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.01235</id><created>2015-12-03</created><updated>2016-03-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>El-Badry</keyname><forenames>Kareem</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wetzel</keyname><forenames>Andrew R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geha</keyname><forenames>Marla</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hopkins</keyname><forenames>Philip F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kere&#x161;</keyname><forenames>Du&#x161;an</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chan</keyname><forenames>T. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faucher-Gigu&#xe8;re</keyname><forenames>Claude-Andr&#xe9;</forenames></author></authors><title>Breathing FIRE: How Stellar Feedback Drives Radial Migration, Rapid Size
  Fluctuations, and Population Gradients in Low-Mass Galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Accepted to ApJ (820, 131) with minor revisions from v1. Figure 4 now
  includes dark matter. Main results in Figures 7 and 11</comments><journal-ref>ApJ, 2016, 820, 131</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/820/2/131</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine the effects of stellar feedback and bursty star formation on
low-mass galaxies ($M_{\rm star}=2\times10^6-5\times10^{10}{\rm M_{\odot}}$)
using the FIRE (Feedback in Realistic Environments) simulations. While previous
studies emphasized the impact of feedback on dark matter profiles, we
investigate the impact on the stellar component: kinematics, radial migration,
size evolution, and population gradients. Feedback-driven outflows/inflows
drive significant radial stellar migration over both short and long timescales
via two processes: (1) outflowing/infalling gas can remain star-forming,
producing young stars that migrate $\sim1{\rm\,kpc}$ within their first $100
{\rm\,Myr}$, and (2) gas outflows/inflows drive strong fluctuations in the
global potential, transferring energy to all stars. These processes produce
several dramatic effects. First, galaxies' effective radii can fluctuate by
factors of $&gt;2$ over $\sim200 {\rm\,Myr}$, and these rapid size fluctuations
can account for much of the observed scatter in radius at fixed $M_{\rm star}.$
Second, the cumulative effects of many outflow/infall episodes steadily heat
stellar orbits, causing old stars to migrate outward most strongly. This
age-dependent radial migration mixes---and even inverts---intrinsic age and
metallicity gradients. Thus, the galactic-archaeology approach of calculating
radial star-formation histories from stellar populations at $z=0$ can be
severely biased. These effects are strongest at $M_{\rm
star}\approx10^{7-9.6}{\rm M_{\odot}}$, the same regime where feedback most
efficiently cores galaxies. Thus, detailed measurements of stellar kinematics
in low-mass galaxies can strongly constrain feedback models and test baryonic
solutions to small-scale problems in $\Lambda$CDM.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.02672</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.02672</id><created>2015-12-08</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bhardwaj</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miyabayashi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panzenb&#xf6;ck</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trabelsi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frey</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abdesselam</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adachi</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aihara</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Said</keyname><forenames>S. Al</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arinstein</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asner</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Atmacan</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aulchenko</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aushev</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ayad</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Babu</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Badhrees</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bahinipati</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bakich</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bala</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bansal</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barberio</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhuyan</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Biswal</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bobrov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bondar</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bozek</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bra&#x10d;ko</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Browder</keyname><forenames>T. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#x10c;ervenkov</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chekelian</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheon</keyname><forenames>B. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chilikin</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chistov</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cho</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chobanova</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>S. -K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cinabro</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dalseno</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Danilov</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dole&#x17e;al</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dutta</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eidelman</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farhat</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fast</keyname><forenames>J. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferber</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frost</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fulsom</keyname><forenames>B. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaur</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gabyshev</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ganguly</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garmash</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gillard</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glattauer</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goh</keyname><forenames>Y. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldenzweig</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Golob</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greenwald</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haba</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hamer</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hayasaka</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hayashii</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>X. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hou</keyname><forenames>W. -S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iijima</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Inami</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishikawa</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Itoh</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iwasaki</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jaegle</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joffe</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joo</keyname><forenames>K. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Julius</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kato</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katrenko</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawasaki</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kiesling</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>D. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>J. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>K. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>S. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Y. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kinoshita</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ko</keyname><forenames>B. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kody&#x161;</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korpar</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kri&#x17e;an</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krokovny</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuhr</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumita</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuzmin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kwon</keyname><forenames>Y. -J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>I. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gioi</keyname><forenames>L. Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Libby</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liventsev</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loos</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lukin</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masuda</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matvienko</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miyata</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mizuk</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mohanty</keyname><forenames>G. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mohanty</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moll</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moon</keyname><forenames>H. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mussa</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakano</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakao</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nanut</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Natkaniec</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nayak</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nisar</keyname><forenames>N. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishida</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ogawa</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okuno</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pakhlova</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pal</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>C. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pedlar</keyname><forenames>T. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pestotnik</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petri&#x10d;</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piilonen</keyname><forenames>L. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pulvermacher</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Purohit</keyname><forenames>M. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rauch</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ribe&#x17e;l</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ritter</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rostomyan</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sahoo</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakai</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sandilya</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santelj</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanuki</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sato</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Savinov</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schnell</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwanda</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seino</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Semmler</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Senyo</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seon</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sevior</keyname><forenames>M. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shebalin</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>C. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shibata</keyname><forenames>T. -A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shiu</keyname><forenames>J. -G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shwartz</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simon</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>J. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sohn</keyname><forenames>Y. -S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sokolov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solovieva</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stari&#x10d;</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stypula</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sumihama</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sumiyoshi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tamponi</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanida</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teramoto</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uchida</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uehara</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uglov</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Unno</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uno</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Urquijo</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Usov</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Hulse</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vanhoefer</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varner</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vinokurova</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vorobyev</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>C. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>M. -Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>X. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wehle</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Won</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamaoka</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yashchenko</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yook</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>C. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yusa</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Z. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhilich</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhulanov</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zupanc</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Inclusive and exclusive measurements of $B$ decays to $\chi_{c1}$ and
  $\chi_{c2}$ at Belle</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>14 Pages, 8 Figures,4 Tables; Published in PRD 93, 052016 (2016)</comments><report-no>Belle Preprint 2015-21, KEK Preprint 2015-56 (Belle Collaboration)</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 052016 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.052016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report inclusive and exclusive measurements for $\chi_{c1}$ and
$\chi_{c2}$ production in $B$ decays. We measure $\mathcal{B}(B \to \chi_{c1}
X)$= $(3.03 \pm 0.05(\mbox{stat}) \pm 0.24(\mbox{syst})) \times 10^{-3}$ and
$\mathcal{B}(B \to \chi_{c2} X)$= $(0.70 \pm 0.06(\mbox{stat}) \pm
0.10(\mbox{syst})) \times 10^{-3}$. For the first time, $\chi_{c2}$ production
in exclusive $B$ decays in the modes $B^0 \to \chi_{c2}\pi^- K^+$ and $B^+ \to
\chi_{c2} \pi^+ \pi^- K^+$ has been observed, along with first evidence for the
$B^+ \to \chi_{c2} \pi^+ K_S^0$ decay mode. For $\chi_{c1}$ production, we
report the first observation in the $B^+ \to \chi_{c1} \pi^+ \pi^- K^+$, $B^0
\to \chi_{c1} \pi^+ \pi^- K_S^0$ and $B^0 \to \chi_{c1} \pi^0 \pi^- K^+$ decay
modes. Using these decay modes, we observe a difference in the production
mechanism of $\chi_{c2}$ in comparison to $\chi_{c1}$ in $B$ decays. In
addition, we report searches for $X(3872)$ and $\chi_{c1}(2P)$ in the $B^+ \to
(\chi_{c1} \pi^+ \pi^-) K^+$ decay mode. The reported results use $772 \times
10^{6}$ $B\overline{B}$ events collected at the $\Upsilon(4S)$ resonance with
the Belle detector at the KEKB asymmetric-energy $e^+e^-$ collider.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.04238</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.04238</id><created>2015-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Gori</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barthel</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Avinash</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lucioni</keyname><forenames>Eleonora</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanzi</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Inguscio</keyname><forenames>Massimo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Modugno</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giamarchi</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Errico</keyname><forenames>Chiara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roux</keyname><forenames>Guillaume</forenames></author></authors><title>Finite-temperature effects on interacting bosonic 1D systems in
  disordered lattices</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>14 pages, 19 figures, paper submitted to PRA</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 033650 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.033650</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the finite-temperature effects on the phase diagram describing the
insulating properties of interacting 1D bosons in a quasi-periodic lattice. We
examine thermal effects by comparing experimental results to exact
diagonalization for small-sized systems and to density-matrix renormalization
group (DMRG) computations. At weak interactions, we find short thermal
correlation lengths, indicating a substantial impact of temperature on the
system coherence. Conversely, at strong interactions, the obtained thermal
correlation lengths are significantly larger than the localization length, and
the quantum nature of the T=0 Bose glass phase is preserved up to a crossover
temperature that depends on the disorder strength. Furthermore, in the absence
of disorder, we show how quasi-exact finite-T DMRG computations, compared to
experimental results, can be employed to estimate the temperature, which is not
directly accessible in the experiment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.05792</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.05792</id><created>2015-12-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Babb</keyname><forenames>James F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hussein</keyname><forenames>Mahir S.</forenames></author></authors><title>van der Waals and Casimir-Polder interactions between neutrons</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>2 pages. To appear in the proceedings of the 21st International
  Conference on Few-Body Problems in Physics (FB21), May 2015, Chicago, USA</comments><journal-ref>EPJ Web of Conferences, 113 (2016) 08001</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201611308001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the van der Waals interaction between neutrons using the
theory of Casimir and Polder, wherein the potential for asymptotically large
separations falls off as the inverse seventh power, and compare it to the
similar interaction between a neutron and a proton, for which the asymptotic
interaction falls off as the inverse fourth power. Modifications of the
formalism to extend the validity to smaller separations using dynamic electric
and magnetic dipole polarizability data are discussed
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07018</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07018</id><created>2015-12-22</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sojasi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mohsenzadeh</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yusofi</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Large Angular Scale CMB Anisotropy from an Excited Initial Mode</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>accepted for publication in chinese physics c, 2016</comments><doi>10.1088/1674-1137/40/7/075101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  According to inflationary cosmology, the CMB anisotropy gives an opportunity
to test predictions of new physics hypotheses. The initial state of quantum
fluctuations is one of the important options at high energy scale, as it can
affect observables such as the CMB power spectrum. In this study a quasi-de
Sitter inflationary background with approximate de Sitter mode function built
over the Bunch-Davies mode is applied to investigate the scale-dependency of
the CMB anisotropy. The recent Planck constraint on spectral index motivated us
to examine the effect of a new excited mode function (instead of pure de Sitter
mode) on the CMB anisotropy at large angular scales. In so doing, it is found
that the angular scale-invariance in the CMB temperature fluctuations is broken
and in the limit $ \ell&lt;200 $ a tiny deviation appears. Also, it is shown that
the power spectrum of CMB anisotropy is dependent on a free parameter with mass
dimension $H&lt;&lt;M_{*}&lt;M_{p}$ and on the slow-roll parameter $\epsilon $.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.08993</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.08993</id><created>2015-12-30</created><updated>2016-02-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nouicer</keyname><forenames>Rachid</forenames></author></authors><title>New State of Nuclear Matter: Nearly Perfect Fluid of Quarks and Gluons
  in Heavy Ion Collisions at RHIC Energies</title><categories>nucl-ex</categories><comments>22 pages, 23 figures, text updated, FOPI's reference added, based on
  my &quot;Habilitation a Diriger des Recherches&quot;:
  https://tel.archives-ouvertes.fr/tel-00925262</comments><journal-ref>European Physical Journal Plus, 131 3 (2016) 70</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjp/i2016-16070-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This article reviews several important results from RHIC experiments and
discusses their implications. They were obtained in a unique environment for
studying QCD matter at temperatures and densities that exceed the limits
wherein hadrons can exist as individual entities and raises to prominence the
quark-gluon degrees of freedom. These findings are supported by major
experimental observations via measuring of the bulk properties of particle
production, particle ratios and chemical freeze-out conditions, and elliptic
flow; followed by hard probe measurements. The results reveal that a dense,
strongly-interacting medium is created in central Au+Au collisions at 200 GeV
at RHIC. This revelation of a new state of nuclear matter has also been
observed in measurements at the LHC. Further, the IP-Glasma model coupled with
viscous hydrodynamic models, which assumes the formation of a QGP, reproduces
well the experimental flow results from Au+Au at 200 GeV. This implies that the
fluctuations in the initial geometry state are important and the created medium
behaves as a nearly perfect liquid of nuclear matter because it has an
extraordinarily low ratio of shear viscosity to entropy density. However, these
discoveries are far from being fully understood. Furthermore, recent
experimental results from RHIC and LHC in small p+A, d+Au and He+A collision
systems provide brand new insight into the role of initial and final state
effects. These have proven to be interesting and more surprising than
originally anticipated; and could conceivably shed new light in our
understanding of collective behavior in heavy-ion physics. Accordingly, the
focus of the experiments at both facilities RHIC and the LHC is on detailed
exploration of the properties of this new state of nuclear matter, the QGP.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.00641</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.00641</id><created>2016-01-04</created><updated>2016-02-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Khakhaleva-Li</keyname><forenames>Zimu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gnedin</keyname><forenames>Nickolay Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmic Reionization On Computers. Ultraviolet Continuum Slopes and Dust
  Opacities in High Redshift Galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>12 pages, 8 figures, accepted for publication in the Astrophysical
  Journal</comments><journal-ref>ApJ, 820, 133 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/820/2/133</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compare the properties of stellar populations of model galaxies from the
Cosmic Reionization On Computers (CROC) project with the exiting UV and IR
data. Since CROC simulations do not follow cosmic dust directly, we adopt two
variants of the dust-follows-metals ansatz to populate model galaxies with
dust. Using the dust radiative transfer code Hyperion, we compute synthetic
stellar spectra, UV continuum slopes, and IR fluxes for simulated galaxies. We
find that the simulation results generally match observational measurements,
but, perhaps, not in full detail. The differences seem to indicate that our
adopted dust-follows-metals ansatzes are not fully sufficient. While the
discrepancies with the exiting data are marginal, the future JWST data will be
of much higher precision, rendering highly significant any tentative difference
between theory and observations. It is, therefore, likely, that in order to
fully utilize the precision of JWST observations, fully dynamical modeling of
dust formation, evolution, and destruction may be required.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.01081</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.01081</id><created>2016-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Tu</keyname><forenames>Matisse Wei-Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aharony</keyname><forenames>Amnon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Entin-Wohlman</keyname><forenames>Ora</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schiller</keyname><forenames>Avraham</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Wei-Min</forenames></author></authors><title>Transient probing of the symmetry and the asymmetry of electron
  interference</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 125437 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.125437</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The transient processes of electron transport in nano-scale devices exhibit
special phenomena that exist only in the transient regime. Besides how fast the
steady states are approached, one interesting aspect of transient transport
arises from its strong dependence on the initial state of the system. Here we
address the issue of how the symmetries embedded in the initial state interplay
with those of the system structure in the course of transient transports. We
explicitly explore the transient currents arising from various initial
occupations in a double-quantum-dot Aharonov-Bohm interferometer. We find
symmetry relations between the transient in-tunneling and out-tunneling
dynamics for initially empty or full quantum dots when the energy levels in the
electrodes are symmetrically distributed with respect to the energy levels in
the QDs. This is true for whatever applied fluxes. We also find the flux-even
components of the currents and the flux-odd components of the currents exhibit
distinct cross-lead symmetric relations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.01200</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.01200</id><created>2016-01-06</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ghioldi</keyname><forenames>E. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonzalez</keyname><forenames>M. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manuel</keyname><forenames>L. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trumper</keyname><forenames>A. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>RVB signatures in the spin dynamics of the square-lattice Heisenberg
  antiferromagnet</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>6 pages with 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Europhysics Letters 113, 57001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/113/57001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the spin dynamics of the square-lattice spin-1/2 Heisenberg
antiferromagnet by means of an improved mean field Schwinger boson calculation.
By identifying both, the long range N\'eel and the RVB-like components of the
ground state, we propose an educated guess for the mean field triplet
excitation consisting on a linear combination of local and bond spin flips to
compute the dynamical structure factor. Our main result is that when this
triplet excitation is optimized in such a way that the corresponding sum rule
is fulfilled, we recover the low and high energy spectral weight features of
the experimental spectrum. In particular, the anomalous spectral weight
depletion at $(\pi,0)$ found in recent inelastic neutron scattering experiments
can be attributed to the interference of the triplet bond excitations of the
RVB component of the ground state. We conclude that the Schwinger boson theory
seems to be a good candidate to adequately interpret the dynamic properties of
the square-lattice Heisenberg antiferromagnet.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.02493</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.02493</id><created>2016-01-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Bok</keyname><forenames>Jin Mo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bae</keyname><forenames>Jong Ju</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Han-Yong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varma</keyname><forenames>Chandra M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Wentao</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Junfeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yuxiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>X. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantitative Determination of the Pairing Interactions for High
  Temperature Superconductivity in Cuprates</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>41 Pages, 9 Figures, Including Supplementary Materials, Accepted in
  Science Advances</comments><journal-ref>Science Advances 2, e1501329 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A profound problem in modern condensed matter physics is discovering and
understanding the nature of the fluctuations and their coupling to fermions in
cuprates which lead to high temperature superconductivity and the invariably
associated strange metal state. Here we report the quantitative determination
of the normal and pairing self-energies, made possible by laser-based
angle-resolved photoemission measurements with unprecedented accuracy and
stability. Through a precise inversion procedure, both the effective
interactions in the attractive d-wave symmetry and the repulsive part in the
full symmetry are determined. The latter are nearly angle independent. Near Tc
both interactions are nearly independent of frequency, and have almost the same
magnitude, over the complete energy range of up to about 0.4 eV except for a
low energy feature around 50 meV present only in the repulsive part which has
less than 10% of the total spectral weight. Well below Tc, they both change
similarly by superconductivity induced features at low energies. Besides
finding the pairing self-energy and the attractive interactions for the first
time, these results expose a central paradox of the high Tc problem: how the
same frequency independent fluctuations can dominantly scatter at angles +-pi/2
in the attractive channel as well as lead to angle-independent repulsive
scattering. The experimental results are compared with the available
theoretical calculations based on antiferromagnetic fluctuations, Hubbard model
and the quantum-critical fluctuations of loop-current order.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07489</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07489</id><created>2016-01-27</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aulbach</keyname><forenames>Julian</forenames><affiliation>Department of Physics, University of Wuerzburg, Wuerzburg, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Erwin</keyname><forenames>Steven C.</forenames><affiliation>Naval Research Laboratory, Washington DC, USA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Claessen</keyname><forenames>Ralph</forenames><affiliation>Department of Physics, University of Wuerzburg, Wuerzburg, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Schaefer</keyname><forenames>Joerg</forenames><affiliation>Department of Physics, University of Wuerzburg, Wuerzburg, Germany</affiliation></author></authors><title>Spin Chains and Electron Transfer at Stepped Silicon Surfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures; Supplement; accepted for publication in Nano
  Letters</comments><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.6b00354</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  High-index surfaces of silicon with adsorbed gold can reconstruct to form
highly ordered linear step arrays. These steps take the form of a narrow strip
of graphitic silicon. In some cases - specifically, for Si(553)-Au and
Si(557)-Au - a large fraction of the silicon atoms at the exposed edge of this
strip are known to be spin-polarized and charge-ordered along the edge. The
periodicity of this charge ordering is always commensurate with the structural
periodicity along the step edge and hence leads to highly ordered arrays of
local magnetic moments that can be regarded as &quot;spin chains&quot;. Here, we
demonstrate theoretically as well as experimentally that the closely related
Si(775)-Au surface has - despite its very similar overall structure - zero spin
polarization at its step edge. Using a combination of density-functional theory
and scanning tunneling microscopy, we propose an electron-counting model that
accounts for these differences. The model also predicts that unintentional
defects and intentional dopants can create local spin moments at Si(hhk)-Au
step edges. We analyze in detail one of these predictions and verify it
experimentally. This finding opens the door to using techniques of surface
chemistry and atom manipulation to create and control silicon spin chains.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07505</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07505</id><created>2016-01-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Kandhway</keyname><forenames>Kundan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kotnis</keyname><forenames>Bhushan</forenames></author></authors><title>Game Theoretic Analysis of Tree Based Referrals for Crowd Sensing Social
  Systems with Passive Rewards</title><categories>cs.GT cs.MA cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures. Presented in Social Networking Workshop at
  International Conference on Communication Systems and Networks (COMSNETS),
  Bangalore, India, January 2016</comments><doi>10.1109/COMSNETS.2016.7439947</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Participatory crowd sensing social systems rely on the participation of large
number of individuals. Since humans are strategic by nature, effective
incentive mechanisms are needed to encourage participation. A popular mechanism
to recruit individuals is through referrals and passive incentives such as
geometric incentive mechanisms used by the winning team in the 2009 DARPA
Network Challenge and in multi level marketing schemes. The effect of such
recruitment schemes on the effort put in by recruited strategic individuals is
not clear. This paper attempts to fill this gap. Given a referral tree and the
direct and passive reward mechanism, we formulate a network game where agents
compete for finishing crowd sensing tasks. We characterize the Nash equilibrium
efforts put in by the agents and derive closed form expressions for the same.
We discover free riding behavior among nodes who obtain large passive rewards.
This work has implications on designing effective recruitment mechanisms for
crowd sourced tasks. For example, usage of geometric incentive mechanisms to
recruit large number of individuals may not result in proportionate effort
because of free riding.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.08232</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.08232</id><created>2016-01-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Sheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pelcovits</keyname><forenames>Robert A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hagan</keyname><forenames>Michael F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Interaction of chiral rafts in self-assembled colloidal membranes</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>18 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 93, 032706 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.93.032706</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Colloidal membranes are monolayer assemblies of rodlike particles that
capture the long-wavelength properties of lipid bilayer membranes on the
colloidal scale. Recent experiments on colloidal membranes formed by chiral
rodlike viruses showed that introducing a second species of virus with
different length and opposite chirality leads to the formation of rafts ---
micron-sized domains of one virus species floating in a background of the other
viruses [Sharma et al., Nature 513, 77 (2014)]. In this article we study the
interaction of such rafts using liquid crystal elasticity theory. By
numerically minimizing the director elastic free energy, we predict the tilt
angle profile for both a single raft and two rafts in a background membrane,
and the interaction between two rafts as a function of their separation. We
find that the chiral penetration depth in the background membrane sets the
scale for the range of the interaction. We compare our results with the
experimental data and find good agreement for the strength and range of the
interaction. Unlike the experiments, however, we do not observe a complete
collapse of the data when rescaled by the tilt angle at the raft edge.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02225</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02225</id><created>2016-02-06</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sarraf</keyname><forenames>Saman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author></authors><title>Functional Brain Imaging: A Comprehensive Survey</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Functional brain imaging allows measuring dynamic functionality in all brain
regions. It is broadly used in clinical cognitive neuroscience as, well as in
research. It will allow the observation of neural activities in the brain
simultaneously. From the beginning when functional brain imaging was initiated
by the mapping of brain functions proposed by phrenologists, many scientists
were asking why we need to image brain functionality since we have already
structural information. Simply, their important question was including a great
answer. Functional information of the human brain would definitely complement
structural information, helping to have a better understanding of what is
happening in the brain. This paper, which could be useful to those who have an
interest in functional brain imaging, such as engineers, will present a quick
review of modalities used in functional brain imaging. We will concentrate on
the most used techniques in functional imaging which are functional magnetic
resonance imaging (fMRI) and functional optical imaging, which is one of
novelties in this area of study.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02896</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02896</id><created>2016-02-09</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ducatez</keyname><forenames>Raphael</forenames><affiliation>CEREMADE</affiliation></author></authors><title>Anderson localisation for infinitely many interacting particles in
  Hartree-Fock theory</title><categories>math-ph math.MP math.SP</categories><comments>New references added</comments><proxy>ccsd</proxy><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove the occurrence of Anderson localisation for a system of infinitely
many particles interacting with a short range potential, within the ground
state Hartree-Fock approximation. We assume that the particles hop on a
discrete lattice and that they are submitted to an external periodic potential
which creates a gap in the non-interacting one particle Hamiltonian. We also
assume that the interaction is weak enough to preserve a gap. We prove that the
mean-field operator has exponentially localised eigenvectors, either on its
whole spectrum or at the edges of its bands, depending on the strength of the
disorder.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02910</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02910</id><created>2016-02-09</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Araki</keyname><forenames>Hiromu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kariyado</keyname><forenames>Toshikaze</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fukui</keyname><forenames>Takahiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hatsugai</keyname><forenames>Yasuhiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement Chern Number of the Kane-Mele Model with Ferromagnetism</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>4 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 85, 043706 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.85.043706</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The entanglement Chern number, the Chern number for the entanglement
Hamiltonian, is used to charac- terize the Kane-Mele model, which is a typical
model of the quantum spin Hall phase with the time reversal symmetry. We first
obtain the global phase diagram of the Kane-Mele model in terms of the
entanglement spin Chern number, which is defined by using a spin subspace as a
subspace to be traced out in preparing the entanglement Hamiltonian. We further
demonstrate the effectiveness of the entanglement Chern number without the time
reversal symmetry and spin conservation by extending the Kane-Mele model to
include the Zeeman term. The numerical results confirm that the sum of the
entanglement spin Chern number equals to the Chern number.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04541</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04541</id><created>2016-02-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Chien-Chang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goan</keyname><forenames>Hsi-Sheng</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects of initial system-environment correlations on open quantum
  system dynamics and state preparation</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>15 pages, 8 figures; accepted for publication in Phys. Rev. A</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review A 93, 032113 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.032113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the preparation of a target initial state for a two-level
(qubit) system from a system-environment equilibrium or correlated state by an
external field. The system-environment equilibrium or correlated state results
from the inevitable interaction of the system with its environment. An
efficient method in an extended auxiliary Liouville space is introduced to
describe the dynamics of the non-Markovian open quantum system in the presence
of a strong field and an initial system-environment correlation. By using the
time evolutions of the population difference, the state trajectory in the Bloch
sphere representation and the trace distance between two reduced system states
of the open quantum system, the effect of initial system-environment
correlations on the preparation of a system state is studied. We introduce an
upper bound and a lower bound for the trace distance within our perturbation
formalism to describe the diverse behaviors of the dynamics of the trace
distance between various correlated states after the system state preparation.
These bounds that are much more computable than similar bounds in the
literature give a sufficient condition and a necessary condition for the
increase of the trace distance and are related to the witnesses of
non-Markovianity and initial system-bath correlation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04932</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04932</id><created>2016-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Pascasio</keyname><forenames>Johannes Mesa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fussy</keyname><forenames>Siegfried</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwabl</keyname><forenames>Herbert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Groessing</keyname><forenames>Gerhard</forenames></author></authors><title>Emergent quantum mechanics without wave functions</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure; based on a poster presented at the 3rd
  international symposium on &quot;Emergent Quantum Mechanics&quot; (Vienna, Austria,
  23-25 October, 2015); see http://www.emqm15.org/</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Conf. Ser. (2016) 701 012036</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/701/1/012036</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present our model of an Emergent Quantum Mechanics which can be
characterized by &quot;realism without pre-determination&quot;. This is illustrated by
our analytic description and corresponding computer simulations of Bohmian-like
&quot;surreal&quot; trajectories, which are obtained classically, i.e. without the use of
any quantum mechanical tool such as wave functions. However, these trajectories
do not necessarily represent ontological paths of particles but rather mappings
of the probability density flux in a hydrodynamical sense. Modelling emergent
quantum mechanics in a high-low intesity double slit scenario gives rise to the
&quot;quantum sweeper effect&quot; with a characteristic intensity pattern. This
phenomenon should be experimentally testable via weak measurement techniques.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.06807</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.06807</id><created>2016-02-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Ren</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Wenlian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Shouhuai</forenames></author></authors><title>Preventive and Reactive Cyber Defense Dynamics Is Globally Stable</title><categories>cs.CR cs.SI cs.SY math.DS physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The recently proposed {\em cybersecurity dynamics} approach aims to
understand cybersecurity from a holistic perspective by modeling the evolution
of the global cybersecurity state. These models describe the interactions
between the various kinds of cyber defenses and the various kinds of cyber
attacks. We study a particular kind of cybersecurity dynamics caused by the
interactions between preventive and reactive defenses (e.g., filtering and
malware detection) against push- and pull-based cyber attacks (e.g., malware
spreading and &quot;drive-by download&quot; attacks). The dynamics was previously shown
to be globally stable in a {\em special} regime of the parameter universe, but
little is known beyond this special regime. In this paper, we resolve an open
problem in this domain by proving that the dynamics is globally stable in the
{\em entire} parameter universe (i.e., the dynamics always converges to a
unique equilibrium). We discuss the cybersecurity meanings and implications of
this theoretic result. We also prove that the dynamics converges {\em
exponentially} to the equilibrium except for a special parameter regime, in
which case the dynamics converges {\em polynomially}. Since it is often
difficult to compute the equilibrium, we propose new bounds of the equilibrium
and numerically show that these bounds are tighter than those proposed in the
literature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01723</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01723</id><created>2016-03-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Belyaev</keyname><forenames>V. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>M. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Otto</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rakityansky</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nuclear fusion induced by X-rays in a crystal</title><categories>nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>27 pages, 12 figures; submitted to Phys. Rev. C on 28 October 2015</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 93(3) 034622 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.93.034622</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The nuclei that constitute a crystalline lattice, oscillate relative to each
other with a very low energy that is not sufficient to penetrate through the
Coulomb barriers separating them. An additional energy, which is needed to
tunnel through the barrier and fuse, can be supplied by external
electromagnetic waves (X-rays or the synchrotron radiation). Exposing to the
X-rays the solid compound LiD (lithium-deuteride) for the duration of 111
hours, we have detected 88 events of the nuclear fusion d+Li6 ---&gt; Be8*. Our
theoretical estimate agrees with what we observed. One of possible applications
of the phenomenon we found, could be the measurements of the rates of various
nuclear reactions (not necessarily fusion) at extremely low energies
inaccessible in accelerator experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01816</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01816</id><created>2016-03-06</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Grosjean</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mivelle</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burr</keyname><forenames>G. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baida</keyname><forenames>F. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fiber-integrated single photon source of high efficiency based on a
  concept of ultra-broadband optical horn antenna</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>Paper published in 2013</comments><journal-ref>Opt. Express 21, 1762-1772 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.21.001762</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically demonstrate a fiber-integrated single photon source of
unprecedented efficiency. This fiber single photon source is achieved by
coupling optically a single quantum emitter to a monomode optical fiber with a
new concept of ultra-broadband optical antenna. Such an optical antenna concept
is the result of the transposition to optical frequencies of the well-known
low-frequency horn antenna The optical horn antenna is here shown to be capable
of directing the radiation from the emitter toward the optical fiber and
efficiently phase-matching the photon emission with the fiber mode. Numerical
results show that an optical horn antenna can funnel up to 85% of the radiation
from a dipolar source within an emission cone semi-angle as small as 7 degrees
(antenna directivity of 300). It is also shown that 50% of the emitted power
from the dipolar source can be collected and coupled to an SMF-28 fiber mode
over spectral ranges larger than 1000 nm, with a maximum energy transfer
reaching 70 %. This approach is highly promising in the engineering of
all-fiber &quot;on-demand&quot; single photon sources for telecommunication, quantum
optics and sensing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02862</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02862</id><created>2016-03-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Walleczek</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Groessing</keyname><forenames>Gerhard</forenames></author></authors><title>Is the World Local or Nonlocal? Towards an Emergent Quantum Mechanics in
  the 21st Century</title><categories>quant-ph physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 3 figures; talk presented at the 3rd international
  symposium on &quot;Emergent Quantum Mechanics&quot; (Vienna, Austria, 23-25 October,
  2015), this URL http://www.emqm15.org/; To be published in J. Phys.: Conf.
  Ser. (2016)</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Conf. Ser. (2016) 701 012001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/701/1/012001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  What defines an emergent quantum mechanics (EmQM)? Can new insight be
advanced into the nature of quantum nonlocality by seeking new links between
quantum and emergent phenomena as described by self-organization, complexity,
or emergence theory? Could the development of a future EmQM lead to a unified,
relational image of the cosmos? One key motivation for adopting the concept of
emergence in relation to quantum theory concerns the persistent failure in
standard physics to unify the two pillars in the foundations of physics:
quantum theory and general relativity theory (GRT). The total contradiction in
the foundational, metaphysical assumptions that define orthodox quantum theory
versus GRT might render inter-theoretic unification impossible. On the one
hand, indeterminism and non-causality define orthodox quantum mechanics, and,
on the other hand, GRT is governed by causality and determinism. How could
these two metaphysically-contradictory theories ever be reconciled? The present
work argues that metaphysical contradiction necessarily implies physical
contradiction. The contradictions are essentially responsible also for the
measurement problem in quantum mechanics. A common foundation may be needed for
overcoming the contradictions between the two foundational theories. The
concept of emergence, and the development of an EmQM, might help advance a
common foundation - physical and metaphysical - as required for successful
inter-theory unification.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03107</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03107</id><created>2016-03-09</created><updated>2016-03-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tai</keyname><forenames>Yuan-Yen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Jian-Xin</forenames></author></authors><title>Local charge variation enhanced spin canting of BiFeO3/La0.7Sr0.3MnO3
  heterostructure</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><report-no>LA-UR-15-27158</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Transition-metal oxides (TMOs) exhibit many emergent phenomena ranging from
high-temperature super- conductivity and giant magnetoresistance to magnetism
and ferroelectricity. When TMOs are interfaced with each other, new
multi-functionalities can arise, which are absent in individual components. In
this work, we have systematically studied, within a unified double-exchange
model, the interfacial magnetic response in layered BiFeO3 (BFO) and
La0.7Sr0.3MnO3 (LSMO) heterostructures. The ferromagnetic/antiferromagnetic
canting is shown to be enhanced on the interface of BFO by the influence of
local charge variation. More interestingly, it is found that the spin canting
in BFO can be further enhanced with deeper penetration depth to the bulk when a
local oxygen vacancy is placed around the interface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03400</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03400</id><created>2016-03-10</created><updated>2016-03-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Walleczek</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author></authors><title>The super-indeterminism in orthodox quantum mechanics does not implicate
  the reality of experimenter free will</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 4 figures; talk presented at the 3rd international
  symposium on &quot;Emergent Quantum Mechanics&quot; (Vienna, Austria, 23-25 October,
  2015), http://www.emqm15.org/; To be published in J. Phys.: Conf. Ser.
  (2016); V2: Explanations were added regarding the meaning, and the specific
  use by John Bell, of the concept of super-determinism</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Conf. Ser. (2016) 701 012005</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/701/1/012005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The concept of 'super-indeterminism' captures the notion that the free choice
assumption of orthodox quantum mechanics necessitates only the following
requirement: an agent's free-choice performance in the selection of measurement
settings must not represent an exception to the rule of irreducible quantum
indeterminism in the physical universe (i.e, &quot;universal indeterminism&quot;). Any
additional metaphysical speculation, such as to whether quantum indeterminism,
i.e., intrinsic randomness, implicates the reality of experimenter &quot;freedom&quot;,
&quot;free will&quot;, or &quot;free choice&quot;, is redundant in relation to the predictive
success of orthodox quantum mechanics. Accordingly, super-indeterminism views
as redundant also, from a technical standpoint, whether an affirmative or a
negative answer is claimed in reference to universal indeterminism as a
necessary precondition for experimenter freedom. Super-indeterminism accounts,
for example, for the circular reasoning which is implicit in the free will
theorem by Conway and Kochen. The concept of super-indeterminism is of great
assistance in clarifying the often misunderstood meaning of the concept of
&quot;free variables&quot; as used by John Bell. The present work argues that Bell sought
an operational, effective free will theorem, one based upon the notion of
&quot;determinism without predetermination&quot;, i.e., one wherein &quot;free variables&quot;
represent universally uncomputable variables. In conclusion, the standard
interpretation of quantum theory does not answer, and does not need to answer
in order to ensure the predictive success of orthodox theory, the question of
whether either incompatibilism or compatibilism is valid in relation to
free-will metaphysics and to the free-will phenomenology of experimenter agents
in quantum mechanics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04357</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04357</id><created>2016-03-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Gurram</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Omar</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zihlmann</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Makk</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xf6;nenberger</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Wees</keyname><forenames>B. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin transport in fully hexagonal boron nitride encapsulated graphene</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures, Accepted in Physical Review B</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.115441</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study fully hexagonal boron nitride (hBN)-encapsulated graphene spin valve
devices at room temperature. The device consists of a graphene channel
encapsulated between two crystalline hBN flakes; thick-hBN flake as a bottom
gate dielectric substrate which masks the charge impurities from SiO2/Si
substrate and single-layer thin-hBN flake as a tunnel barrier. Full
encapsulation prevents the graphene from coming in contact with any
polymer/chemical during the lithography and thus gives homogeneous charge and
spin transport properties across different regions of the encapsulated
graphene. Further, even with the multiple electrodes in between the injection
and the detection electrodes which are in conductivity mismatch regime, we
observe spin transport over 12.5 um long distance under the thin-hBN
encapsulated graphene channel, demonstrating the clean interface and the
pin-hole free nature of the thin-hBN as an efficient tunnel barrier.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04945</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04945</id><created>2016-03-15</created><updated>2016-03-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Isagozawa</keyname><forenames>Ayami</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shirakura</keyname><forenames>Takayuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanabe</keyname><forenames>Satsuki</forenames></author></authors><title>Instability of group formation through indirect reciprocity under
  imperfect information and implementation error</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 11 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Indirect reciprocity is a key mechanism behind the evolution of cooperation.
Oishi et al. analytically showed the formation of two exclusive groups under
the KANDORI assessment rule in the case of perfect information and no
implementation error, regardless of the population size $N$. Here, we
numerically show the formation of many exclusive groups under the JUDGING
assessment rule in the same case. Introducing degrees of exclusive groups, we
numerically examine the stability of the group formation under imperfect
information and implementation error.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05082</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05082</id><created>2016-03-16</created><updated>2016-03-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kremer</keyname><forenames>G. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richarte</keyname><forenames>Mart&#xed;n G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>Karla</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-gravitating systems of ideal gases in the 1PN approximation</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.GA hep-th</categories><comments>11 pages, 6 figures. Phys. Rev. D 93, 064073 (2016)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 064073 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.064073</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We obtain the Maxwell-J\&quot;uttner distribution function at first order in the
post-Newtonian approximation within the framework of general relativity. Taking
into account the aforesaid distribution function, we compute the particle
four-flow and energy-momentum tensor. We focus on the search of static
solutions for the gravitational potentials with spherical symmetry. In doing
so, we obtain the density, pressure and gravitational potential energy profiles
in terms of dimensionless radial coordinate by solving the aforesaid equations
numerically. In particular, we find the parametric profile for the equation of
state $p/\rho$ in terms of the dimensionless radial coordinate. Due to its
physical relevance, we also find the galaxy rotation curves using the
post-Newtonian approximation. We join two different kinds of static solutions
in order to account for the linear regime near the center and the typical
flatten behavior at large radii as well.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05392</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05392</id><created>2016-03-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Xing</keyname><forenames>Xiangzhuo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Nan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Feifei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Yongqiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Haijun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Xiaofeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Zhixiang</forenames></author></authors><title>Anisotropic Ginzburg-Landau scaling of Hc2 and transport properties of
  112-type Ca0.8La0.2Fe0.98Co0.02As2 single crystal</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>15 pages, 7 figures, Accepted for publication in
  Supercond.Sci.Technol</comments><journal-ref>Supercond.Sci.Technol. 29, 055005 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-2048/29/5/055005</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  High-quality single crystal of Ca0.8La0.2Fe0.98Co0.02As2 has been
successfully synthesized using a self-flux method. The magnetization
measurement reveals a second peak effect and high critical current density
exceeding 2*10^6 A/cm2 at 5 K(self-field). The upper critical field anisotropy
was systematically studied by measuring the electrical resistivity under
various magnetic fields and angles. The angle dependent magnetoresistance, by
choosing an appropriate anisotropy parameter within the framework of the
anisotropic Ginzburg Landau (AGL) theory, can be scaled onto one single curve.
In the normal state, the negative Hall coefficient shows strong but
nonmonotonic T-dependence through a minimum at 175 K. Moreover, it is shown
that the magnetoresistance apparently violates the semiclassical Kohler's rule
below 175 K but can be well scaled by the Hall angle instead. This suggests
either the change of carriers with T or the exotic anisotropic scattering in
the system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05595</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05595</id><created>2016-03-16</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Paschos</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Short Wavelength Oscillations with Right-Handed Neutrinos</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>17 pages</comments><report-no>DO-TH 16/08</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The standard model is extended with three right-handed, singlet neutrinos
with general couplings permitted by the $SU(2)_{L}\times U(1)$ symmetry. The
traditional oscillations are accounted for, as usually, by three left-handed
neutrinos. The article investigates new structures that develop when the masses
of the right-handed states are in the eV range. The new states interfere and
oscillate with the standard light neutrinos. New structures appear when the
detectors average over short wavelengths. I use these results to present and
classify properties of the observed anomalies in the MiniBooNe, reactor and
Gallium-detector experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05866</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05866</id><created>2016-03-18</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Costa</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sciacca</keyname><forenames>Eva</forenames></author><author><keyname>Becciani</keyname><forenames>Ugo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Massimino</keyname><forenames>Piero</forenames></author><author><keyname>Riggi</keyname><forenames>Simone</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanchez</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vitello</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author></authors><title>An Innovative Workspace for The Cherenkov Telescope Array</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Cherenkov Telescope Array (CTA) is an initiative to build the next
generation, ground-based gamma-ray observatories. We present a prototype
workspace developed at INAF that aims at providing innovative solutions for the
CTA community. The workspace leverages open source technologies providing web
access to a set of tools widely used by the CTA community. Two different user
interaction models, connected to an authentication and authorization
infrastructure, have been implemented in this workspace. The first one is a
workflow management system accessed via a science gateway (based on the Liferay
platform) and the second one is an interactive virtual desktop environment. The
integrated workflow system allows to run applications used in astronomy and
physics researches into distributed computing infrastructures (ranging from
clusters to grids and clouds). The interactive desktop environment allows to
use many software packages without any installation on local desktops
exploiting their native graphical user interfaces. The science gateway and the
interactive desktop environment are connected to the authentication and
authorization infrastructure composed by a Shibboleth identity provider and a
Grouper authorization solution. The Grouper released attributes are consumed by
the science gateway to authorize the access to specific web resources and the
role management mechanism in Liferay provides the attribute-role mapping.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06604</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06604</id><created>2016-03-21</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Rong-Feng</forenames><affiliation>Hebrew University</affiliation><affiliation>Tel Aviv University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Nakar</keyname><forenames>Ehud</forenames><affiliation>Tel Aviv University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Piran</keyname><forenames>Tsvi</forenames><affiliation>Hebrew University</affiliation></author></authors><title>The dynamics of radiation driven, optically thick winds</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>9 pages, 3 figures, MNRAS accepted, corrected proof</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw645</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent observation of some luminous transient sources with low color
temperatures suggests that the emission is dominated by optically thick winds
driven by super-Eddington accretion. We present a general analytical theory of
the dynamics of radiation pressure-driven, optically thick winds. Unlike the
classical adiabatic stellar wind solution whose dynamics are solely determined
by the sonic radius, here the loss of the radiation pressure due to photon
diffusion also plays an important role. We identify two high mass loss rate
regimes ($\dot{M} &gt; L_{\rm Edd\,}/c^2$). In the large total luminosity regime
the solution resembles an adiabatic wind solution. Both the radiative
luminosity, $L$, and the kinetic luminosity, $L_k$, are super-Eddington with $L
&lt; L_k$ and $L \propto L_k^{1/3}$. In the lower total luminosity regime most of
the energy is carried out by the radiation with $L_k &lt; L \approx L_{\rm
Edd\,}$. In a third, low mass loss regime ($\dot{M} &lt; L_{\rm Edd\,}/c^2$), the
wind becomes optically thin early on and, unless gas pressure is important at
this stage, the solution is very different from the adiabatic one. The results
are independent from the energy generation mechanism at the foot of the wind,
therefore they are applicable to a wide range of mass ejection systems, from
black hole accretion, to planetary nebulae, and to classical novae.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06816</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06816</id><created>2016-03-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Bourrion</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boyer</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Derome</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pignol</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>UCTM2: An updated User friendly Configurable Trigger, scaler and delay
  Module for nuclear and particle physics</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>14 pages, 9 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1110.2917</comments><journal-ref>Nucl. Instrum. Meth. A 821 (2016) 169-177</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2016.03.068</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We developed a highly integrated and versatile electronic module to equip
small nuclear physics experiments and lab teaching classes: the User friendly
Configurable Trigger, scaler and delay Module for nuclear and particle physics
(UCTM). It is configurable through a Graphical User Interface (GUI) and
provides a large number of possible trigger conditions without any Hardware
Description Language (HDL) required knowledge. This new version significantly
enhances the previous capabilities by providing two additional features: signal
digitization and time measurements. The design, performances and a typical
application are presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09106</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09106</id><created>2016-03-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Obukhov</keyname><forenames>Yuri N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Puetzfeld</keyname><forenames>Dirk</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics of test bodies in scalar-tensor theory and equivalence
  principle</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>Gravitation, Astrophysics, and Cosmology - Proceedings of the Twelfth
  Asia-Pacific International Conference, Moscow, 28 Jun - 5 July 2015, Eds. V.
  Melnikov and J.-P. Hsu, World Scientific (Singapore), 2016, pp. 231-235</comments><doi>10.1142/9789814759816_0043</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  How do test bodies move in scalar-tensor theories of gravitation? We provide
an answer to this question on the basis of a unified multipolar scheme. In
particular, we give the explicit equations of motion for pointlike, as well as
spinning test bodies, thus extending the well-known general relativistic
results of Mathisson, Papapetrou, and Dixon to scalar-tensor theories of
gravity. We demonstrate the validity of the equivalence principle for test
bodies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09344</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09344</id><created>2016-03-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Payne</keyname><forenames>Matthew J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Veras</keyname><forenames>Dimitri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holman</keyname><forenames>Matthew J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaensicke</keyname><forenames>Boris T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Liberating exomoons in white dwarf planetary systems</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Published (MNRAS): First published online January 19, 2016</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS (March 21, 2016) 457 (1): 217-231</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv2966</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Previous studies indicate that more than a quarter of all white dwarf (WD)
atmospheres are polluted by remnant planetary material, with some WDs being
observed to accrete the mass of Pluto in 10^6 years. The short sinking
timescale for the pollutants indicate that the material must be frequently
replenished. Moons may contribute decisively to this pollution process if they
are liberated from their parent planets during the post-main-sequence evolution
of the planetary systems. Here, we demonstrate that gravitational scattering
events among planets in WD systems easily triggers moon ejection. Repeated
close encounters within tenths of a planetary Hill radii are highly destructive
to even the most massive, close-in moons. Consequently, scattering increases
both the frequency of perturbing agents in WD systems, as well as the available
mass of polluting material in those systems, thereby enhancing opportunities
for collision and fragmentation and providing more dynamical pathways for
smaller bodies to reach the WD. Moreover, during intense scattering, planets
themselves have pericenters with respect to the WD of only a fraction of an AU,
causing extreme Hill-sphere contraction, and the liberation of moons into
WD-grazing orbits. Many of our results are directly applicable to exomoons
orbiting planets around main sequence stars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09357</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09357</id><created>2016-03-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Ovelar</keyname><forenames>M. de Juan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pinilla</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Min</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dominik</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Birnstiel</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Constraining turbulence mixing strength in transitional discs with
  planets using SPHERE and ALMA</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Accepted 2016 March 21, MNRAS Letters. Monthly Notices of the Royal
  Astronomical Society: Letters 2016</comments><doi>10.1093/mnrasl/slw051</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the effect that the turbulent mixing strength parameter
$\alpha_{\rm{turb}}$ plays on near-infrared polarimetric and sub-millimetre
interferometric imaging observations of transitional discs (TDs) with a gap
carved by a planet. We generate synthetic observations of these objects with
ALMA and VLT/SPHERE-ZIMPOL by combining hydrodynamical, dust evolution,
radiative transfer and instrument models for values of
$\alpha_{\rm{turb}}=[10^{-4}, 10^{-3}, 10^{-2}]$. We find that, through a
combination of effects on the viscosity of the gas, the turbulent mixing and
dust evolution processes, $\alpha_{\rm{turb}}$ strongly affects the morphology
of the dust distribution that can be traced with these observations. We
constrain the value of $\alpha_{\rm{turb}}$ to be within an order of magnitude
of $10^{-3}$ in TD sources that show cavities in sub-mm continuum images while
featuring continuous distribution of dust or smaller cavities in
NIR-polarimetric images.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09360</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09360</id><created>2016-03-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Donev</keyname><forenames>Stoil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tashkova</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Pre-metric Formulation and Nonlinearization of Charge-free
  Electrodynamics</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.MP</categories><comments>17 pages, no figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1508.04824</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Geometry and Symmetry in Physics, vol.40 (1-24) 2015</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents a coordinate free pre-metric formulation of charge free
Maxwell-Minkowski electrodynamics, and of the developed by the authors
non-linear Extended Electrodynamics. First we introduce some formal relations
from multilinear algebra and differential geometry to be used further. Then we
recall and appropriately modify the existing pre-metric formulation of linear
charge free electrodynamics in pre-relativistic and relativistic forms as
preparation to turn to corresponding pre-metric nonlinearization. After some
preliminary examples and notes on nonlinearization, we motivate our view for
existence and explicit formulation of time stable subsystems of the physical
field objects considered. Section 5 presents the formal results of our approach
on the pre-metric nonlinear formulations in static case, in time-dependent
case, and in space-time formulation. In the Conclusion we give our general view
on &quot;why and how to nonlinearize&quot;. The Appendix gives a possible formal
extension of our aproach to many subsystem field objects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09366</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09366</id><created>2016-02-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Belyaev</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kazakov</keyname><forenames>D. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sperling</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>SUSY at the LHC without Missing P_T</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>PdfLatex, 11 pages, 5 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1505.02041</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a specific class of events of the SUSY particle production at the
LHC without missing p_T. Namely, we discuss the chargino pair production with a
further decay into the W-boson and the neutralino when the masses of the
chargino and neutralino differ by 80-90 GeV. In this case, in the final state
one has two Ws and missing E_T but no missing P_T. The produced neutralinos are
just boosted along Ws. For a demonstration we consider the MSSM with
non-universal gaugino masses. In this case, such events are quite probable in
the region of parameter space where the lightest chargino and neutralino are
mostly gauginos. The excess in the W production cross-section reach about 10 %
over the Standard Model background. We demonstrate that the LHC experiments,
which presently measure the WW production cross section at the 8 % level can
probe chargino mass around 110 GeV within the suggested scenario, which is not
accessible via other searches. If the precision of WW cross section measurement
at the LHC will achieve the 3 % level, then it would probe chargino masses up
to about 150 GeV within the no missing P_T scenario.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09370</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09370</id><created>2016-03-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Pagnotta</keyname><forenames>Ashley</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zurek</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-Detection of Nova Shells Around Asynchronous Polars</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures, to be published in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, 2016, Volume
  458, Issue 2, p.1833-1838</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw424</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Asynchronous polars (APs) are accreting white dwarfs (WDs) that have
different WD and orbital angular velocities, unlike the rest of the known
polars, which rotate synchronously (i.e., their WD and orbital angular
velocities are the same). Past nova eruptions are the predicted cause of the
asynchronicity, in part due to the fact that one of the APs, V1500 Cyg, was
observed to undergo a nova eruption in 1975. We used the Southern African Large
Telescope 10m class telescope and the MDM 2.4m Hiltner telescope to search for
nova shells around three of the remaining four APs (V1432 Aql, BY Cam, and CD
Ind) as well as one Intermediate Polar with a high asynchronicity (EX Hya). We
found no evidence of nova shells in any of our images. We therefore cannot say
that any of the systems besides V1500 Cyg had nova eruptions, but because not
all post-nova systems have detectable shells, we also cannot exclude the
possibility of a nova eruption occurring in any of these systems and knocking
the rotation out of sync.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09374</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09374</id><created>2016-03-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Haze</keyname><forenames>Kanae</forenames></author><author><keyname>Enya</keyname><forenames>Keigo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abe</keyname><forenames>Lyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takahashi</keyname><forenames>Aoi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kotani</keyname><forenames>Takayuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamamuro</keyname><forenames>Tomoyasu</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental demonstration of binary shaped pupil mask coronagraphs for
  telescopes with obscured pupils</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>17 pages, 8 figures</comments><doi>10.1093/pasj/psu161</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the fabrication and experimental demonstration of three
free-standing binary shaped pupil mask coronagraphs, which are applicable for
telescopes with partially obscured pupils. Three masks, designed to be
complementary (labeled Mask-A, Mask-B, and Mask-C), were formed in 5 micron
thick nickel. The design of Mask-A is based on a one-dimensional barcode mask.
The design principle of Mask-B is similar, but has a smaller inner working
angle and a lower contrast than Mask-A. Mask-C is based on a concentric ring
mask and provides the widest dark region and a symmetric point spread function.
Mask-A and Mask-C were both designed to produce a flexibly tailored dark region
(i.e., non-uniform contrast). The contrast was evaluated using a light source
comprising a broadband super-luminescent light-emitting diode with a center
wavelength of 650 nm, and the measurements were carried out in a large vacuum
chamber. Active wavefront control was not applied in this work. The
coronagraphic images obtained by experiment were mostly consistent with the
designs. The contrast of Mask-A within the ranges 3.3 - 8 lambda/D and 8 - 12
lambda/D was ~10^{-4} - 10^{-7} and ~10^{-7}, respectively, where lambda is the
wavelength and D is the pupil diameter. The contrast close to the center of
Mask-B was ~10^{-4} and that of Mask-C over an extended field of view (5 - 25
lambda/D) was ~10^{-5} - 10^{-6}. The effect of tilting the masks was
investigated, and found to be irrelevant at the ~10^{-7} contrast level.
Therefore the masks can be tilted to avoid ghosting. These high-contrast
free-standing masks have the potential to enable coronagraphic imaging over a
wide wavelength range using both ground-based and space-borne general-purpose
telescopes with pupil structures not specifically designed for coronagraphy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09378</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09378</id><created>2016-03-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Chunyun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Mo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yuwen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Zheng</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects of Slotted Structures on Nonlinear Characteristics of Natural
  Convection in a Cylinder with an Internal Concentric Slotted Annulus</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Natural convection in a cylinder with an internally slotted annulus was
solved by SIMPLE algorithm, and the effects of different slotted structures on
nonlinear characteristics of natural convection were investigated. The results
show that the equivalent thermal conductivity Keq increases with Rayleigh
number, and reaches the maximum in the vertical orientation. Nonlinear results
were obtained by simulating the fluid flow at different conditions. With
increasing Rayleigh number, heat transfer is intensified and the state of heat
transfer changes from the steady to unsteady. We investigated different slotted
structures effects on natural convection, and analyze the corresponding
nonlinear characteristics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09380</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09380</id><created>2016-03-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Irawan</keyname><forenames>Dasapta Erwin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Puradimaja</keyname><forenames>Deny Juanda</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yeni</keyname><forenames>Defitri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuntoro</keyname><forenames>Arno Adi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Julian</keyname><forenames>Miga Magenika</forenames></author></authors><title>Decreasing groundwater quality at Cisadane riverbanks:
  groundwater-surface water approach</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures, have been presented in Asian Physics Symposium in
  Indonesia 2015 and will be published in IOP Conference Series</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The decreasing of groundwater quality has been the major issue in Tangerang
area. One of the key process is the interaction between groundwater and
Cisadane river water, which flows over volcanic deposits of Bojongmanik Fm,
Genteng Fm, Tuf Banten, and Alluvial Fan. The objective of this study is to
unravel such interactions based on the potentiometric mapping in the riverbank.
We had 60 stop sites along the riverbank for groundwater and river water level
observations, and chemical measurements (TDS, EC, temp, and pH). Three river
water gauge were also analyzed to see the fluctuations.
  We identified three types of hydrodynamic relationships with fairly low flow
gradients: effluent flow at Segmen I (Kranggan - Batuceper) with 0.2-0.25
gradient, perched flow at Segmen II (Batuceper-Kalibaru) with gradient
0.2-0.25, and influent flow at Segmen III (Kalibaru-Tanjungburung) with
gradient 0.15-0.20. Such low flow gradient is controlled by the moderate to low
morphological slope in the area. The gaining and losing stream model were also
supported by the river water fluctuation data. TDS and EC readings increased
more than 40$\%$ from upstream to downstream. At some points the both
measurements were two times higher than the permissible limits, along with the
drops of pH values at those areas.
  This study shows the very close interaction between Cisadane river water and
groundwater in the riverbank. Therefore the authorities need to be managed the
areas with a very strict regulations related to the small and large scale
industries located near by the river.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09395</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09395</id><created>2016-03-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Bin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Dong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Pei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Hong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Fuli</forenames></author></authors><title>Observing spin Hall effect of pseudo-thermal light through weak
  measurement</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is well known that the spin Hall effect of light (SHEL) can be easily
observed via weak measurement by the dark strip resulted from the splitting of
different polarization components. We find that the SHEL of partially coherent
beam (PCB) also has similar phenomenon. However, the existence of the dark
strip in the SHEL of PCB can not be properly justified by considering the beam
as a statistical assemble of coherent speckles. Also, the dark strip of PCB is
not purely dark. By analyzing the autocorrelation of the central dark strip
part of the SHEL of PCB, we show that SHEL of PCB is essentially the direct
result of overlapping coherent speckles' SHEL. Then we further prove our
conclusion by adjusting the converging level and the incident angle of the
beam. Finally, we develop a qualitative theory by taking the intensity
distribution of PCB into account, to fully clarify the SHEL of PCB. The
feasibility of our theory to Goos-H\&quot;anchen (GH) scenario is also demonstrated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09416</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09416</id><created>2016-03-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Titov</keyname><forenames>Oleg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lambert</keyname><forenames>Sebastien</forenames></author></authors><title>Search for the primordial gravitational waves with Very Long Baseline
  Interferometry</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>28th Texas Symposium on Relativistic Astrophysics</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Some models of the expanding Universe predict that the astrometric proper
motion of distant radio sources embedded in space-time are non-zero as the
radial distance from observer to the source grows. Systematic proper motion
effects would produce a predictable quadrupole pattern on the sky that could be
detected using Very Long Baseline Interferometry (VLBI) technique. This
quadrupole pattern can be interpreted either as an anisotropic Hubble
expansion, or as a signature of the primordial gravitational waves in the early
Universe. We present our analysis of a large set of geodetic VLBI data spanning
1979--2015 to estimate the dipole and quadrupole harmonics in the expansion of
the vector field of the proper motions of quasars in the sky. The analysis is
repeated for different redshift zones.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09428</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09428</id><created>2016-03-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Montet</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loomis</keyname><forenames>Ryan</forenames></author></authors><title>SET-E: The Search for Extraterrestrial Environmentalism</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures, Comments Welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There is currently no evidence for life on any known exoplanet. Here, we
propose a form of &quot;galactic anthropology&quot; to detect not only the existence of
life on transiting exoplanets, but also the existence of environmentalism
movements. By observing the planet's atmosphere over long time baselines, the
destruction and recovery of a hole in an exoplanet's ozone layer may be
observable. While not readily detectable for any one system with JWST, by
binning together observations of hundreds of systems we can finally determine
the occurrence rate of environmental movements on Earthlike planets in the
galaxy, a number we term eta-Green-Earth.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09438</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09438</id><created>2016-03-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Hinton</keyname><forenames>Samuel R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davis</keyname><forenames>Tamara M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lidman</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glazebrook</keyname><forenames>Karl</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lewis</keyname><forenames>Geraint F.</forenames></author></authors><title>MARZ: Manual and Automatic Redshifting Software</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>15 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Astronomy and Computing, 15 (2016) 61-71</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ascom.2016.03.001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Australian Dark Energy Survey (OzDES) is a 100-night spectroscopic survey
underway on the Anglo-Australian Telescope using the fibre-fed 2-degree-field
(2dF) spectrograph. We have developed a new redshifting application Marz with
greater usability, flexibility, and the capacity to analyse a wider range of
object types than the Runz software package previously used for redshifting
spectra from 2dF. Marz is an open-source, client-based, Javascript
web-application which provides an intuitive interface and powerful automatic
matching capabilities on spectra generated from the AAOmega spectrograph to
produce high quality spectroscopic redshift measurements. The software can be
run interactively or via the command line, and is easily adaptable to other
instruments and pipelines if conforming to the current FITS file standard is
not possible. Behind the scenes, a modified version of the Autoz
cross-correlation algorithm is used to match input spectra against a variety of
stellar and galaxy templates, and automatic matching performance for OzDES
spectra has increased from 54% (Runz) to 91% (Marz). Spectra not matched
correctly by the automatic algorithm can be easily redshifted manually by
cycling automatic results, manual template comparison, or marking spectral
features.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09449</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09449</id><created>2016-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>Ryota</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lambiotte</keyname><forenames>Renaud</forenames></author></authors><title>TiDeH: Time-Dependent Hawkes Process for Predicting Retweet Dynamics</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>The manuscript has been accepted in the 10th International AAAI
  Conference on Web and Social Media (ICWSM 2016)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Online social networking services allow their users to post content in the
form of text, images or videos. The main mechanism driving content diffusion is
the possibility for users to re-share the content posted by their social
connections, which may then cascade across the system. A fundamental problem
when studying information cascades is the possibility to develop sound
mathematical models, whose parameters can be calibrated on empirical data, in
order to predict the future course of a cascade after a window of observation.
In this paper, we focus on Twitter and, in particular, on the temporal patterns
of retweet activity for an original tweet. We model the system by
Time-Dependent Hawkes process (TiDeH), which properly takes into account the
circadian nature of the users and the aging of information. The input of the
prediction model are observed retweet times and structural information about
the underlying social network. We develop a procedure for parameter
optimization and for predicting the future profiles of retweet activity at
different time resolutions. We validate our methodology on a large corpus of
Twitter data and demonstrate its systematic improvement over existing
approaches in all the time regimes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09453</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09453</id><created>2016-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Woodall</keyname><forenames>William H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Meng J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paynabar</keyname><forenames>Kamran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sparks</keyname><forenames>Ross</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilson</keyname><forenames>James D.</forenames></author></authors><title>An overview and perspective on social network monitoring</title><categories>stat.OT cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>To appear, IIE Transactions</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this expository paper we give an overview of some statistical methods for
the monitoring of social networks. We discuss the advantages and limitations of
various methods as well as some relevant issues. One of our primary
contributions is to give the relationships between network monitoring methods
and monitoring methods in engineering statistics and public health
surveillance. We encourage researchers in the industrial process monitoring
area to work on developing and comparing the performance of social network
monitoring methods. We also discuss some of the issues in social network
monitoring and give a number of research ideas.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09470</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09470</id><created>2016-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Troitskaya</keyname><forenames>Saule D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Behavior as $t\rightarrow \infty$ of Solutions of a problem in
  Mathematical Physics</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Published version with some misprints corrected</comments><msc-class>35L (Primary) 47A11, 76U05 (Secondary)</msc-class><journal-ref>Russian Journal of Mathematical Physics, Vol. 17, No. 3, 2010, pp.
  342-362</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S1061920810020093</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A class of solutions, decaying as $t\rightarrow \infty$, of a two-dimensional
model problem on the oscillations of an ideal rotating fluid in some domains
with angular points is constructed explicitly. The existence of solutions whose
$L_2$-norms decrease more rapidly than any negative power of $t$, is
established.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09484</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09484</id><created>2016-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Constantin</keyname><forenames>L. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fabiano</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Della Sala</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Kinetic and Exchange Energy Densities near the Nucleus</title><categories>cond-mat.other cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the behavior of the kinetic and the exchange energy densities
near the nuclear cusp of atomic systems. Considering hydrogenic orbitals, we
derive analytical expressions near the nucleus, for single shells, as well as
in the semiclassical limit of large non-relativistic neutral atoms. We show
that a model based on the helium iso-electronic series is very accurate, as
also confirmed by numerical calculations on real atoms up to two thousands
electrons. Based on this model, we propose non-local density-dependent
ingredients that are suitable for the description of the kinetic and exchange
energy densities in the region close to the nucleus. These non-local
ingredients are invariant under the uniform scaling of the density, and they
can be used in the construction of non-local exchange-correlation and kinetic
functionals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09494</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09494</id><created>2016-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Toranzo</keyname><forenames>I. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dehesa</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>R\'enyi, Shannon and Tsallis entropies of Rydberg hydrogenic systems</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. Lett. (EPL) 113 (2016) 48003</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/113/48003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The R\'enyi entropies $R_{p}[\rho], 0&lt;p&lt;\infty$ of the probability density
$\rho_{n,l,m}(\vec{r})$ of a physical system completely characterize the
chemical and physical properties of the quantum state described by the three
integer quantum numbers $(n,l,m)$. The analytical determination of these
quantities is practically impossible up until now, even for the very few
systems where their Schr\&quot;odinger equation is exactly solved. In this work, the
R\'enyi entropies of Rydberg (highly-excited) hydrogenic states are explicitly
calculated in terms of the quantum numbers and the parameter $p$. To do that we
use a methodology which first connects these quantities to the
$\mathcal{L}_{p}$-norms $N_{n,l}(p)$ of the Laguerre polynomials which
characterize the state's wavefunction. Then, the R\'enyi, Shannon and Tsallis
entropies of the Rydberg states are determined by calculating the asymptotics
($n\rightarrow\infty$) of these Laguerre norms. Finally, these quantities are
numerically examined in terms of the quantum numbers and the nuclear charge.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09496</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09496</id><created>2016-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Lund</keyname><forenames>Michael B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Astrology in the Era of Exoplanets</title><categories>physics.pop-ph astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures, submission for Acta Prima Aprilia</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The last two decades have seen the number of known exoplanets increase from a
small handful to nearly 2000 known exoplanets, thousands more planet
candidates, and several upcoming missions that are expected to further increase
the population of known exoplanets. Beyond the strictly scientific questions
that this has led to regarding planet formation and frequency, this has also
led to broader questions such as the philosophical implications of life
elsewhere in the universe and the future of human civilization and space
exploration. One additional realm that hasn't been adequately considered,
however, is that this large increase in exoplanets would also impact claims
regarding astrology. In this paper we look at the distribution of planets
across the sky and along the Ecliptic, as well as the current and future
implications of this planet distribution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09499</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09499</id><created>2016-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Urasaki</keyname><forenames>Kentaro</forenames></author></authors><title>Classicality in Quantum Mechanics: model for pointer states and
  decoherence</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have studied the emergence of classical states in the perturbative
interaction model. The states which interact with many other degrees of
freedom, such as the center of mass of a macro-object, play important role.
Although the random phase mechanism is effective as same as Zurek's strong
correlation model, there are enormous states, each of which independently
developes due to the orthogonality of the environmental states. In these
privileged states, the subsystem picture with the separability is stable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09506</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09506</id><created>2016-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Mustill</keyname><forenames>Alexander James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davies</keyname><forenames>Melvyn B</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johansen</keyname><forenames>Anders</forenames></author></authors><title>Hot Jupiters and Super-Earths</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Proceedings of the conference &quot;Twenty years of giant exoplanets&quot;.
  Twenty years of giant exoplanets - Proceedings of the Haute Provence
  Observatory Colloquium, 5-9 October 2015 - Edited by I. Boisse, O. Demangeon,
  F. Bouchy &amp; L. Arnold - Published online 9 March 2016. p. 132-138</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore the role of dynamics in shaping planetary system multiplicities,
focussing on two particular problems. (1) We propose that the lack of close-in
super-Earths in hot Jupiter systems is a signature of the migration history of
the hot Jupiters and helps to discriminate between different mechanisms of
migration. We present N-body simulations of dynamical migration scenarios where
proto-hot Jupiters are excited to high eccentricities prior to tidal
circularisation and orbital decay. We show that in this scenario, the eccentric
giant planet typically destroys planets in the inner system, in agreement with
the observed lack of close super-Earth companions to hot Jupiters. (2) We
explore the role of the dynamics of outer systems in affecting the
multiplicities of close-in systems such as those discovered by Kepler. We
consider specifically the effects of planet--planet scattering and Kozai
perturbations on an exterior giant planet on the architecture of the inner
system, and evaluate the ability of such scenarios to reduce the inner system's
multiplicity and contribute to the observed excess of single Kepler planets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09571</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09571</id><created>2015-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Moskalenko</keyname><forenames>Sveatoslav A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Podlesny</keyname><forenames>Igor V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dumanov</keyname><forenames>Evgheni V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liberman</keyname><forenames>Michael A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects of Rashba spin-orbit coupling, Zeeman splitting and gyrotropy in
  two-dimensional cavity polaritons under the influence of the Landau
  quantization</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>24 pages, 11 figures</comments><report-no>NORDITA_2015-77</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. B (2015) 88: 218</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2015-60335-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  GaAs-type quantum wells (QWs) with p-type valence band embedded into the
resonators. The Landau quantization of the electrons and heavy-holes (hh) was
investigated taking into account the Rashba spin-orbit coupling with
third-order chirality terms for hh and with nonparabolicity terms in their
dispersion low including the Zeeman splitting (ZS) effects. The exact solutions
for the eigenfunctions and eigenenergies were obtained using the Rashba method
[1]. We derive in the second quantization representation the Hamiltonians
describing the Coulomb electron-electron and the electron-radiation
interactions and determine the magnetoexciton energy branches and the
magnetoexciton-photon interaction. The fifth order dispersion equation
describing the energy spectrum of the cavity magnetoexciton-polariton is
investigated. It takes into account the interaction of the cavity photons with
two dipole-active and with two quadrupole-active 2D magnetoexciton energy
branches. The cavity photons have the circular polarizations oriented along
their wave vectors, which has the quantized longitudinal component. The
selection rules of the exciton-photon interaction is expressed through the
scalar products of the two-types circular polarizations and it is related with
the numbers of the LQ levels of electrons and heavy-holes. It is shown that the
Rabi frequency of the polariton branches and the magnetoexciton oscillator
strength increase in dependence on the magnetic field strength. The optical
gyrotropy effects may be revealed if changing the sign of the photon circular
polarization at a given sign of the wave vector longitudinal projection or
equivalently changing the sign of the longitudinal projection at the same
selected light circular polarization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09573</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09573</id><created>2015-11-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Istomin</keyname><forenames>Ya. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Semerikov</keyname><forenames>I. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic field evolution of accreting neutron stars</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>8 pages,6 figures</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv2473</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The flow of a matter, accreting onto a magnetized neutron star, is
accompanied by an electric current. The closing of the electric current occurs
in the crust of a neutron stars in the polar region across the magnetic field.
But the conductivity of the crust along the magnetic field greatly exceeds the
conductivity across the field, so the current penetrates deep into the crust
down up to the super conducting core. The magnetic field, generated by the
accretion current, increases greatly with the depth of penetration due to the
Hall conductivity of the crust is also much larger than the transverse
conductivity. As a result, the current begins to flow mainly in the toroidal
direction, creating a strong longitudinal magnetic field, far exceeding an
initial dipole field. This field exists only in the narrow polar tube of $r$
width, narrowing with the depth, i.e. with increasing of the crust density
$\rho$, $r\propto \rho^{-1/4}$. Accordingly, the magnetic field $B$ in the tube
increases with the depth, $B\propto \rho^{1/2}$, and reaches the value of about
$10^{17}$ Gauss in the core. It destroys super conducting vortices in the core
of a star in the narrow region of the size of the order of ten centimeters.
Because of generated density gradient of vortices they constantly flow into
this dead zone and the number of vortices decreases, the magnetic field of a
star decreases as well. The attenuation of the magnetic field is exponential,
$B=B_0(1+t/\tau)^{-1}$. The characteristic time of decreasing of the magnetic
field $\tau$ is equal to $\tau\simeq 10^3$ years. Thus, the magnetic field of
accreted neutron stars decreases to values of $10^8 - 10^9$ Gauss during
$10^7-10^6$ years.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09576</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09576</id><created>2015-07-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Jun Hee</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xe9;zsm&#xe1;ki</keyname><forenames>Istvan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fishman</keyname><forenames>Randy S.</forenames></author></authors><title>First-principles approach to the dynamic magnetoelectric couplings in
  BiFeO$_3$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Despite its great technological importance, the magnetoelectric (ME)
couplings in \BF are barely understood. By using a first-principles approach,
we uncover the {\it dynamic} ME couplings of the long-range spin-cycloid in
BiFeO$_3$. Based on a microscopic Hamiltonian, our first-principles approach
disentangles the hidden ME couplings due to spin-current and
exchange-striction. Beyond the spin-current polarization governed by the
inverse Dzyaloshinskii-Moriya interaction \cite{iDM}, various spin-current
polarizations derived from both ferroelectric and antiferrodistortive
distortions cooperatively produce the strong non-reciprocal directional
dichroism or the asymmetry in the absorption of counter-propagating light in
BiFeO$_3$. Our systematic approach can be generally applied to any multiferroic
material, laying the foundation for revealing hidden ME couplings on an atomic
scale and for exploiting optical ME effects in the next generation of
technological devices such as optical diodes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09577</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09577</id><created>2015-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Chai</keyname><forenames>Zhenhua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Baochang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Zhaoli</forenames></author></authors><title>A general multiple-relaxation-time lattice Boltzmann model for nonlinear
  anisotropic convection-diffusion equations</title><categories>physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>45 pages, 17 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, based on the previous work [B. Shi, Z. Guo, Lattice Boltzmann
model for nonlinear convection-diffusion equations, Phys. Rev. E 79 (2009)
016701], we develop a general multiple-relaxation-time (MRT) lattice Boltzmann
model for nonlinear anisotropic convection-diffusion equation (NACDE), and show
that the NACDE can be recovered correctly from the present model through the
Chapman-Enskog analysis. We then test the MRT model through some classic CDEs,
and find that the numerical results are in good agreement with analytical
solutions or some available results. Besides, the numerical results also show
that similar to the single-relaxation-time (SRT) lattice Boltzmann model or
so-called BGK model, the present MRT model also has a second-order convergence
rate in space. Finally, we also perform a comparative study on the accuracy and
stability of the MRT model and BGK model by using two examples. In terms of the
accuracy, both the theoretical analysis and numerical results show that a
\emph{numerical} slip on the boundary would be caused in the BGK model, and
cannot be eliminated unless the relaxation parameter is fixed to be a special
value, while the \emph{numerical} slip in the MRT model can be overcome once
the relaxation parameters satisfy some constrains. The results in terms of
stability also demonstrate that the MRT model could be more stable than the BGK
model through tuning the free relaxation parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09580</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09580</id><created>2015-09-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Rui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Shaofeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Xiaozhi</forenames></author></authors><title>Charge transfer of edge states in zigzag silicene nanoribbons with
  Stone-Wales defects</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 Pages, 9 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Stone-Wales (SW) defects are favorably existed in graphenelike materials with
honeycomb lattice structure and potentially employed to change the electronic
properties in band engineering. In this paper, we investigate structural and
electronic properties of SW defects in bulk silicene and its nanoribbons as a
function of their concentration using the methods of periodic boundary
conditions with first-principles calculations. We first calculate the formation
energy, structural properties, and electronic band structures of SW defects in
bulk silicene, with dependence on the concentration of SW defects. Our results
show a good agreement with available values from the previous first-principles
calculations. The energetics, structural aspects, and electronic properties of
SW defects with dependence on defect concentration and location in
edge-hydrogenated zigzag silicene nanoribbons are obtained. For all calculated
concentrations, the SW defects prefer to locate at the edge due to the lower
formation energy. The SW defects at the center of silicene nanoribbons slightly
influence on the electronic properties, whereas the SW defects at the edge of
silicene nanoribbons split the degenerate edge states and induce a sizable gap,
which depends on the concentration of defects. It is worth to find that the SW
defects produce a perturbation repulsive potential, which leads the decomposed
charge of edge states at the side with defect to transfer to the other side
without defect.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09583</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09583</id><created>2016-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Holten</keyname><forenames>Vincent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hrub&#xfd;</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Dongen</keyname><forenames>M. E. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smeulders</keyname><forenames>D. M. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Comment on &quot;Unraveling the 'Pressure Effect' in Nucleation&quot;</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>2 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a 2008 Letter, Wedekind et al. discussed the influence of an inert carrier
gas on the vapor-liquid nucleation rate. They found an additional
&quot;pressure-volume work&quot; that is performed against the carrier gas, and also
quantified the nonisothermal effects arising from the carrier gas. We argue
that the pressure-volume work term represents the influence of the carrier gas
on phase equilibrium itself. This term will not appear explicitly when a
definition of the supersaturation is used that is appropriate for high-pressure
nucleation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09590</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09590</id><created>2016-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Perri</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salafia</keyname><forenames>Om S.</forenames></author></authors><title>An unexpected new explanation of seasonality in suicide attempts: Grey's
  Anatomy broadcasting</title><categories>physics.pop-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Seasonality is one of the oldest and most elucidation-resistant issues in
suicide epidemiological research. Despite winter depression (also known as
Seasonal Affective Disorder, SAD) is known and treated since many years,
worldwide cross-sectional data from 28 countries show a lower frequency of
suicide attempts around the equinoxes and a higher frequency in spring (both in
Northern and Southern Hemisphere). This peak is not compatible with the SAD
explanation. However, in recent years epidemiological research has yielded new
results, which provide new perspectives on the matter. In fact, the discovery
of a new pathology called Post-Series Depression (PSD) could provide an
explanation of the suicide attempts pattern. The aim of this study is to
analyse weekly data in order to compare them with the TV series broadcasting.
Since medical observations in our sample are distributed over many years, in
order to compare them as best as we can with the television programming, Grey's
Anatomy series was chosen. This medical drama has been in the top 10 of most
viewed TV series since 12 years and it is broadcast all over the world, so that
it can be considered a universal and homogeneous phenomenon. A full season of
the series is split into two separate units with a hiatus around the end of the
calendar year, and it runs from September through May. Data analysis was made
in order to prove the correlation between PSD and the increase of suicide
attempts. Surprisingly, the data analysis shows that the increase of rate of
suicide attempts does not coincide with the breaks in Grey's Anatomy
scheduling, but with the series broadcasting. This therefore suggests that it
is the series itself to increase the viewer's depression.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09602</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09602</id><created>2016-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>I.</keyname><forenames>Gabriel D&#xed;az</forenames></author><author><keyname>Livorati</keyname><forenames>Andr&#xe9; L. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leonel</keyname><forenames>Edson D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistical investigation and thermal properties for a 1-D impact system
  with dissipation</title><categories>nlin.CD</categories><comments>To appear in Physics Letters A (2016)</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physleta.2016.03.032</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The behavior of the average velocity, its deviation and average squared
velocity are characterized using three techniques for a 1-D dissipative impact
system. The system -- a particle, or an ensemble of non interacting particles,
moving in a constant gravitation field and colliding with a varying platform --
is described by a nonlinear mapping. The average squared velocity allows to
describe the temperature for an ensemble of particles as a function of the
parameters using: (i) straightforward numerical simulations; (ii) analytically
from the dynamical equations; (iii) using the probability distribution
function. Comparing analytical and numerical results for the three techniques,
one can check the robustness of the developed formalism, where we are able to
estimate numerical values for the statistical variables, without doing
extensive numerical simulations. Also, extension to other dynamical systems is
immediate, including time dependent billiards.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09608</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09608</id><created>2016-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Tran</keyname><forenames>Toan Trong</forenames></author><author><keyname>ElBadawi</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author><author><keyname>Totonjian</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lobo</keyname><forenames>Charlene J</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grosso</keyname><forenames>Gabriele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moon</keyname><forenames>Hyowon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Englund</keyname><forenames>Dirk R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ford</keyname><forenames>Michael J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aharonovich</keyname><forenames>Igor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toth</keyname><forenames>Milos</forenames></author></authors><title>Robust multicolor single photon emission from point defects in hexagonal
  boron nitride</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.optics quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hexagonal boron nitride (hBN) is an emerging two dimensional material for
quantum photonics owing to its large bandgap and hyperbolic properties. Here we
report a broad range of multicolor room temperature single photon emissions
across the visible and the near infrared spectral ranges from point defects in
hBN multilayers. We show that the emitters can be categorized into two general
groups, but most likely possess similar crystallographic structure. We further
show two approaches for engineering of the emitters using either electron beam
irradiation or annealing, and characterize their photophysical properties. The
emitters exhibit narrow line widths of sub 10 nm at room temperature, and a
short excited state lifetime with high brightness. Remarkably, the emitters are
extremely robust and withstand aggressive annealing treatments in oxidizing and
reducing environments. Our results constitute the first step towards
deterministic engineering of single emitters in 2D materials and hold great
promise for the use of defects in boron nitride as sources for quantum
information processing and nanophotonics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09615</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09615</id><created>2016-03-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Berezowski</keyname><forenames>Marek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fudala</keyname><forenames>Ewa</forenames></author></authors><title>Bifurcation analysis of the statics and dynamics of a logistic model
  with two delays</title><categories>nlin.CD math.DS</categories><comments>17 pages, 8 figures, published in the Chaos, Solitons &amp; Fractals,
  Vol. 28, Issue 2, April 2006</comments><journal-ref>Chaos, Solitons &amp; Fractals, Vol. 28, Issue 2, 2006</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.chaos.2005.08.002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The mathematical - numerical analysis of a discrete dynamical model with two
independent delays was performed. Such model may describe a continuous system
with delays that have real rational number values. Applicable characteristic
equations were derived for both a single and double cycle. The results of the
analysis were illustrated by numerical examples in the form of boundary
bifurcation curves and Feigenbaums diagrams.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09618</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09618</id><created>2016-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Alexandrakis</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kechrakos</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moutis</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niarchos</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hadjipanayis</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panagiotopoulos</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Coercivity and random interfacial exchange coupling in CoPt/Co films</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Appl. Phys. 119, 123905 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4945027</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hard-soft bilayers are analogous to prototype exchange-biased ferromagnetic
-antiferromagnetic systems as the minor loop of the soft layer is biased by the
hard and furthermore they offer bias layer tunability. In sputtered CoPt/Co
hard-soft bilayers we demonstrate that the exchange bias field shows a linear
dependence on the hard layer magnetization, while the coercivity shows a
quadratic dependence. Analysis of the minor hysteresis loop features supported
by Monte-Carlo simulations provide clear evidence that the coercivity of the
soft layer is mainly determined by the tunable randomness of the domain state
of the hard layer.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09626</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09626</id><created>2016-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Collini</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author></authors><title>Fedosov Quantization and Perturbative Quantum Field Theory</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>This is a preprint (with minor modifications) of my doctoral thesis,
  which is being submitted to Fakult\&quot;at f\&quot;ur Physik und Geowissenschaften -
  Universit\&quot;at Leipzig. 169 pages, 3 figures, 2 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Fedosov has described a geometro-algebraic method to construct in a canonical
way a deformation of the Poisson algebra associated with a finite-dimensional
symplectic manifold (&quot;phase space&quot;). His algorithm gives a non-commutative, but
associative, product (a so-called &quot;star-product&quot;) between smooth phase space
functions parameterized by Planck's constant $\hbar$, which is treated as a
deformation parameter. In the limit as $\hbar$ goes to zero, the star product
commutator goes to $\hbar$ times the Poisson bracket, so in this sense his
method provides a quantization of the algebra of classical observables. In this
work, we develop a generalization of Fedosov's method which applies to the
infinite-dimensional symplectic &quot;manifolds&quot; that occur in Lagrangian field
theories. We show that the procedure remains mathematically well-defined, and
we explain the relationship of this method to more standard perturbative
quantization schemes in quantum field theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09640</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09640</id><created>2016-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Sabyasachi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fontoura</keyname><forenames>Carlos E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krein</keyname><forenames>Gast&#xe3;o</forenames></author></authors><title>Mesonic Decay of Charm Hypernuclei $\Lambda^+_c$</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph nucl-ex</categories><comments>Conference name : 21st International Conference on Few-Body Problems
  in Physics (Chicago, Illinois, USA, from May 18th to 22nd, 2015), Conference
  Link : http://www.phy.ohiou.edu/~fewbody/FB21Files/generalinfo.html ;
  Proceeding Link :
  http://www.epj-conferences.org/articles/epjconf/abs/2016/08/epjconf_fb2016_05016/epjconf_fb2016_05016.html</comments><journal-ref>EPJ Web of Conferences 113, 05016 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201611305016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  $\Lambda^+_c$ hypernuclei are expected to have binding energies and other
properties similar to those of strange hypernuclei in view of the similarity
between the quark structures of the strange and charmed hyperons, namely
$\Lambda(uds)$ and $\Lambda^+_c (udc)$. One striking difference however occurs
in their mesonic decays, as there is almost no Pauli blocking in the nucleonic
decay of a charm hypernucleus because the final-state nucleons leave the
nucleus at high energies. The nuclear medium nevertheless affects the mesonic
decays of charm hypernucleus because the nuclear mean fields modify the masses
of the charm hyperon. In the present communication we present results of a
first investigation of the effects of finite baryon density on different weak
mesonic decay channels of the $\Lambda^+_c$ baryon. We found a non-negligible
reduction of the decay widths as compared to their vacuum values.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09657</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09657</id><created>2016-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Stockmeyer</keyname><forenames>Edgardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vugalter</keyname><forenames>Semjon</forenames></author></authors><title>Infinite mass boundary conditions for Dirac operators</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>19 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a self-adjoint realization of a massless Dirac operator on a bounded
connected domain $\Omega\subset \mathbb{R}^2$ which is frequently used to model
graphene quantum dots. In particular, we show that this operator is the limit,
as $M\to \infty$, of a Dirac operator defined on the whole plane, with a mass
term of size $M$ supported outside $\Omega$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09658</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09658</id><created>2016-02-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Bagarello</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author></authors><title>An improved model of alliances between political parties</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>Accepted for the Proceedings of the Conference WASCOM 2015</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider an operatorial model of alliances between three political parties
which interact with their electors, with the undecided voters, and with the
electors of the other parties. This extends what was done in a previous paper,
where this last type of interactions was not considered. Of course, taking them
into account makes the system closer to real life. To produce an exactly
solvable model, we restrict here to quadratic Hamiltonians, so that the
equations of motion turn out to be linear. The dynamics of the so-called {\em
decision functions} are deduced, and some explicit situations are considered in
details.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09659</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09659</id><created>2016-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Stankevich</keyname><forenames>Nataliya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuznetsov</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>Synchronization of coupled generators of quasiperiodic oscillations</title><categories>nlin.CD</categories><comments>6 pages, 9 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dynamics of two coupled generators of quasiperiodic oscillations is
studied. The opportunity of complete and phase synchronization of generators in
the regime of quasiperiodic oscillations is obtained. The features of structure
of parameter plane is researched using charts of dynamical regimes and charts
of Lyapunov exponents, in which typical structures as resonance Arnold web were
revealed. The possible quasiperiodic bifurctions in the system are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09667</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09667</id><created>2016-03-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Tawfik</keyname><forenames>Abdel Nasser</forenames><affiliation>Egyptian Ctr. Theor. Phys., Cairo, WLCAPP, Cairo</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Diab</keyname><forenames>Abdel Magied</forenames><affiliation>Egyptian Ctr. Theor. Phys., Cairo, WLCAPP, Cairo</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dahab</keyname><forenames>Eiman Abou El</forenames><affiliation>WLCAPP, Cairo and MTI U., Cairo</affiliation></author></authors><title>Friedmann inflation in Horava-Lifshitz gravity with a scalar field</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>16 pages, 7 figures</comments><report-no>ECTP-2015-07, WLCAPP-2015-07</report-no><journal-ref>Int. J. Mod. Phys. A 31, No. 9 (2016) 1650042</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X16500421</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study Friedmann inflation in general Horava-Lifshitz (HL) gravity with
detailed and non-detailed but also without the projectability conditions.
Accordingly, we derive the modifications in the Friedmann equations due to
single scalar field potentials describing power-law and
minimal-supersymmetrically extended inflation. By implementing four types of
the equations-of-state charactering the cosmic background geometry, the
dependence of the tensorial and spectral density fluctuations and their ratio
on the inflation field is determined. The latter characterizes the time
evolution of the inflation field relative to the Hubble parameter. Furthermore,
the ratio of tensorial-to-spectral density fluctuations is calculated in
dependence on the spectral index. The resulting slow-roll parameters apparently
differ from the ones deduced from the standard General Relativity (Friedmann
gravity). We also observe that the tensorial-to-spectral density fluctuations
continuously decrease when moving from non-detailed HL gravity, to Friedmann
gravity, to HL gravity without the projectibility, and to detailed HL gravity.
This regular patter is valid for three types of cosmic equations-of-state and
different inflation potential models. The results fit well with the recent
PLANCK observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09668</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09668</id><created>2016-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Noble</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jentschura</keyname><forenames>U. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dirac Hamiltonian and Reissner-Nordstrom Metric: Coulomb Interaction in
  Curved Space-Time</title><categories>gr-qc physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>11 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev.A 93 (2016) 032108</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.032108</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the spin-1/2 relativistic quantum dynamics in the curved
space-time generated by a central massive charged object (black hole). This
necessitates a study of the coupling of a Dirac particle to the
Reissner-Nordstrom space-time geometry and the simultaneous covariant coupling
to the central electrostatic field. The relativistic Dirac Hamiltonian for the
Reissner-Nordstrom geometry is derived. A Foldy-Wouthuysen transformation
reveals the presence of gravitational, and electro-gravitational spin-orbit
coupling terms which generalize the Fokker precession terms found for the
Dirac-Schwarzschild Hamiltonian, and other electro-gravitational correction
terms to the potential proportional to alpha^n G, where alpha is the
fine-structure constant, and G is the gravitational coupling constant. The
particle-antiparticle symmetry found for the Dirac-Schwarzschild geometry (and
for other geometries which do not include electromagnetic interactions) is
shown to be explicitly broken due to the electrostatic coupling. The resulting
spectrum of radially symmetric, electrostatically bound systems (with
gravitational corrections) is evaluated for example cases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09671</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09671</id><created>2016-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Craig</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Parampreet</forenames></author></authors><title>The Vertex Expansion in the Consistent Histories Formulation of Spin
  Foam Loop Quantum Cosmology</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>6 pages. To appear in Proceedings of the Fourteenth Marcel Grossman
  Meeting on General Relativity</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Assignment of consistent quantum probabilities to events in a quantum
universe is a fundamental challenge which every quantum cosmology/gravity
framework must overcome. In loop quantum cosmology, this issue leads to a
fundamental question: What is the probability that the universe undergoes a
non-singular bounce? Using the consistent histories formulation, this question
was successfully answered recently by the authors for a spatially flat FRW
model in the canonical approach. In this manuscript, we obtain a covariant
generalization of this result. Our analysis is based on expressing loop quantum
cosmology in the spin foam paradigm and using histories defined via volume
transitions to compute the amplitudes of transitions obtained using a vertex
expansion. We show that the probability for bounce turns out to be unity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09674</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09674</id><created>2016-03-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Ciufolini</keyname><forenames>Ignazio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paolozzi</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pavlis</keyname><forenames>Erricos C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koenig</keyname><forenames>Rolf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ries</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gurzadyan</keyname><forenames>Vahe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matzner</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Penrose</keyname><forenames>Roger</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sindoni</keyname><forenames>Giampiero</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paris</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khachatryan</keyname><forenames>Harutyun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mirzoyan</keyname><forenames>Sergey</forenames></author></authors><title>A Test of General Relativity Using the LARES and LAGEOS Satellites and a
  GRACE Earth's Gravity Model</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>13 pages, 4 figures, published on EPJ C</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2016) 76:120</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-3961-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a test of General Relativity, the measurement of the Earth's
dragging of inertial frames. Our result is obtained using about 3.5 years of
laser-ranged observations of the LARES, LAGEOS and LAGEOS 2 laser-ranged
satellites together with the Earth's gravity field model GGM05S produced by the
space geodesy mission GRACE. We measure $\mu = (0.994 \pm 0.002) \pm 0.05$,
where $\mu$ is the Earth's dragging of inertial frames normalized to its
General Relativity value, 0.002 is the 1-sigma formal error and 0.05 is the
estimated systematic error mainly due to the uncertainties in the Earth's
gravity model GGM05S. Our result is in agreement with the prediction of General
Relativity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09723</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09723</id><created>2016-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Armstrong</keyname><forenames>Eve</forenames></author></authors><title>Pipe-cleaner Model of Neuronal Network Dynamics</title><categories>physics.pop-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a functional model of neuronal network connectivity in which the
single architectural element is the object commonly known in handicraft circles
as a pipe cleaner. We argue that the dual nature of a neuronal circuit - that
it be at times highly robust to external manipulation and yet sufficiently
flexible to allow for learning and adaptation - is embodied in the pipe
cleaner, and thus that a pipe cleaner framework serves as an instructive
scaffold in which to examine network dynamics. Regarding the dynamics
themselves: as pipe cleaners possess no intrinsic dynamics, in our model we
attribute the emergent circuit dynamics to magic. Magic is a strategy that has
been largely neglected in the neuroscience community, and may serve as an
illuminating comparison to the common physics-based approaches. This model
makes predictions that it would be really awesome to test experimentally.
Moreover, the relative simplicity of the pipe cleaner - setting aside the fact
that it comes in an overwhelming variety of colors - renders it an excellent
theoretical building block with which to create simple network models. Also,
they are incredibly cheap when bought wholesale on Amazon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09733</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09733</id><created>2016-03-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Spaans</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author></authors><title>Stimulated Black Hole Evaporation</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>3 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Black holes are extreme expressions of gravity. Their existence is predicted
by Einstein's theory of general relativity and is supported by observations.
Black holes obey quantum mechanics and evaporate spontaneously. Here it is
shown that a mass rate $R_f\sim 3\times 10^{-8} (M_0/M)^{1/2}$ $M_0$ yr$^{-1}$
onto the horizon of a black hole with mass $M$ (in units of solar mass $M_0$)
stimulates a black hole into rapid evaporation. Specifically, $\sim 3 M_0$
black holes can emit a large fraction of their mass, and explode, in $M/R_f
\sim 3\times 10^7 (M/M_0)^{3/2}$ yr. These stimulated black holes radiate a
spectral line power $P \sim 2\times 10^{39} (M_0/M)^{1/2}$ erg s$^{-1}$, at a
wavelength $\lambda \sim 3\times 10^5 (M/M_0)$ cm. This prediction can be
observationally verified.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09746</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-04-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09746</id><created>2016-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Terrazas</keyname><forenames>Bryan A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bell</keyname><forenames>Eric F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Henriques</keyname><forenames>Bruno M. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>White</keyname><forenames>Simon D. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Diversity of Growth Histories of Milky Way-mass Galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>19 pages, 9 figures, 1 table. Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw673</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use the semi-analytic model developed by Henriques et al. (2015) to
explore the origin of star formation history diversity for galaxies that lie at
the centre of their dark matter haloes and have present-day stellar masses in
the range 5-8 $\times$ 10$^{10}$ M$_{\odot}$, similar to that of the Milky Way.
In this model, quenching is the dominant physical mechanism for introducing
scatter in the growth histories of these galaxies. We find that present-day
quiescent galaxies have a larger variety of growth histories than star-formers
since they underwent 'staggered quenching' - a term describing the correlation
between the time of quenching and present-day halo mass. While halo mass
correlates broadly with quiescence, we find that quiescence is primarily a
function of black hole mass, where galaxies quench when heating from their
active galactic nuclei becomes sufficient to offset the redshift-dependent
cooling rate. In this model, the emergence of a prominent quiescent population
is the main process that flattens the stellar mass-halo mass relation at mass
scales at or above that of the Milky Way.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
