<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T11:13:05Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-06-09" from="2017-06-09" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0712.1299</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0712.1299</id><created>2007-12-08</created><updated>2007-12-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Humpherys</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lyng</keyname><forenames>Gregory</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zumbrun</keyname><forenames>Kevin</forenames></author></authors><title>Stability of strong ideal-gas shock layers</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><doi>10.1007/s00205-008-0195-4</doi><abstract>  Extending recent results in the isentropic case, we use a combination of
asymptotic ODE estimates and numerical Evans-function computations to examine
the spectral stability of shock-wave solutions of the compressible
Navier--Stokes equations with ideal gas equation of state. Our main results are
that, in appropriately rescaled coordinates, the Evans function associated with
the linearized operator about the wave (i) converges in the large-amplitude
limit to the Evans function for a limiting shock profile of the same equations,
for which internal energy vanishes at one endstate; and (ii) has no unstable
(positive real part) zeros outside a uniform ball $|\lambda|\le \Lambda$. Thus,
the rescaled eigenvalue ODE for the set of all shock waves, augmented with the
(nonphysical) limiting case, form a compact family of boundary-value problems
that can be conveniently investigated numerically. An extensive numerical
Evans-function study yields one-dimensional spectral stability, independent of
amplitude, for gas constant $\gamma$ in $[1.2, 3]$ and ratio $\nu/\mu$ of heat
conduction to viscosity coefficient within $[0.2,5]$ ($\gamma\approx 1.4$,
$\nu/\mu\approx 1.47$ for air). Other values may be treated similarly but were
not considered. The method of analysis extends also to the multi-dimensional
case, a direction that we shall pursue in a future work.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.3515</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.3515</id><created>2014-12-10</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liao</keyname><forenames>Shihong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Dalong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chu</keyname><forenames>M. -C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Jiayu</forenames></author></authors><title>Angular momentum - mass relation for dark matter haloes</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>16 pages, 17 figures, matches the version published in The
  Astrophysical Journal</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal 809, 64 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0004-637X/809/1/64</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the empirical relation between an astronomical object's angular
momentum $J$ and mass $M$, $J=\beta M^\alpha$, the $J-M$ relation, using N-body
simulations. In particular, we investigate the time evolution of the $J-M$
relation to study how the initial power spectrum and cosmological model affect
this relation, and to test two popular models of its origin - mechanical
equilibrium and tidal torque theory. We find that in the $\Lambda$CDM model,
$\alpha$ starts with a value of $\sim 1.5$ at high redshift $z$, increases
monotonically, and finally reaches $5/3$ near $z=0$, whereas $\beta$ evolves
linearly with time in the beginning, reaches a maximum and decreases, and
stabilizes finally. A three-regime scheme is proposed to understand this newly
observed picture. We show that the tidal torque theory accounts for this time
evolution behaviour in the linear regime, whereas $\alpha=5/3$ comes from the
virial equilibrium of haloes. The $J-M$ relation in the linear regime contains
the information of the power spectrum and cosmological model. The $J-M$
relations for haloes in different environments and with different merging
histories are also investigated to study the effects of a halo's non-linear
evolution. An updated and more complete understanding of the $J-M$ relation is
thus obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.06423</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.06423</id><created>2015-01-26</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sch&#xe4;ffner</keyname><forenames>Mathias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schl&#xf6;merkemper</keyname><forenames>Anja</forenames></author></authors><title>On Lennard-Jones systems with finite range interactions and their
  asymptotic analysis</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The aim of this work is to provide further insight into the qualitative
behavior of mechanical systems that are well described by Lennard-Jones type
interactions on an atomistic scale. By means of $\Gamma$-convergence
techniques, we study the continuum limit of one-dimensional chains of atoms
with finite range interactions of Lennard-Jones type, including the classical
Lennard-Jones potentials. So far, explicit formulae for the continuum limit
were only available for the case of nearest and next-to-nearest neighbour
interactions. In this work, we provide an explicit expression for the continuum
limit in the case of finite range interactions. The obtained homogenization
formula is given by the convexification of a Cauchy-Born energy density.
  Furthermore, we study suitably rescaled energies in which bulk and surface
contributions scale in the same way. The related discrete-to-continuum limit
yields a rigorous derivation of a one-dimensional version of Griffith' fracture
energy and thus generalizes earlier derivations for nearest and next-to-nearest
neighbors to the case of finite range interactions.
  A crucial ingredient to our proofs is a novel decomposition of the energy
that allows for refined estimates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.03054</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.03054</id><created>2015-01-19</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Changbiao</forenames></author></authors><title>Is the Abraham electromagnetic force physical?</title><categories>physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>Journal version. 3 pages, 12 references</comments><msc-class>83, 78A25</msc-class><journal-ref>Optik 127 (2016) 2887-2889</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ijleo.2015.12.016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A conventional general electromagnetic force definition has been widely used
to analyze radiation forces in dielectric media in published research works.
However in this paper, we would like to indicate that this conventional force
definition is flawed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.00254</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.00254</id><created>2015-03-01</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hobrecht</keyname><forenames>Hendrik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hucht</keyname><forenames>Alfred</forenames></author></authors><title>Many-body critical Casimir interactions in colloidal suspensions</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech hep-lat</categories><comments>13 pages, 9 figures, accepted</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 92, 042315 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.92.042315</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the fluctuation-induced Casimir interactions in colloidal
suspensions, especially between colloids immersed in a binary liquid close to
its critical demixing point. To simulate these systems, we present a highly
efficient cluster Monte Carlo algorithm based on geometric symmetries of the
Hamiltonian. Utilizing the principle of universality, the medium is represented
by an Ising system while the colloids are areas of spins with fixed
orientation. Our results for the Casimir interaction potential between two
particles at the critical point in two dimensions perfectly agree with the
exact predictions. However, we find that in finite systems the behavior
strongly depends on whether the $Z_{2}$ symmetry of the system is broken by the
particles. Eventually we present Monte Carlo results for the three-body Casimir
interaction potential and take a close look onto the case of one particle in
the vicinity of two adjacent particles, which can be calculated from the
two-particle interaction by a conformal mapping. These results emphasize the
failure of the common decomposition approach for many-particle critical Casimir
interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.08282</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.08282</id><created>2015-03-28</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ge</keyname><forenames>Jianlei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Rui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Tianru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>Yuyuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fei</keyname><forenames>Fucong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Shuai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bai</keyname><forenames>Zhanbin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Liling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xuefeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xinran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Fengqi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>You</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Baigeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Guanghou</forenames></author></authors><title>Mimicing the Kane-Mele type spin orbit interaction by spin-flexual
  phonon coupling in graphene devices</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  On the efforts of enhancing the spin orbit interaction (SOI) of graphene for
seeking the dissipationless quantum spin Hall devices, unique Kane-Mele type
SOI and high mobility samples are desired. However, common external decoration
often introduces extrinsic Rashba-type SOI and simultaneous impurity
scattering. Here we show, by the EDTA-Dy molecule dressing, the Kane-Mele type
SOI is mimicked with even improved carrier mobility. It is evidenced by the
suppressed weak localization at equal carrier densities and simultaneous
Elliot-Yafet spin relaxation. The extracted spin scattering time is
monotonically dependent on the carrier elastic scattering time, where the
Elliot-Yafet plot gives the interaction strength of 3.3 meV. Improved quantum
Hall plateaus can be even seen after the external operation. This is attributed
to the spin-flexural phonon coupling induced by the enhanced graphene ripples,
as revealed by the in-plane magnetotransport measurement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.07071</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.07071</id><created>2015-09-23</created><updated>2015-11-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Wei-Kuo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dey</keyname><forenames>Partha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panchenko</keyname><forenames>Dmitry</forenames></author></authors><title>Fluctuations of the free energy in the mixed $p$-spin models with
  external field</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Version 2: 12 pages, new co-author, new title and new results</comments><msc-class>60K35, 82B44</msc-class><journal-ref>Probab. Theory Related Fields 168, no. 1-2, 41-53 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the free energy in the mixed $p$-spin models of spin glasses
does not superconcentrate in the presence of external field, which means that
its variance is of the order suggested by the Poincar\'e inequality. This
complements the result of Chatterjee who showed that the free energy
superconcentrates when there is no external field. For models without odd
$p$-spin interactions for $p\geq 3$, we prove the central limit theorem for the
free energy at any temperature and give an explicit formula for the limiting
variance. Although we only deal with the case of Ising spins, all our results
can be extended to the spherical models as well.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.00905</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.00905</id><created>2015-12-02</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kuusela</keyname><forenames>Mikael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stark</keyname><forenames>Philip B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Shape-constrained uncertainty quantification in unfolding steeply
  falling elementary particle spectra</title><categories>stat.AP hep-ex physics.data-an stat.ME</categories><comments>44 pages, 9 figures, to appear in the Annals of Applied Statistics</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The high energy physics unfolding problem is an important statistical inverse
problem in data analysis at the Large Hadron Collider (LHC) at CERN. The goal
of unfolding is to make nonparametric inferences about a particle spectrum from
measurements smeared by the finite resolution of the particle detectors.
Previous unfolding methods use ad hoc discretization and regularization,
resulting in confidence intervals that can have significantly lower coverage
than their nominal level. Instead of regularizing using a roughness penalty or
stopping iterative methods early, we impose physically motivated shape
constraints: positivity, monotonicity, and convexity. We quantify the
uncertainty by constructing a nonparametric confidence set for the true
spectrum, consisting of all those spectra that satisfy the shape constraints
and that predict the observations within an appropriately calibrated level of
fit. Projecting that set produces simultaneous confidence intervals for all
functionals of the spectrum, including averages within bins. The confidence
intervals have guaranteed conservative frequentist finite-sample coverage in
the important and challenging class of unfolding problems for steeply falling
particle spectra. We demonstrate the method using simulations that mimic
unfolding the inclusive jet transverse momentum spectrum at the LHC. The
shape-constrained intervals provide usefully tight conservative inferences,
while the conventional methods suffer from severe undercoverage.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.03805</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.03805</id><created>2015-12-11</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vanasse</keyname><forenames>Jared</forenames></author></authors><title>The Triton Charge Radius to Next-to-next-to-leading order in Pionless
  Effective Field Theory</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>v1: 41 pages, 21 figures; v2: 47 pages, 19 figures; v3: 51 pages 19
  figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 95, 024002 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.95.024002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The triton point charge radius is calculated to next-to-next-to-leading order
(NNLO) in pionless effective field theory ($\mathrm{EFT}(\not{\!\pi})$),
yielding a prediction of $1.14\pm0.19$ fm (leading order), $1.59\pm0.08$ fm
(next-to leading order), and $1.62\pm0.03$ fm (NNLO) in agreement with the
current experimental extraction of $1.5978\pm0.040$ fm [Angeli and Marinova,
At. Data Nucl. Data Tables 99, 69 (2013)]. The error at NNLO is due to cutoff
variation ($\sim$ 1%) within a reasonable range of calculated cutoffs and from
a $\mathrm{EFT}(\not{\!\pi})$ error estimate ($\sim$ 1.5%). In addition new
techniques are introduced to add perturbative corrections to bound and
scattering state calculations for short range effective field theories, but
with a focus on their use in $\mathrm{EFT}(\not{\!\pi})$
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.00158</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.00158</id><created>2016-01-02</created><updated>2016-03-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ercole</keyname><forenames>Loris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marcolongo</keyname><forenames>Aris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Umari</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baroni</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>Gauge invariance of thermal transport coefficients</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Low. Temp. Phys. (2016) 185: 79</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10909-016-1617-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Thermal transport coefficients are independent of the specific microscopic
expression for the energy density and current from which they can be derived
through the Green-Kubo formula. We discuss this independence in terms of a kind
of gauge invariance resulting from energy conservation and extensivity, and
demonstrate it numerically for a Lennard-Jones fluid, where different forms of
the microscopic energy density lead to different time correlation functions for
the heat flux, all of them, however, resulting in the same value for the
thermal conductivity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00449</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00449</id><created>2016-05-02</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Radnell</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schippers</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Staubach</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames></author></authors><title>Quasiconformal Teichmuller theory as an analytical foundation for
  two-dimensional conformal field theory</title><categories>math.CV math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>27 pages. Typos fixed and references updated</comments><msc-class>30F60 (Primary), 30C55, 30C62, 32G15, 46E20, 81T40 (Secondary)</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The functorial mathematical definition of conformal field theory was first
formulated approximately 30 years ago. The underlying geometric category is
based on the moduli space of Riemann surfaces with parametrized boundary
components and the sewing operation. We survey the recent and careful study of
these objects, which has led to significant connections with quasiconformal
Teichmuller theory and geometric function theory.
  In particular we propose that the natural analytic setting for conformal
field theory is the moduli space of Riemann surfaces with so-called
Weil-Petersson class parametrizations. A collection of rigorous analytic
results is advanced here as evidence. This class of parametrizations has the
required regularity for CFT on one hand, and on the other hand are natural and
of interest in their own right in geometric function theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06824</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06824</id><created>2016-05-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>J. -Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yi</keyname><forenames>C. -J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lv</keyname><forenames>B. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Z. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nie</keyname><forenames>S. -M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kong</keyname><forenames>L. -Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Y. -B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richard</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weng</keyname><forenames>H. -M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernevig</keyname><forenames>B. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Y. -G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qian</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental Discovery of the First Nonsymmorphic Topological Insulator
  KHgSb</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>15 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Science Advances 3, e1602415 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1126/sciadv.1602415</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Topological insulators (TIs) host novel states of quantum matter,
distinguished from trivial insulators by the presence of nontrivial conducting
boundary states connecting the valence and conduction bulk bands. Up to date,
all the TIs discovered experimentally rely on the presence of either time
reversal or symmorphic mirror symmetry to protect massless Dirac-like boundary
states. Very recently, it has been theoretically proposed that several
materials are a new type of TIs protected by nonsymmorphic symmetry, where
glide-mirror can protect novel exotic surface fermions with hourglass-shaped
dispersion. However, an experimental confirmation of such new nonsymmorphic TI
(NSTI) is still missing. Using angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy, we
reveal that such hourglass topology exists on the (010) surface of crystalline
KHgSb while the (001) surface has no boundary state, which is fully consistent
with first-principles calculations. We thus experimentally demonstrate that
KHgSb is a NSTI hosting hourglass fermions. By expanding the classification of
topological insulators, this discovery opens a new direction in the research of
nonsymmorphic topological properties of materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03810</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03810</id><created>2016-06-13</created><updated>2017-02-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dey</keyname><forenames>Rukmini</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ganguli</keyname><forenames>Saibal</forenames></author></authors><title>The dimension of the Hilbert Space of Geometic quantization of vortices
  on a Riemann surface</title><categories>math.DG math-ph math.AG math.AT math.MP math.SG</categories><comments>Written in a more reader friendly way</comments><doi>10.1142/S0219887817501444</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article we calculate the dimension of the Hilbert space of Kahler
quantization of the moduli space of vortices on a Riemann surface. This
dimension is given by the holomorphic Euler characteristic of the quantum line
bundle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02657</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02657</id><created>2016-07-09</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kostadinova</keyname><forenames>E G</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liaw</keyname><forenames>C D</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matthews</keyname><forenames>L S</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hyde</keyname><forenames>T W</forenames></author></authors><title>Physical interpretation of the spectral approach to delocalization in
  infinite disordered systems</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>16 pages, 5 figures</comments><report-no>CASPER-16-1</report-no><journal-ref>Materials Research Express 3.12 (2016): 125904</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we introduce the spectral approach to delocalization in
infinite disordered systems and provide a physical interpretation in context of
the classical model of Edwards and Thouless. We argue that spectral analysis is
an important contribution to localization problems since it avoids issues
related to the use of boundary conditions. Applying the method to 2D and 3D
numerical simulations with various amount of disorder W shows that
delocalization occurs for W&lt;=0.6 in 2D and for W&lt;=5 for 3D.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03048</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03048</id><created>2016-07-11</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hogan</keyname><forenames>Craig</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kwon</keyname><forenames>Ohkyung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richardson</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistical Model of Exotic Rotational Correlations in Emergent
  Space-Time</title><categories>gr-qc quant-ph</categories><comments>21 pages, 6 figures. This is an author-created, un-copyedited version
  of an article published in Classical and Quantum Gravity. IOP Publishing Ltd
  is not responsible for any errors or omissions in this version of the
  manuscript or any version derived from it. The Version of Record is available
  online at the DOI link below</comments><report-no>FERMILAB-PUB-16-264-A</report-no><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 34:135006 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6382/aa73c0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A Lorentz invariant statistical model is presented for rotational
fluctuations in the local inertial frame that arise from new quantum degrees of
freedom of space-time. The model assumes invariant classical causal structure,
and a Planck information density in invariant proper time determined by the
world line of an observer. It describes macroscopic spacelike correlations that
appear as observable timelike correlations in phase differences of light
propagating on paths that begin and end on the same world line. The model
allows an exact prediction for the autocorrelation of any interferometer time
signal from the shape of the light paths. Specific examples computed for
configurations that approximate realistic experiments show that the model can
be rigorously tested, allowing a direct experimental probe of Planck scale
degrees of freedom.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08512</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08512</id><created>2016-07-28</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rastegin</keyname><forenames>Alexey E.</forenames></author></authors><title>On entropic uncertainty relations in the presence of a minimal length</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, no figures. With final corrections, it matches the journal
  version</comments><journal-ref>Ann. Phys., Vol. 382, 170-180 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2017.04.014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Entropic uncertainty relations for the position and momentum within the
generalized uncertainty principle are examined. Studies of this principle are
motivated by the existence of a minimal observable length. Then the position
and momentum operators satisfy the modified commutation relation, for which
more than one algebraic representation is known. One of them is described by
auxiliary momentum so that the momentum and coordinate wave functions are
connected by the Fourier transform. However, the probability density functions
of the physically true and auxiliary momenta are different. As the
corresponding entropies differ, known entropic uncertainty relations are
changed. Using differential Shannon entropies, we give a state-dependent
formulation with correction term. State-independent uncertainty relations are
obtained in terms of the R\'{e}nyi entropies and the Tsallis entropies with
binning. Such relations allow one to take into account a finiteness of
measurement resolution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.00719</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.00719</id><created>2016-08-02</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mochizuki</keyname><forenames>Ken</forenames></author><author><keyname>Obuse</keyname><forenames>Hideaki</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects of disorder on non-unitary $\mathcal{PT}$ symmetric quantum
  walks</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Interdisciplinary Information Sciences 23, 95 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.4036/iis.2017.A.12</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  $\mathcal{PT}$ symmetry, namely, a combined parity and time-reversal symmetry
can make non-unitary quantum walks exhibit entirely real eigenenergy. However,
it is known that the concept of $\mathcal{PT}$ symmetry can be generalized and
an arbitrary anti-unitary symmetry has a possibility to substitute
$\mathcal{PT}$ symmetry. The aim of the present work is to seek such
non-unitary quantum walks with generalized $\mathcal{PT}$ symmetry by focusing
on effects of spatially random disorder which breaks $\mathcal{PT}$ symmetry.
We numerically find non-unitary quantum walks whose quasi-energy is entirely
real despite $\mathcal{PT}$ symmetry is broken.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01011</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01011</id><created>2016-08-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>Carl A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Yaoyun</forenames></author></authors><title>Certifying the absence of quantum nonlocality</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Information and Computation, Vol. 17, No. 7&amp;8, pp.
  0595-0610 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum nonlocality is an inherently non-classical feature of quantum
mechanics and manifests itself through violation of Bell inequalities for
nonlocal games. We show that in a fairly general setting, a simple extension of
a nonlocal game can certify instead the absence of quantum nonlocality. Through
contraposition, our result implies that a super-classical performance for such
a game ensures that a player's output is unpredictable to the other player.
Previously such output unpredictability was known with respect to a third
party.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.02514</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.02514</id><created>2016-08-08</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Maslov</keyname><forenames>Dmitrii L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chubukov</keyname><forenames>Andrey V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical response of correlated electron systems</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>as published version</comments><journal-ref>Rep. Prog. Phys. v. 80, 026503 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6633/80/2/026503</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent progress in experimental techniques has made it possible to extract
detailed information on dynamics of carriers in a correlated electron material
from its optical conductivity, $\sigma(\Omega, T)$. This review consists of
three parts, addressing the following three aspects of optical response: 1) the
role of momentum relaxation, 2) $\Omega/T$ scaling of the optical conductivity
of a Fermi-liquid metal, and 3) optical conductivity of non-Fermi-liquid
metals. In the first part (Sec. II), we analyze the interplay between the
contributions to the conductivity from normal and umklapp scattering. In the
second part (Secs. III and IV), we re-visit the Gurzhi formula for the optical
scattering rate, $1/\tau(\Omega,T)\propto\Omega^2+4\pi^2 T^2$, and show that a
factor of $4\pi^2$ is the manifestation of the &quot;first-Matsubara-frequency
rule&quot;, which states that $1/\tau(\Omega,T)$ must vanish upon analytic
continuation to the first boson Matsubara frequency. However, recent
experiments show that the coefficient $b$ in the Gurzhi-like form,
$1/\tau(\Omega,T)\propto\Omega^2+b\pi^2 T^2$, differs significantly from $b=4$
in most of the cases. We suggest that the discrepancy may be due to the
presence of elastic scattering, which decreases the value of $b$ below $4$,
with $b=1$ corresponding to purely elastic scattering. In the third part (Sec.
V), we consider the optical conductivity of metals near quantum phase
transitions to nematic and spin-density-wave (SDW) states. In the last case, we
focus on &quot;composite&quot; scattering processes, which give rise to a
non-Fermi--liquid behavior of the optical conductivity:
$\sigma'(\Omega,T)\propto \Omega^{-1/3}$ at low frequencies and
$\sigma'(\Omega,T)\propto \Omega^{-1}$ at higher frequencies. We also discuss
$\Omega/T$ scaling and show that $\sigma'(\Omega,T)$ in the same model scales
in a non-Fermi-liquid way, as $T^{4/3}\Omega^{-5/3}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03821</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03821</id><created>2016-08-11</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>H&#xf6;mberg</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patacchini</keyname><forenames>F. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakamoto</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zimmer</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>A revisited Johnson-Mehl-Avrami-Kolmogorov model and the evolution of
  grain-size distributions in steel</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>16 pages, 19 figures</comments><doi>10.1093/imamat/hxx012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The classical Johnson-Mehl-Avrami-Kolmogorov approach for nucleation and
growth models of diffusive phase transitions is revisited and applied to model
the growth of ferrite in multiphase steels. For the prediction of mechanical
properties of such steels, a deeper knowledge of the grain structure is
essential. To this end, a Fokker-Planck evolution law for the volume
distribution of ferrite grains is developed and shown to exhibit a log-normally
distributed solution. Numerical parameter studies are given and confirm
expected properties qualitatively. As a preparation for future work on
parameter identification, a strategy is presented for the comparison of volume
distributions with area distributions experimentally gained from polished
micrograph sections.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05568</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05568</id><created>2016-08-19</created><updated>2017-02-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sahu</keyname><forenames>Siddharth S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Siva</keyname><forenames>Vantari</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pradhan</keyname><forenames>Paresh C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nayak</keyname><forenames>Maheswar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Senapati</keyname><forenames>Kartik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sahoo</keyname><forenames>Pratap K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Progressive magnetic softening of ferromagnetic layers in multilayer
  ferromagnet-nonmagnet systems and the role of granularity</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Applied Physics 121, 213905 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4985120</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report a study of the structural and magnetic behavior of the topmost
magnetic layer in a ferromagnet-nonmagnet (Co-Au) multilayer system. Glancing
angle X-ray diffraction measurements performed on a series of multilayers
showed a gradually increasing degree of amorphization of the topmost magnetic
layer with increasing number of bilayers. Concurrently, the magnetic hardness
and magneto-crystalline anisotropy of the top Co layer were found to decrease,
as observed by magneto-optical Kerr effect measurements. This magnetic
softening has been discussed in the light of Herzer's random anisotropy model.
Micromagnetic simulations of the multilayer system also corroborated these
observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05933</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05933</id><created>2016-08-21</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aoki</keyname><forenames>Arata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soda</keyname><forenames>Jiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Detecting ultralight axion dark matter wind with laser interferometers</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure, published version</comments><report-no>KOBE-COSMO-16-10</report-no><journal-ref>Int. J. Mod. Phys. D 26, 1750063 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218271817500638</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ultralight axion with mass around $10^{-22}$ eV is known as a candidate
of dark matter. A peculiar feature of the ultralight axion is oscillating
pressure in time, which produces oscillation of gravitational potentials. Since
the solar system moves through the dark matter halo at the velocity of about $v
\sim 300 \, \text{km} / \text{s} = 10^{-3}$, there exists axion wind, which
looks like scalar gravitational waves for us. Hence, there is a chance to
detect ultralight axion dark matter with a wide mass range by using laser
interferometer detectors. We calculate the detector signal induced by the
oscillating pressure of the ultralight axion field, which would be detected by
future laser interferometer experiments. We also argue that the detector signal
can be enhanced due to the resonance in modified gravity theory explaining the
dark energy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00614</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00614</id><created>2016-09-02</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>de Barros</keyname><forenames>J. Acacio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oas</keyname><forenames>Gary</forenames></author></authors><title>Can we Falsify the Consciousness-Causes-Collapse Hypothesis in Quantum
  Mechanics?</title><categories>quant-ph physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we examine some proposals to disprove the hypothesis that the
interaction between mind and matter causes the collapse of the wave function,
showing that such proposals are fundamentally flawed. We then describe a
general experimental setup retaining the key features of the ones examined, and
show that even a more general case is inadequate to disprove the mind-matter
collapse hypothesis. Finally, we use our setup provided to argue that, under
some reasonable assumptions about consciousness, such hypothesis is
unfalsifiable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.00547</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.00547</id><created>2016-10-03</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sawicki</keyname><forenames>Adam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karnas</keyname><forenames>Katarzyna</forenames></author></authors><title>Criteria for universality of quantum gates</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.GR math.MP</categories><comments>Significantly improved universality criteria and the much simpler
  algorithm that allows deciding universality of an arbitrary set of gates</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 062303 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.062303</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the problem of deciding if a set of quantum one-qudit gates
$\mathcal{S}=\{U_1,\ldots,U_n\}$ is universal. We provide the compact form
criteria leading to a simple algorithm that allows deciding universality of any
given set of gates in a finite number of steps. Moreover, for a non-universal
$\mathcal{S}$ our criteria indicate what type of gates can be added to
$\mathcal{S}$ to turn it into a universal set.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01693</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01693</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Fatemi</keyname><forenames>Fredrik K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoffman</keyname><forenames>Jonathan E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solano</keyname><forenames>Pablo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fenton</keyname><forenames>Eliot F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beadie</keyname><forenames>Guy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rolston</keyname><forenames>Steven L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orozco</keyname><forenames>Luis A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Near-field measurement of modal interference in optical nanofibers for
  sub-Angstrom radius sensitivity</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Optica Vol. 4, Issue 1, pp. 157-162 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OPTICA.4.000157</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Optical nanofibers (ONF) of subwavelength dimensions confine light in modes
with a strong evanescent field that can trap, probe, and manipulate nearby
quantum systems. To measure the evanescent field and propagating modes, and to
optimize ONF performance, a surface probe is desirable during fabrication. We
demonstrate a nondestructive measurement of light propagation in ONFs by
sampling the local evanescent field with a microfiber. This approach reveals
the behavior of all propagating modes, and because the modal beat lengths in
cylindrical waveguides depend strongly on radius, simultaneously provides
exquisite sensitivity to the ONF radius. We show that our measured spatial
frequencies provide a map of the average ONF radius (over a 600 micrometer
window) along the 10 mm ONF waist with 40 picometer resolution and high
signal-to-noise ratio. The measurements agree with scanning electron microscopy
(SEM) to within SEM instrument resolution. This fast method is immune to
polarization, intrinsic birefringence, mechanical vibrations, scattered light,
and provides a set of constraints to protect from systematic errors in the
measurements
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05140</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05140</id><created>2016-10-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>Carl A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Yaoyun</forenames></author></authors><title>Certified randomness between mistrustful players</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages. Comments welcome</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Information and Computation, Vol. 17, No. 7&amp;8, pp.
  0595-0610 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is known that if two players achieve a superclassical score at a nonlocal
game $G$, then their outputs are certifiably random - that is, regardless of
the strategy used by the players, a third party will not be able to perfectly
predict their outputs (even if he were given their inputs). We prove that for
any complete-support game $G$, there is an explicit nonzero function $F_G$ such
that if Alice and Bob achieve a superclassical score of $s$ at $G$, then Bob
has a probability of at most $1 - F_G ( s )$ of correctly guessing Alice's
output after the game is played. Our result implies that certifying global
randomness through such games must necessarily introduce local randomness.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.06508</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.06508</id><created>2016-10-20</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bain</keyname><forenames>Reggie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Makris</keyname><forenames>Yiannis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mehen</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Transverse Momentum Dependent Fragmenting Jet Functions with
  Applications to Quarkonium Production</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>25 pages, 7 figures</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP11(2016)144</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce the transverse momentum dependent fragmenting jet function
(TMDFJF), which appears in factorization theorems for cross sections for jets
with an identified hadron. These are functions of $z$, the hadron's
longitudinal momentum fraction, and transverse momentum,
$\boldsymbol{\mathrm{p}}_{\perp}$, relative to the jet axis. In the framework
of Soft-Collinear Effective Theory (SCET) we derive the TMDFJF from both a
factorized SCET cross section and the TMD fragmentation function defined in the
literature. The TMDFJFs are factorized into distinct collinear and
soft-collinear modes by matching onto SCET$_+$. As TMD calculations contain
rapidity divergences, both the renormalization group (RG) and rapidity
renormalization group (RRG) must be used to provide resummed calculations with
next-to-leading-logarithm prime (NLL') accuracy. We apply our formalism to the
production of $J/\psi$ within jets initiated by gluons. In this case the TMDFJF
can be calculated in terms of NRQCD (Non-relativistic quantum chromodynamics)
fragmentation functions. We find that when the $J/\psi$ carries a significant
fraction of the jet energy, the $p_T$ and $z$ distributions differ for
different NRQCD production mechanisms. Another observable with discriminating
power is the average angle that the $J/\psi$ makes with the jet axis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.00713</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.00713</id><created>2016-11-02</created><updated>2017-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jusufi</keyname><forenames>Kimet</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Effects on the Deflection of Light and the Gauss-Bonnet Theorem</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in International Journal of Geometric
  Methods in Modern Physics</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Geom. Methods Mod. Phys. 14, 1750137 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0219887817501377</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this letter we apply the Gauss--Bonnet theorem (GB) to calculate the
deflection angle by a quantum corrected Schwarzschild black hole in the weak
limit approximation. In particular we calculate the light deflection by two
types of quantum corrected black holes: the renormalization group improved
Schwarzschild solution and the quantum corrected Schwarzschild solution in
Bohmian quantum mechanics. We start from the corresponding optical metrics to
use then the GB theorem and calculate the Gaussian curvature in both cases. We
calculate the leading terms of the deflection angle and show that quantum
corrections modifies the deflection angle in both solutions. Finally by
performing geodesics calculations we show that GB method gives exact results in
leading order terms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.00877</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.00877</id><created>2016-11-03</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cuzinatto</keyname><forenames>R. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Morais</keyname><forenames>E. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Medeiros</keyname><forenames>L. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Souza</keyname><forenames>C. Naldoni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pimentel</keyname><forenames>B. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>de Broglie-Proca and Bopp-Podolsky massive photon gases in cosmology</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures; v2 matches the published version</comments><journal-ref>EPL, 118 (2017) 19001</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/118/19001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the influence of massive photons on the evolution of the
expanding universe. Two particular models for generalized electrodynamics are
considered, namely de Broglie-Proca and Bopp-Podolsky electrodynamics. We
obtain the equation of state (EOS) $P=P(\varepsilon)$ for each case using
dispersion relations derived from both theories. The EOS are inputted into the
Friedmann equations of a homogeneous and isotropic space-time to determine the
cosmic scale factor $a(t)$. It is shown that the photon non-null mass does not
significantly alter the result $a\propto t^{1/2}$ valid for a massless photon
gas; this is true either in de Broglie-Proca's case (where the photon mass $m$
is extremely small) or in Bopp-Podolsky theory (for which $m$ is extremely
large).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03140</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03140</id><created>2016-11-09</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alekseechkin</keyname><forenames>Nikolay V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Surface effects in nucleation</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>53 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The classical nucleation theory (CNT) concept of a nucleus as a fragment of
the bulk new phase fails for nanosized nuclei. An extension of CNT taking into
account the properties of the transition region between coexisting bulk phases
is proposed. For this purpose, the finite-thickness layer method which is an
alternative to Gibbs one is used; the transition region is considered as a
separate (surface) phase. An equation for the nucleation work is derived which
is basic for the multivariable theory of nucleation. Equations of equilibrium
following from it are employed for considering the dependences of surface
tension on radius and temperature for droplets; Kelvin formula for the
equilibrium vapor pressure is extended to small radii. It is shown that the
ratio of the isothermal nucleation rate to that of CNT can achieve several
orders of magnitude due to the curvature effect (the dependence of surface
tension on curvature). The analysis of different dependences of the Tolman
length on radius, d(R), suggests that (i) the curvature effect is determined by
the value of d(0) which is positive and relates to the limiting (spinodal)
vapor supersaturation and (ii) the function d(R) decreases with increasing
radius; at the same time, this effect is weakly sensitive to the form of the
function d(R) and its asymptotic value. The second differential of the work is
obtained as a quadratic form with contributions from both the bulk and surface
phases. It is used for calculating the fluctuations of surface layer parameters
such as the surface tension and the specific surface area as well as the
fluctuations of nucleus parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.04287</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.04287</id><created>2016-11-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Wenchao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Yongsong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Pengfei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Haibin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Yao</forenames></author></authors><title>Energetic disorder induced leakage current in organic bulk
  heterojunction solar cells: comprehending the ultra-high open circuit voltage
  loss at low temperatures</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Applied 7, 044017 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevApplied.7.044017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In organic bulk heterojunction solar cells, the open circuit voltage
($V_\mathrm{oc}$) suffers from an ultra-high loss at low temperatures. In this
work we investigate the origin of the loss through calculating the
$V_\mathrm{oc}-T$ plots with the device model method systematically and
comparing it with experimentally observed ones. When the energetic disorder is
incorporated into the model by considering the disorder-suppressed and
temperature-dependent charge carrier mobilities, it is found that for
nonselective contacts the $V_\mathrm{oc}$ reduces drastically under the low
temperature regime, while for selective contacts the $V_\mathrm{oc}$ keeps
increasing with the decreasing temperature. The main reason is revealed that as
the temperature decreases, the reduced mobilities give rise to low charge
extraction efficiency and small bimolecular recombination rate for the
photogenerated charge carriers, so that in the former case they can be
extracted from the wrong electrode to form a leakage current which counteracts
the photocurrent and increases quickly with voltage, leading to the anomalous
reduction of $V_\mathrm{oc}$. In addition, it is revealed that the charge
generation rate is slow-varying with temperature and does not induce
significant $V_\mathrm{oc}$ loss. This work also provides a comprehensive
picture for the $V_\mathrm{oc}$ behavior under varying device working
conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00152</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00152</id><created>2016-12-01</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Takeuchi</keyname><forenames>Kazumasa A.</forenames></author></authors><title>$1/f^\alpha$ power spectrum in the Kardar-Parisi-Zhang universality
  class</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech math.PR</categories><comments>19 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A 50, 264006 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa7106</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The power spectrum of interface fluctuations in the $(1+1)$-dimensional
Kardar-Parisi-Zhang (KPZ) universality class is studied both experimentally and
numerically. The $1/f^\alpha$-type spectrum is found and characterized through
a set of &quot;critical exponents&quot; for the power spectrum. The recently formulated
&quot;aging Wiener-Khinchin theorem&quot; accounts for the observed exponents.
Interestingly, the $1/f^\alpha$ spectrum in the KPZ class turns out to contain
information on a universal distribution function characterizing the asymptotic
state of the KPZ interfaces, namely the Baik-Rains universal variance. It is
indeed observed in the presented data, both experimental and numerical, and for
both circular and flat interfaces, in the long time limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03016</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03016</id><created>2016-12-09</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>ATLAS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Precision measurement and interpretation of inclusive $W^+$, $W^-$ and
  $Z/\gamma^*$ production cross sections with the ATLAS detector</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>98 pages in total, author list starting page 82, 32 figures, 29
  tables, published in EPJC, All figures including auxiliary figures are
  available at
  https://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/GROUPS/PHYSICS/PAPERS/STDM-2012-20</comments><report-no>CERN-EP-2016-272</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 77 (2017) 367</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4911-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  High-precision measurements by the ATLAS Collaboration are presented of
inclusive $W^+\to\ell^+\nu$, $W^-\to\ell^-\bar{\nu}$ and
$Z/\gamma^*\to\ell\ell$ ($\ell=e,\mu$) Drell-Yan production cross sections at
the LHC. The data were collected in proton-proton collisions at $\sqrt{s} = 7$
TeV with an integrated luminosity of 4.6 fb$^{-1}$. Differential $W^+$ and
$W^-$ cross sections are measured in a lepton pseudorapidity range
$|\eta_{\ell}| = 2.5$. Differential $Z/\gamma^*$ cross sections are measured as
a function of the absolute dilepton rapidity, for $|y_{\ell\ell}| &lt; 3.6$, for
three intervals of dilepton mass, $m_{\ell\ell}$, extending from 46 to 150 GeV.
The integrated and differential electron- and muon-channel cross sections are
combined and compared to theoretical predictions using recent sets of parton
distribution functions. The data, together with the final inclusive $e^{\pm}p$
scattering cross-section data from H1 and ZEUS, are interpreted in a
next-to-next-to-leading-order QCD analysis, and a new set of parton
distribution functions, ATLAS-epWZ16, is obtained. The ratio of
strange-to-light sea-quark densities in the proton is determined more
accurately than in previous determinations based on collider data only, and is
established to be close to unity in the sensitivity range of the data. A new
measurement of the CKM matrix element $|V_{cs}|$ is also provided.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04092</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04092</id><created>2016-12-13</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Grechnev</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames><affiliation>Institute of Solar-Terrestrial Physics SB RAS, Irkutsk, Russia</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kiselev</keyname><forenames>V. I.</forenames><affiliation>Institute of Solar-Terrestrial Physics SB RAS, Irkutsk, Russia</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Uralov</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames><affiliation>Institute of Solar-Terrestrial Physics SB RAS, Irkutsk, Russia</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Klein</keyname><forenames>K. -L.</forenames><affiliation>Observatoire de Paris, Univ. Paris, Observatoire de Meudon, Meudon, France</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kochanov</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames><affiliation>Institute of Solar-Terrestrial Physics SB RAS, Irkutsk, Russia</affiliation></author></authors><title>The 26 December 2001 Solar Eruptive Event Responsible for GLE63. III.
  CME, Shock Waves, and Energetic Particles</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>40 pages, 18 figures. For associated movie file, see
  http://ssrt.iszf.irk.ru/~grechnev/papers/2001-12-26_3_eruptions/ Accepted for
  publication in Solar Physics. The final publication is available at Springer
  via http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11207-017-1122-3</comments><doi>10.1007/s11207-017-1122-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The SOL2001-12-26 moderate solar eruptive event (GOES importance M7.1,
microwaves up to 4000 sfu at 9.4 GHz, CME speed 1446 km/s) produced strong
fluxes of solar energetic particles and ground-level enhancement of cosmic-ray
intensity (GLE63). To find a possible reason for the atypically high proton
outcome of this event, we study multi-wavelength images and dynamic radio
spectra and quantitatively reconcile the findings with each other. An
additional eruption probably occurred in the same active region about half an
hour before the main eruption. The latter produced two blast-wave-like shocks
during the impulsive phase. The two shock waves eventually merged around the
radial direction into a single shock traced up to $25R_\odot$ as a halo ahead
of the expanding CME body, in agreement with an interplanetary Type II event
recorded by the Radio and Plasma Wave Investigation (WAVES) experiment on the
Wind spacecraft. The shape and kinematics of the halo indicate an intermediate
regime of the shock between the blast wave and bow shock at these distances.
The results show that i) the shock wave appeared during the flare rise and
could accelerate particles earlier than usually assumed; ii) the particle event
could be amplified by the preceding eruption, which stretched closed structures
above the developing CME, facilitated its lift-off and escape of
flare-accelerated particles, enabled a higher CME speed and stronger shock
ahead; iii) escape of flare-accelerated particles could be additionally
facilitated by reconnection of the flux rope, where they were trapped, with a
large coronal hole; iv) the first eruption supplied a rich seed population
accelerated by a trailing shock wave.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.05925</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.05925</id><created>2016-12-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Bozhko</keyname><forenames>Dmytro A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clausen</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melkov</keyname><forenames>Gennadii A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>L'vov</keyname><forenames>Victor S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pomyalov</keyname><forenames>Anna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vasyuchka</keyname><forenames>Vitaliy I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chumak</keyname><forenames>Andrii V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hillebrands</keyname><forenames>Burkard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serga</keyname><forenames>Alexander A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Bottleneck accumulation of hybrid magneto-elastic bosons</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 237201 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.237201</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is known that an ensemble of magnons, quanta of spin waves, can be
prepared as a Bose gas of weakly interacting quasiparticles with conservation
of the particle number. Furthermore, the thermalization of the overpopulated
magnon gas can lead to the formation of a Bose-Einstein condensate at the
bottom of a spin-wave spectrum. However, magnon-phonon scattering processes can
significantly modify this scenario and new quasiparticles are formed -
magneto-elastic bosons. Our observations of a parametrically populated magnon
gas in a single-crystal film of Yttrium Iron Garnet by means of
wavevector-resolved Brillouin light scattering spectroscopy including
magneto-elastic coupling resulted in the discovery of a novel condensation
phenomenon: A spontaneous accumulation of hybrid magneto-elastic bosonic
quasiparticles at the intersection of the lowest magnon mode and a transversal
acoustic wave.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.06436</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.06436</id><created>2016-12-19</created><updated>2017-06-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tindall</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Torres-Rincon</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rose</keyname><forenames>J. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petersen</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Equilibration and freeze-out of an expanding gas in a transport approach
  in a Friedmann-Robertson-Walker metric</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>v2: 9 pages, 7 figures. Added discussion on the numerical relation
  between the Hubble and scattering rates at the end of Sec. 3. Updated
  references. This version matches the accepted manuscript by Phys.Lett.B
  journal</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Lett. B770 (2017) 532-538</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.04.080</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by a recent finding of an exact solution of the relativistic
Boltzmann equation in a Friedmann-Robertson-Walker spacetime, we implement this
metric into the newly developed transport approach Simulating Many Accelerated
Strongly-interacting Hadrons (SMASH). We study the numerical solution of the
transport equation and compare it to this exact solution for massless
particles. We also compare a different initial condition, for which the
transport equation can be independently solved numerically. Very nice agreement
is observed in both cases. Having passed these checks for the SMASH code, we
study a gas of massive particles within the same spacetime, where the particle
decoupling is forced by the Hubble expansion. In this simple scenario we
present an analysis of the freeze-out times, as function of the masses and
cross sections of the particles. The results might be of interest for their
potential application to relativistic heavy-ion collisions, for the
characterization of the freeze-out process in terms of hadron properties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08573</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08573</id><created>2016-12-27</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Zhengwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Feng</forenames></author></authors><title>Jones-Wassermann subfactors for modular tensor categories</title><categories>math.OA math-ph math.MP math.QA</categories><comments>29 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The representation theory of a conformal net is a unitary modular tensor
category. It is captured by the bimodule category of the Jones-Wassermann
subfactor. In this paper, we construct multi-interval Jones-Wassermann
subfactors for unitary modular tensor categories. We prove that these
subfactors are self-dual. It generalizes and categorifies the self-duality of
finite abelian groups and we call it modular self-duality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01633</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01633</id><created>2017-01-06</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Shan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khodjamirian</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Virto</keyname><forenames>Javier</forenames></author></authors><title>$B\to\pi\pi$ Form Factors from Light-Cone Sum Rules with $B$-meson
  Distribution Amplitudes</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>28 pages, 3 figures. A few comments added. Version published in JHEP</comments><report-no>SI-HEP-2016-09, QFET-2016-04, NIOBE-2017-01</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1705 (2017) 157</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP05(2017)157</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study $B\to\pi\pi$ form factors using QCD light-cone sum rules with
$B$-meson distribution amplitudes. These form factors describe the semileptonic
decay $B\to \pi\pi \ell\bar{\nu}_{\ell}$, and constitute an essential input in
$B\to \pi\pi \ell^+\ell^-$ and $B\to \pi\pi\pi$ decays. We employ the
correlation functions where a dipion isospin-one state is interpolated by the
vector light-quark current. We obtain sum rules where convolutions of the
$P$-wave $\bar{B}^0\to \pi^+\pi^0$ form factors with the time-like pion vector
form factor are related to universal $B$-meson distribution amplitudes. These
sum rules are valid in the kinematic regime where the dipion state has a large
energy and a low invariant mass, and reproduce analytically the known
light-cone sum rules for $B\to \rho$ form factors in the limit of
$\rho$-dominance with zero width, thus providing a systematics for
so-far-unaccounted corrections to $B\to\rho$ transitions. Using data for the
pion vector form factor, we estimate finite width-effects and the contribution
of excited $\rho$-resonances to the $B\to\pi\pi$ form factors. We find that
these contributions amount up to $\sim 20\%$ in the small dipion mass region
where they can be effectively regarded as a nonresonant ($P$-wave) background
to the $B\to\rho$ transition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.02763</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.02763</id><created>2017-01-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Hyunseok</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Wook-Jae</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farrell</keyname><forenames>Alan C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Senanayake</keyname><forenames>Pradeep</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huffaker</keyname><forenames>Diana L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Monolithic InGaAs nanowire array lasers on silicon-on-insulator
  operating at room temperature</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.7b00384</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Chip-scale integrated light sources are a crucial component in a broad range
of photonics applications. III-V semiconductor nanowire emitters have gained
attention as a fascinating approach due to their superior material properties,
extremely compact size, and the capability to grow directly on
lattice-mismatched silicon substrates. Although there have been remarkable
advances in nanowire-based emitters, their practical applications are still in
the early stages due to the difficulties in integrating nanowire emitters with
photonic integrated circuits (PICs). Here, we demonstrate for the first time
optically pumped III-V nanowire array lasers monolithically integrated on
silicon-on-insulator (SOI) platform. Selective-area growth of purely
single-crystalline InGaAs/InGaP core/shell nanowires on an SOI substrate
enables the nanowire array to form a photonic crystal nanobeam cavity with
superior optical and structural properties, resulting in the laser to operate
at room temperature. We also show that the nanowire array lasers are
effectively coupled with SOI waveguides by employing nanoepitaxy on a
pre-patterned SOI platform. These results represent a new platform for
ultra-compact and energy-efficient optical links, and unambiguously point the
way toward practical and functional nanowire lasers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05562</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05562</id><created>2017-01-19</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yagi</keyname><forenames>Junya</forenames></author></authors><title>Surface defects and elliptic quantum groups</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP math.QA</categories><comments>31 pages. v2: minor changes and corrections; v3: minor improvements,
  published version</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 06 (2017) 013</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP06(2017)013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A brane construction of an integrable lattice model is proposed. The model is
composed of Belavin's R-matrix, Felder's dynamical R-matrix, the
Bazhanov-Sergeev-Derkachov-Spiridonov R-operator and some intertwining
operators. This construction implies that a family of surface defects act on
supersymmetric indices of four-dimensional $\mathcal{N} = 1$ supersymmetric
field theories as transfer matrices related to elliptic quantum groups.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.06781</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.06781</id><created>2017-01-24</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fernandez-de-Cossio-Diaz</keyname><forenames>Jorge</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Martino</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mulet</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author></authors><title>Microenvironmental cooperation promotes early spread and bistability of
  a Warburg-like phenotype</title><categories>q-bio.MN cond-mat.dis-nn physics.bio-ph q-bio.TO</categories><comments>14 pages</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, 3103 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-03342-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce an in silico model for the initial spread of an aberrant
phenotype with Warburg-like overflow metabolism within a healthy homeostatic
tissue in contact with a nutrient reservoir (the blood), aimed at
characterizing the role of the microenvironment for aberrant growth. Accounting
for cellular metabolic activity, competition for nutrients, spatial diffusion
and their feedbacks on aberrant replication and death rates, we obtain a phase
portrait where distinct asymptotic whole-tissue states are found upon varying
the tissue-blood turnover rate and the level of blood-borne primary nutrient.
Over a broad range of parameters, the spreading dynamics is bistable as random
fluctuations can impact the final state of the tissue. Such a behaviour turns
out to be linked to the re-cycling of overflow products by non-aberrant cells.
Quantitative insight on the overall emerging picture is provided by a spatially
homogeneous version of the model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.08218</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.08218</id><created>2017-01-27</created><updated>2017-05-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lunts</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schlief</keyname><forenames>Andres</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Sung-Sik</forenames></author></authors><title>Emergence of a control parameter for the antiferromagnetic quantum
  critical metal</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>20 pages, 8 figures; ver2: minor corrections, comparison to
  ferromagnetic quantum criticality added, typos fixed, references added</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 245109 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.245109</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the antiferromagnetic quantum critical metal in $3-\epsilon$ space
dimensions by extending the earlier one-loop analysis [Sur and Lee, Phys. Rev.
B 91, 125136 (2015)] to higher-loop orders. We show that the
$\epsilon$-expansion is not organized by the standard loop expansion, and a
two-loop graph becomes as important as one-loop graphs due to an infrared
singularity caused by an emergent quasilocality. This qualitatively changes the
nature of the infrared (IR) fixed point, and the $\epsilon$-expansion is
controlled only after the two-loop effect is taken into account. Furthermore,
we show that a ratio between velocities emerges as a small parameter, which
suppresses a large class of diagrams. We show that the critical exponents do
not receive corrections beyond the linear order in $\epsilon$ in the limit that
the ratio of velocities vanishes. The $\epsilon$-expansion gives critical
exponents which are consistent with the exact solution obtained in $0 &lt;
\epsilon \leq 1$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.00016</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.00016</id><created>2017-01-31</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>D'Eramo</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kavanagh</keyname><forenames>Bradley J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panci</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing Leptophilic Dark Sectors with Hadronic Processes</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO hep-ex</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures, version published in Physics Letters B</comments><report-no>SCIPP 17/01, CERN-TH-2017-016</report-no><journal-ref>Phys.Lett. B771 (2017) 339-348</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.05.063</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study vector portal dark matter models where the mediator couples only to
leptons. In spite of the lack of tree-level couplings to colored states,
radiative effects generate interactions with quark fields that could give rise
to a signal in current and future experiments. We identify such experimental
signatures: scattering of nuclei in dark matter direct detection; resonant
production of lepton-antilepton pairs at the Large Hadron Collider; and
hadronic final states in dark matter indirect searches. Furthermore, radiative
effects also generate an irreducible mass mixing between the vector mediator
and the $Z$ boson, severely bounded by ElectroWeak Precision Tests. We use
current experimental results to put bounds on this class of models, accounting
for both radiatively induced and tree-level processes. Remarkably, the former
often overwhelm the latter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.01768</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.01768</id><created>2017-02-06</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Young</keyname><forenames>Karl</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wen</keyname><forenames>Qi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hanany</keyname><forenames>Shaul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Imada</keyname><forenames>Hiroaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koch</keyname><forenames>J&#xfc;rgen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsumura</keyname><forenames>Tomotake</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suttmann</keyname><forenames>Oliver</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xfc;tz</keyname><forenames>Viktor</forenames></author></authors><title>Broadband Millimeter-Wave Anti-Reflection Coatings on Silicon Using
  Pyramidal Sub-Wavelength Structures</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>12 pages, 16 figures, published in Journal of Applied Physics</comments><doi>10.1063/1.4984892</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We used two novel approaches to produce sub-wavelength structure (SWS)
anti-reflection coatings (ARC) on silicon for the millimeter and sub-millimeter
(MSM) wave band: picosecond laser ablation and dicing with beveled saws. We
produced pyramidal structures with both techniques. The diced sample, machined
on only one side, had pitch and height of 350 $\mu$m and 972 $\mu$m. The two
laser ablated samples had pitch of 180 $\mu$m and heights of 720 $\mu$m and 580
$\mu$m; only one of these samples was ablated on both sides. We present
measurements of shape and optical performance as well as comparisons to the
optical performance predicted using finite element analysis and rigorous
coupled wave analysis. By extending the measured performance of the one-sided
diced sample to the two-sided case, we demonstrate 25 % band averaged
reflectance of less than 5 % over a bandwidth of 97 % centered on 170 GHz.
Using the two-sided laser ablation sample, we demonstrate reflectance less than
5 % over 83 % bandwidth centered on 346 GHz.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02532</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02532</id><created>2017-02-08</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Costagliola</keyname><forenames>Gianluca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bosia</keyname><forenames>Federico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pugno</keyname><forenames>Nicola M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Tuning friction with composite hierarchical surfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>16 pages, 8 figures</comments><doi>10.1016/j.triboint.2017.05.012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Macroscopic friction coefficients observed in experiments are the result of
various types of complex multiscale interactions between sliding surfaces.
Therefore, there are several ways to modify them depending on the physical
phenomena involved. Recently, it has been demonstrated that surface structure,
e.g. artificial patterning, can be used to tune frictional properties. In this
paper, we show how the global friction coefficients can also be manipulated
using composite surfaces with varying roughness or stiffness values, i.e. by
combining geometrical features with the modification of local friction
coefficients or stiffnesses. We show that a remarkable reduction of static
friction can be achieved by introducing hierarchical arrangements of varying
local roughness values, or by introducing controlled material stiffness
variations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.03933</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.03933</id><created>2017-02-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Law-Smith</keyname><forenames>Jamie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eisenstein</keyname><forenames>Daniel J.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Color and Stellar Mass Dependence of Small-scale Galaxy Clustering
  in SDSS-III BOSS</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures, 3 tables. Published in ApJ</comments><journal-ref>ApJ 836, 87 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/836/1/87</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We measure the color and stellar mass dependence of clustering in
spectroscopic galaxies at $0.6 &lt; z &lt; 0.65$ using data from the Baryon
Oscillation Spectroscopic Survey component of the Sloan Digital Sky Survey. We
greatly increase the statistical precision of our clustering measurements by
using the cross-correlation of 66,657 spectroscopic galaxies to a sample of 6.6
million fainter photometric galaxies. The clustering amplitude $w(R)$ is
measured as the ratio of the mean excess number of photometric galaxies found
within a specified radius annulus around a spectroscopic galaxy to that from a
random photometric galaxy distribution. We recover many of the familiar trends
at high signal-to-noise ratio. We find the ratio of the clustering amplitudes
of red and blue massive galaxies to be $w_\text{red}/w_\text{blue} = 1.92 \pm
0.11$ in our smallest annulus of 75-125 kpc. At our largest radii (2-4 Mpc), we
find $w_\text{red}/w_\text{blue} = 1.24 \pm 0.05$. Red galaxies therefore have
denser environments than their blue counterparts at $z \sim 0.625$, and this
effect increases with decreasing radius. Irrespective of color, we find that
$w(R)$ does not obey a simple power-law relation with radius, showing a dip
around 1 Mpc. Holding stellar mass fixed, we find a clear differentiation
between clustering in red and blue galaxies, showing that clustering is not
solely determined by stellar mass. Holding color fixed, we find that clustering
increases with stellar mass, especially for red galaxies at small scales (more
than a factor of 2 effect over 0.75 dex in stellar mass).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04991</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04991</id><created>2017-02-16</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nemes-Incze</keyname><forenames>P&#xe9;ter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kukucska</keyname><forenames>Gerg&#x151;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koltai</keyname><forenames>J&#xe1;nos</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xfc;rti</keyname><forenames>Jen&#x151;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hwang</keyname><forenames>Chanyong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tapaszt&#xf3;</keyname><forenames>Levente</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bir&#xf3;</keyname><forenames>L&#xe1;szl&#xf3; P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Preparing local strain patterns in graphene by atomic force microscope
  based indentation</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 7, 3035 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-03332-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Patterning graphene into various mesoscopic devices such as nanoribbons,
quantum dots, etc. by lithographic techniques has enabled the guiding and
manipulation of graphene's Dirac-type charge carriers. Graphene, with
well-defined strain patterns, holds promise of similarly rich physics while
avoiding the problems created by the hard to control edge configuration of
lithographically prepared devices. To engineer the properties of graphene via
mechanical deformation, versatile new techniques are needed to pattern strain
profiles in a controlled manner. Here we present a process by which strain can
be created in substrate supported graphene layers. Our atomic force
microscope-based technique opens up new possibilities in tailoring the
properties of graphene using mechanical strain.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.05725</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.05725</id><created>2017-02-19</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>ATLAS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Measurements of the production cross section of a $Z$ boson in
  association with jets in pp collisions at $\sqrt{s} = 13$ TeV with the ATLAS
  detector</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>47 pages in total, author list starting page 31, 8 figures, 6 tables,
  published in Eur. Phys. J. C77 (2017) 361. All figures including auxiliary
  figures are available at
  https://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/GROUPS/PHYSICS/PAPERS/STDM-2016-01/</comments><report-no>CERN-EP-2016-297</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C77 (2017) 361</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4900-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Measurements of the production cross section of a $Z$ boson in association
with jets in proton-proton collisions at $\sqrt{s} = 13$ TeV are presented,
using data corresponding to an integrated luminosity of 3.16 fb$^{-1}$
collected by the ATLAS experiment at the CERN Large Hadron Collider in 2015.
Inclusive and differential cross sections are measured for events containing a
$Z$ boson decaying to electrons or muons and produced in association with up to
seven jets with $p_T &gt; 30$ GeV and $|y| &lt;2.5$. Predictions from different Monte
Carlo generators based on leading-order and next-to-leading-order matrix
elements for up to two additional partons interfaced with parton shower and
fixed-order predictions at next-to-leading order and next-to-next-to-leading
order are compared with the measured cross sections. Good agreement within the
uncertainties is observed for most of the modelled quantities, in particular
with the generators which use next-to-leading-order matrix elements and the
more recent next-to-next-to-leading-order fixed-order predictions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.06960</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.06960</id><created>2017-02-22</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Moosa</keyname><forenames>Mudassir</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-relativistic geometry of holographic screens</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>v2: published version</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP06(2017)038</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose that the intrinsic geometry of holographic screens should be
described by the Newton-Cartan geometry. As a test of this proposal, we show
that the evolution equations of the screen can be written in a covariant form
in terms of a stress tensor, an energy current, and a momentum one-form. We
derive the expressions for the stress tensor, energy density, and momentum
one-form using Brown-York action formalism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.07356</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.07356</id><created>2017-02-23</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aloni</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Efrati</keyname><forenames>Aielet</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grossman</keyname><forenames>Yuval</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nir</keyname><forenames>Yosef</forenames></author></authors><title>$\Upsilon$ and $\psi$ leptonic decays as probes of solutions to the
  $R_D^{(*)}$ puzzle</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Version published in JHEP, 17 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of High Energy Physics, 2017(6), 1-27</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP06(2017)019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Experimental measurements of the ratios $R(D^{(*)})\equiv\frac{\Gamma(B\to
D^{(*)}\tau\nu)}{\Gamma(B\to D^{(*)}\ell\nu)}$ ($\ell=e,\mu$) show a
$3.9\sigma$ deviation from the Standard Model prediction. In the absence of
light right-handed neutrinos, a new physics contribution to $b\to c\tau\nu$
decays necessarily modifies also $b\bar b\to\tau^+\tau^-$ and/or $c\bar
c\to\tau^+\tau^-$ transitions. These contributions lead to violation of lepton
flavor universality in, respectively, $\Upsilon$ and $\psi$ leptonic decays. We
analyze the constraints resulting from measurements of the leptonic
vector-meson decays on solutions to the $R(D^{(*)})$ puzzle. Available data
from BaBar and Belle can already disfavor some of the new physics explanations
of this anomaly. Further discrimination can be made by measuring
$\Upsilon(1S,2S,3S)\to\tau\tau$ in the upcoming Belle II experiment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.07541</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.07541</id><created>2017-02-24</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Okai</keyname><forenames>Michito</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawaguchi</keyname><forenames>Koji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tachibana</keyname><forenames>Yasuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirano</keyname><forenames>Tetsufumi</forenames></author></authors><title>New approach to initializing hydrodynamic fields and mini-jet
  propagation in quark-gluon fluids</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph nucl-ex</categories><comments>9 pages, 8 figures; v2: published version, title changed</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 95, 054914 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.95.054914</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a new approach to initialize the hydrodynamic fields such as
energy density distributions and four flow velocity fields in hydrodynamic
modeling of high-energy nuclear collisions at the collider energies. Instead of
matching the energy-momentum tensor or putting the initial conditions of
quark-gluon fluids at a fixed initial time, we utilize a framework of
relativistic hydrodynamic equations with source terms to describe the initial
stage. Putting the energy and momentum loss rate of the initial partons into
the source terms, we obtain hydrodynamic initial conditions dynamically. The
resultant initial profile of the quark-gluon fluid looks highly bumpy as seen
in the conventional event-by-event initial conditions. In addition, initial
random flow velocity fields also are generated as a consequence of momentum
deposition from the initial partons. We regard the partons that survive after
the dynamical initialization process as the mini-jets and find sizable effects
of both mini-jet propagation in the quark-gluon fluids and initial random
transverse flow on the final momentum spectra and anisotropic flow observables.
We perform event-by-event $(3+1)$-dimensional ideal hydrodynamic simulations
with this new framework that enables us to describe the hydrodynamic bulk
collectivity, parton energy loss, and interplay among them in a unified manner.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.07606</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.07606</id><created>2017-02-24</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Furusaki</keyname><forenames>Akira</forenames></author></authors><title>Weyl points and Dirac lines protected by multiple screw rotations</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>8 pages, v2 added references; v3 corrected typos, sec.IIB slightly
  expanded</comments><journal-ref>Science Bulletin 62, 788 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.scib.2017.05.014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In three-dimensional noncentrosymmetric materials two-fold screw rotation
symmetry forces electron's energy bands to have Weyl points at which two bands
touch. This is illustrated for space groups No. 19 ($P2_12_12_1$) and No. 198
($P2_13$), which have three orthogonal screw rotation axes. In the case of
space groups No. 61 ($Pbca$) and No. 205 ($P$a-3) that have extra inversion
symmetry, Weyl points are promoted to four-fold degenerate line nodes in
glide-invariant planes. The three-fold rotation symmetry present in the space
groups No. 198 and No. 205 allows Weyl and Dirac points, respectively, to
appear along its rotation axes in the Brillouin zone and generates four-fold
and six-fold degeneracy at the $\Gamma$ point and R point, respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.07766</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.07766</id><created>2017-02-24</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Heydarzade</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Darabi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Black Hole Solutions Surrounded by Perfect Fluid in Rastall Theory</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>15 Paes, 6 Tables</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters B, 771, (2017) 365-373</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.05.064</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we obtain uncharged\charged Kiselev-like black holes as a new
class of black hole solutions surrounded by perfect fluid in the context of
Rastall theory. Then, we study the specific cases of the uncharged\charged
black holes surrounded by regular matter like dust and radiation, or exotic
matter like quintessence, cosmological constant and phantom fields. By
comparing the Kiselev-like black hole solutions in Rastall theory with the
Kiselev black hole solutions in GR, we find an effective perfect fluid
behaviour for the black hole's surrounding field. It is shown that the
corresponding effective perfect fluid has interesting characteristic features
depending on the different ranges of the parameters in Rastall theory. For
instance, Kiselev-like black holes surrounded by regular matter in Rastall
theory may be considered as Kiselev black holes surrounded by exotic matter in
GR, or Kiselev-like black holes surrounded by exotic matter in Rastall theory
may be considered as Kiselev black holes surrounded by regular matter in GR.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.03316</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.03316</id><created>2017-03-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Shi-Biao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vijay</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Y. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duan</keyname><forenames>L. -M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Converting quasiclassical states into arbitrary Fock state
  superpositions in a superconducting cavity</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>3 figures and 2 tables in the main, 5 figures and 1 table in the
  supplement</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 223604 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.223604</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose and experimentally demonstrate a new method to generate arbitrary
Fock-state superpositions in a superconducting quantum circuit, where a qubit
is dispersively coupled to a microwave cavity mode without the need of
fine-frequency tuning. Here the qubit is used to conditionally modulate the
probability amplitudes of the Fock state components of a coherent state to
those of the desired superposition state, instead of pumping photons one by one
into the cavity as in previous schemes. Our method does not require the
adjustment of the qubit frequency during the cavity state preparation, and is
more robust to noise and accumulation of experimental errors compared to
previous ones. Using the method, we experimentally generate high-fidelity phase
eigenstates under various Hilbert-space dimensions and squeezed states, which
are useful for quantum walk and high-precision measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.04669</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.04669</id><created>2017-03-14</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ruiz</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author></authors><title>Lepton Number Violation at Colliders from Kinematically Inaccessible
  Gauge Bosons</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>Published version. Minor typos, additional references. Results
  unchanged</comments><report-no>IPPP/17/21</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2017) 77: 375</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4950-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We reevaluate the necessity of $W_R$ gauge bosons being kinematically
accessible to test the Left-Right Symmetric Model (LRSM) at hadron colliders.
In the limit that $W_R$ are too heavy, resonant production of sub-TeV Majorana
neutrinos $N$ can still proceed at the Large Hadron Collider (LHC) via the
process $pp\rightarrow W_R^{\pm *}\rightarrow N \ell^\pm \to \ell^\pm \ell^\pm
+nj $ if mediated by a far off-shell $W_R$. Traditional searches strategies are
insensitive to this regime as they rely on momenta of final states scaling with
TeV-scale $M_{W_R}$. For such situations, the process is actually kinematically
and topologically identical to the direct production (DP) process
$pp\rightarrow W_{\rm SM}^{\pm *} \rightarrow N \ell^\pm \rightarrow \ell^\pm
\ell^\pm +nj$. In this context, we reinterpret $\sqrt{s}=8$ TeV LHC constraints
on DP rates for the minimal LRSM. For $m_N = 200-500$ GeV and right-left
coupling ratio $\kappa_R = g_R/g_L$, we find $(M_{W_R} / \kappa_R) &gt; {1.1-1.8}$
TeV at 95\% CLs. Expected sensitivities to DP at 14 (100) TeV are also recast:
with $\mathcal{L}=1~(10)~\text{ab}^{-1}$, one can probe $(M_{W_R} / \kappa_R) &lt;
{7.9-8.9~(14-40)}$ TeV for $m_N = {100 - 700~(1200)}$ GeV. Findings in terms of
gauge invariant dimension-six operators with heavy $N$ are also reported.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08170</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08170</id><created>2017-03-23</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Grinstein</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobach</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author></authors><title>Model-Independent Extraction of $|V_{cb}|$ from $\bar{B}\rightarrow D^*
  \ell \overline{\nu}$</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures; corrected minor typographical errors</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Lett. B771 (2017) 359-364</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.05.078</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We fit the unfolded data of $\bar{B}^0\rightarrow D^{*+} \ell \overline{\nu}$
from the Belle experiment, where $\ell \equiv e, \mu$, using a method
independent of heavy quark symmetry to extrapolate to zero-recoil and extract
the value of $|V_{cb}|$. This results in $|V_{cb}| =
(41.9^{~+2.0}_{~-1.9})\times 10^{-3}$, which is robust to changes in the
theoretical inputs and very consistent with the value extracted from inclusive
semileptonic $B$ decays.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.09122</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.09122</id><created>2017-03-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Solano</keyname><forenames>Pablo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fatemi</keyname><forenames>Fredrik K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orozco</keyname><forenames>Luis A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rolston</keyname><forenames>S. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics of trapped atoms around an optical nanofiber probed through
  polarimetry</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Optics Letters Vol. 42, Issue 12, pp. 2283-2286 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.42.002283</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The evanescent field outside an optical nanofiber (ONF) can create optical
traps for neutral atoms. We present a non-destructive method to characterize
such trapping potentials. An off-resonance linearly polarized probe beam that
propagates through the ONF experiences a slow axis of polarization produced by
trapped atoms on opposite sides along the ONF. The transverse atomic motion is
imprinted onto the probe polarization through the changing atomic index of of
refraction. By applying a transient impulse, we measure a time-dependent
polarization rotation of the probe beam that provides both a rapid and
non-destructive measurement of the optical trapping frequencies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.09504</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.09504</id><created>2017-03-28</created><updated>2017-05-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Whalley</keyname><forenames>Lucy D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frost</keyname><forenames>Jarvist M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jung</keyname><forenames>Young-Kwang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walsh</keyname><forenames>Aron</forenames></author></authors><title>Perspective: Theory and simulation of hybrid halide perovskites</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Chemical Physics 146, 220901 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4984964</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Organic-inorganic halide perovskites present a number of challenges for
first-principles atomistic materials modelling. These `plastic crystals'
feature dynamic processes across multiple length-scales and time-scales, which
include: (i) transport of slow ions and fast electrons; (ii) highly anharmonic
lattice dynamics with short phonon lifetimes; (iii) local symmetry breaking of
the average crystallographic space group; (iv) strong relativistic (spin-orbit
coupling) effects on the electronic band structure; (v) thermodynamic
metastability and rapid chemical breakdown. These issues, which affect the
operation of solar cells, are outlined in this perspective. We also discuss
general guidelines for performing quantitative and predictive simulations of
these materials, which are relevant to metal-organic frameworks and other
hybrid semiconducting, dielectric and ferroelectric compounds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.10533</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.10533</id><created>2017-03-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Solano</keyname><forenames>Pablo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grover</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoffman</keyname><forenames>Jonathan E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ravets</keyname><forenames>Sylvain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fatemi</keyname><forenames>Fredrik K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orozco</keyname><forenames>Luis A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rolston</keyname><forenames>Steven L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical Nanofibers: a new platform for quantum optics</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>65 pages, to appear in Advances in Atomic, Molecular and Optical
  Physics</comments><journal-ref>Advances in Atomic, Molecular, and Optical Physics, Vol. 66, Pages
  439-505 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/bs.aamop.2017.02.003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The development of optical nanofibers (ONF) and the study and control of
their optical properties when coupling atoms to their electromagnetic modes has
opened new possibilities for their use in quantum optics and quantum
information science. These ONFs offer tight optical mode confinement (less than
the wavelength of light) and diffraction-free propagation. The small cross
section of the transverse field allows probing of linear and non-linear
spectroscopic features of atoms with exquisitely low power. The cooperativity
-- the figure of merit in many quantum optics and quantum information systems
-- tends to be large even for a single atom in the mode of an ONF, as it is
proportional to the ratio of the atomic cross section to the electromagnetic
mode cross section. ONFs offer a natural bus for information and for
inter-atomic coupling through the tightly-confined modes, which opens the
possibility of one-dimensional many-body physics and interesting quantum
interconnection applications. The presence of the ONF modifies the vacuum
field, affecting the spontaneous emission rates of atoms in its vicinity. The
high gradients in the radial intensity naturally provide the potential for
trapping atoms around the ONF, allowing the creation of one-dimensional arrays
of atoms. The same radial gradient in the transverse direction of the field is
responsible for the existence of a large longitudinal component that introduces
the possibility of spin-orbit coupling of the light and the atom, enabling the
exploration of chiral quantum optics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00613</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00613</id><created>2017-04-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Hernandez</keyname><forenames>Sergio A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fonseca</keyname><forenames>Alexandre F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Anisotropic Elastic Modulus, High Poisson's ratio and Negative Thermal
  Expansion of Graphynes and Graphdiynes</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><doi>10.1016/j.diamond.2017.06.002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Graphyne (GY) and graphdiyne (GDY) are two-dimensional one-atom-thick carbon
allotropes highly considered to substitute graphene in electronic applications
because of the prediction of non null band-gap. There are seven types of GY
structures not yet fully investigated in literature. In this work, by means of
classical molecular dynamics simulations, the Young's modulus, Poisson's ratio
and linear thermal expansion coefficient (TEC) of all originally proposed seven
types of GYs and corresponding GDYs are calculated. The dependence of these
properties with the density of the structure is investigated for the first
time. Quadratic increasing of the TEC of GY and GDY structures with density was
found. The elastic modulus of GYs and GDYs were shown to be more sensitive to
their density than general porous materials. In particular, non-symmetric
structures are much softer along the armchair direction than along zigzag
direction, implying that the elasticity along armchair direction of GY and GDY
structures are similar to that of porous gels materials. Values larger than
unity were found for the Poisson's ratio of some non-symmetric GYs and GDYs. A
simple honeycomb mechanical model is shown to capture the observed values of
Poisson's ratio of GYs and GDYs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01698</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01698</id><created>2017-04-05</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hatakeyama</keyname><forenames>Kohta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsuchiya</keyname><forenames>Asato</forenames></author></authors><title>Correlation functions and renormalization in a scalar field theory on
  the fuzzy sphere</title><categories>hep-th hep-lat</categories><comments>22 pages, 11 figures, published version</comments><journal-ref>Prog. Theor. Exp. Phys. (2017) 063B01</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/ptep/ptx070</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study renormalization in a scalar field theory on the fuzzy sphere. The
theory is realized by a matrix model, where the matrix size plays the role of a
UV cutoff. We define correlation functions by using the Berezin symbol
identified with a field and calculate them nonperturbatively by Monte Carlo
simulation. We find that the 2-point and 4-point functions are made independent
of the matrix size by tuning a parameter and performing a wave function
renormalization. The results strongly suggest that the theory is
nonperturbatively renormalizable in the ordinary sense.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.07478</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.07478</id><created>2017-04-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Floryan</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Buren</keyname><forenames>Tyler</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rowley</keyname><forenames>Clarence W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smits</keyname><forenames>Alexander J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Scaling the propulsive performance of heaving and pitching foils</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>11 pages</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Fluid Mechanics, Vol. 822, pp. 386-397 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/jfm.2017.302</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Scaling laws for the propulsive performance of rigid foils undergoing
oscillatory heaving and pitching motions are presented. Water tunnel
experiments on a nominally two-dimensional flow validate the scaling laws, with
the scaled data for thrust, power, and efficiency all showing excellent
collapse. The analysis indicates that the behaviour of the foils depends on
both Strouhal number and reduced frequency, but for motions where the viscous
drag is small the thrust closely follows a linear dependence on reduced
frequency. The scaling laws are also shown to be consistent with biological
data on swimming aquatic animals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08864</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08864</id><created>2017-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Ninarello</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berthier</keyname><forenames>Ludovic</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coslovich</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author></authors><title>Models and algorithms for the next generation of glass transition
  studies</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>22 pages, 15 figs</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. X 7, 021039 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevX.7.021039</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Successful computer studies of glass-forming materials need to overcome both
the natural tendency to structural ordering and the dramatic increase of
relaxation times at low temperatures. We present a comprehensive analysis of
eleven glass-forming models to demonstrate that both challenges can be
efficiently tackled using carefully designed models of size polydisperse
supercooled liquids together with an efficient Monte Carlo algorithm where
translational particle displacements are complemented by swaps of particle
pairs. We study a broad range of size polydispersities, using both discrete and
continuous mixtures, and we systematically investigate the role of particle
softness, attractivity and non-additivity of the interactions. Each system is
characterized by its robustness against structural ordering and by the
efficiency of the swap Monte Carlo algorithm. We show that the combined
optimisation of the potential's softness, polydispersity and non-additivity
leads to novel computer models with excellent glass-forming ability. For such
models, we achieve over ten orders of magnitude gain in the equilibration
timescale using the swap Monte Carlo algorithm, thus paving the way to
computational studies of static and thermodynamic properties under experimental
conditions. In addition, we provide microscopic insights into the performance
of the swap algorithm which should help optimizing models and algorithms even
further.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06587</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06587</id><created>2017-05-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Sen</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marsik</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perret</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prada</keyname><forenames>R. de Andres</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alberca</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Biskup</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varela</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernhard</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Superconductivity and charge carrier localization in ultrathin
  $\mathbf{{La_{1.85}Sr_{0.15}CuO_4}/{La_2CuO_4}}$ bilayers</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 214506 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.214506</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  $\mathrm{La_{1.85}Sr_{0.15}CuO_4}$/$\mathrm{La_2CuO_4}$ (LSCO15/LCO) bilayers
with a precisely controlled thickness of N unit cells (UCs) of the former and M
UCs of the latter ([LSCO15\_N/LCO\_M]) were grown on (001)-oriented {\slao}
(SLAO) substrates with pulsed laser deposition (PLD). X-ray diffraction and
reciprocal space map (RSM) studies confirmed the epitaxial growth of the
bilayers and showed that a [LSCO15\_2/LCO\_2] bilayer is fully strained,
whereas a [LSCO15\_2/LCO\_7] bilayer is already partially relaxed. The
\textit{in situ} monitoring of the growth with reflection high energy electron
diffraction (RHEED) revealed that the gas environment during deposition has a
surprisingly strong effect on the growth mode and thus on the amount of
disorder in the first UC of LSCO15 (or the first two monolayers of LSCO15
containing one $\mathrm{CuO_2}$ plane each). For samples grown in pure
$\mathrm{N_2O}$ gas (growth type-B), the first LSCO15 UC next to the SLAO
substrate is strongly disordered. This disorder is strongly reduced if the
growth is performed in a mixture of $\mathrm{N_2O}$ and $\mathrm{O_2}$ gas
(growth type-A). Electric transport measurements confirmed that the first UC of
LSCO15 next to the SLAO substrate is highly resistive and shows no sign of
superconductivity for growth type-B, whereas it is superconducting for growth
type-A. Furthermore, we found, rather surprisingly, that the conductivity of
the LSCO15 UC next to the LCO capping layer strongly depends on the thickness
of the latter. A LCO capping layer with 7~UCs leads to a strong localization of
the charge carriers in the adjacent LSCO15 UC and suppresses superconductivity.
The magneto-transport data suggest a similarity with the case of weakly hole
doped LSCO single crystals that are in a so-called {&quot;{cluster-spin-glass
state}&quot;}
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06925</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06925</id><created>2017-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Jago</keyname><forenames>Roland</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wendler</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malic</keyname><forenames>Ermin</forenames></author></authors><title>Current enhancement due to field-induced dark carrier multiplication in
  graphene</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><doi>10.1088/2053-1583/aa7408</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a microscopic study on current generation in graphene in response
to an electric field. While scattering is generally considered to reduce the
current, we reveal that in graphene Auger processes give rise to a current
enhancement via a phenomenon we denote dark carrier multiplication. Based on a
microscopic approach, we show that, if other scattering channels are absent,
this prevents the carrier distribution to reach a stationary value. Taking into
account scattering with phonons a finite current is restored, however its value
exceeds the stationary current without scattering.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09013</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09013</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Ya-ping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>Wei-xiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Chang-wen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Ping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Pei-ji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kong</keyname><forenames>Biao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Sheng-shi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Shi-shen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Kang</forenames></author></authors><title>Discovery of Intrinsic Quantum Anomalous Hall Effect in Organic Mn-DCA
  Lattice</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>9 pages,4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Applied Physics Letters 110, 233107 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4985144</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quantum anomalous Hall (QAH) phase is a novel topological state of matter
characterized by a nonzero quantized Hall conductivity without an external
magnetic field. The realizations of QAH effect, however, are experimentally
challengeable. Based on ab initio calculations, here we propose an intrinsic
QAH phase in DCA Kagome lattice. The nontrivial topology in Kagome bands are
confirmed by the nonzero chern number, quantized Hall conductivity, and gapless
chiral edge states of Mn-DCA lattice. A tight-binding (TB) model is further
constructed to clarify the origin of QAH effect. Furthermore, its Curie
temperature, estimated to be ~ 253 K using Monte-Carlo simulation, is
comparable with room temperature and higher than most of two-dimensional
ferromagnetic thin films. Our findings present a reliable material platform for
the observation of QAH effect in covalent-organic frameworks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02312</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02312</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Pascalie</keyname><forenames>Romain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Altamirano</keyname><forenames>Natacha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mann</keyname><forenames>Robert B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Emergent Dark Energy in Classical Channel Gravity with Matter</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO quant-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 3 figures, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by the recent increased interest in energy non-conserving models in
cosmology, we extend the analysis of the cosmological consequences of the
Classical Channel Model of Gravity (CCG). This model is based on the
classical-quantum interaction between a test particle and a metric (classical)
and results in a theory with a modified Wheeler-deWitt equation that in turn
leads to non conservation of energy. We show that CCG applied to a cosmological
scenario with primordial matter leads to an emergent dark fluid that at late
times behaves as a curvature term in the Friedmann equations, showing that the
late time behaviour is always dominated by the vacuum solutions. We discuss
possible observational constraints for this model and that, in its current
formulation, CCG eludes any meaningful constraints from current observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02314</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02314</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Guevara</keyname><forenames>Alfredo</forenames></author></authors><title>Holomorphic Classical Limit for Spin Effects in Gravitational and
  Electromagnetic Scattering</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>37 pages. 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide universal expressions for the classical piece of the amplitude
given by the graviton/photon exchange between massive particles of arbitrary
spin, at both tree and one loop level. In the gravitational case this leads to
higher order terms in the post-Newtonian expansion, which have been previously
used in the binary inspiral problem. The expressions are obtained in terms of a
contour integral that computes the Leading Singularity, which was recently
shown to encode the relevant information up to one loop. The classical limit is
performed along a holomorphic trajectory in the space of kinematics, such that
the leading order is enough to extract arbitrarily high multipole corrections.
These multipole interactions are given in terms of a recently proposed
representation for massive particles of any spin by Arkani-Hamed et al. This
explicitly shows universality of the multipole interactions in the effective
potential with respect to the spin of the scattered particles. We perform the
explicit match to standard EFT operators for $S=\frac{1}{2}$ and $S=1$. As a
natural byproduct we obtain the classical pieces up to one loop for the bending
of light.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02352</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02352</id><created>2017-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schafer</keyname><forenames>D. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krzywinski</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robert</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Decker</keyname><forenames>F. -J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct Experimental Observation of the Gas Filamentation Effect using a
  Two-bunch X-ray FEL Beam</title><categories>physics.app-ph physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 6 figures, X-ray FEL Diagnostics Workshop 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the experimental observation of the filamentation effect in gas
devices designed for X-ray Free-electron Lasers. The measurements were carried
out at the Linac Coherent Light Source on the X-ray Correlation Spectroscopy
(XCS) instrument using a Two-bunch FEL beam at 6.5 keV with 122.5 ns separation
passing through an Argon gas cell. The relative intensities of the two pulses
of the Two-bunch beam were measured, after and before the gas cell, from the
X-ray scattering off thin targets by using fast diodes with sufficient temporal
resolution. It was found that the after-to-before ratio of the intensities of
the second pulse was consistently higher than that of the first pulse,
revealing lower effective attenuation of the gas cell due to the heating and
subsequent gas density reduction in the beam path by the first pulse. This
measurement is important in guiding the design and/or mitigating the adverse
effect in gas devices for high repetition-rate FELs such as the LCLS-II and the
European XFEL or other future high repetition-rate upgrade to existing FEL
facilities
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02357</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02357</id><created>2017-06-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Guadagnini</keyname><forenames>Enore</forenames></author></authors><title>Quasi-particles, thermodynamic consistency and the gap equation</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>16 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The thermodynamic properties of superconducting electrons are usually studied
by means of the quasi-particles distribution; but in this approach, the ground
state energy and the dependence of the chemical potential on the electron
density cannot be determined. In order to solve these problems, the
thermodynamic potentials are derived by means of the Bogoliubov-Valatin
formalism. The thermodynamic potentials can be obtained by computing the free
energy of a gas of quasi-particles, whose energy spectrum is conditional on the
gap function. However, the nontrivial dependence of the gap on the temperature
jeopardises the validity of the standard thermodynamic relations. In this
article it is shown how the thermodynamic consistency (i.e. the validity of the
Maxwell relations) is recovered, and the correction terms to the
quasi-particles potentials are computed. It is shown that the
Bogoliubov-Valatin transformation avoids the problem of the thermodynamic
consistency of the quasi-particle approach; in facts, the correct
identification of the variables, which are associated with the quasi-particles,
leads to a precise calculation of the quasi-particles vacuum energy and of the
dependence of the chemical potential on the electron density. The stationarity
condition for the grand potential coincides with the gap equation, which
guarantees the thermodynamic consistency. The expressions of various
thermodynamic potentials, as functions of the (T,V,N) variables, are produced
in the low temperature limit; as a final check, a rederivation of the
condensation energy is presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02363</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02363</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Honda</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>White</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harris</keyname><forenames>A. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chapon</keyname><forenames>L. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fennell</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roessli</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zaharko</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murakami</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kenzelmann</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kimura</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Coupled multiferroic domain switching in the canted conical spin spiral
  system Mn$_{2}$GeO$_{4}$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>25+4 pages, 4+1 figures, 2+2 tables</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 8, 15457 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms15457</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Despite remarkable progress in developing multifunctional materials,
spin-driven ferroelectrics featuring both spontaneous magnetization and
electric polarization are still rare. Among such ferromagnetic ferroelectrics
are conical spin spiral magnets with a simultaneous reversal of magnetization
and electric polarization that is still little understood. Such materials can
feature various multiferroic domains that complicates their study. Here we
study the multiferroic domains in ferromagnetic ferroelectric Mn$_{2}$GeO$_{4}$
using neutron diffraction, and show that it features a double-Q conical
magnetic structure that, apart from trivial 180 degree commensurate magnetic
domains, can be described by ferromagnetic and ferroelectric domains only. We
show unconventional magnetoelectric couplings such as the magnetic-field-driven
reversal of ferroelectric polarization with no change of spin-helicity, and
present a phenomenological theory that successfully explains the
magnetoelectric coupling. Our measurements establish Mn$_{2}$GeO$_{4}$ as a
conceptually simple multiferroic in which the magnetic-field-driven flop of
conical spin spirals leads to the simultaneous reversal of magnetization and
electric polarization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02367</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02367</id><created>2017-06-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Nikulin</keyname><forenames>Igor F.</forenames></author></authors><title>CME Structure and Particle Acceleration</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>REVTeX4, 9 pages, 5 EPS figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The differences of the ejection-image structures in the chromospheric lines
and the coronal continuum are considered. The outer, more diffusive scattering
envelope of the ejection seems to be produced by the excessive free electrons
due to the Compton effect. The resulting electric field accelerate the
particles while the hard radiation is acting. The directed motion of the
accelerated particles induces the magnetic fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02378</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02378</id><created>2017-06-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Metzger</keyname><forenames>Nikolaus Klaus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spesyvtsev</keyname><forenames>Roman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruce</keyname><forenames>Graham D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>Bill</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maker</keyname><forenames>Gareth T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malcolm</keyname><forenames>Graeme</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazilu</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dholakia</keyname><forenames>Kishan</forenames></author></authors><title>Harnessing speckle for a sub-femtometre resolved broadband wavemeter and
  laser stabilization</title><categories>physics.ins-det physics.atom-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>13 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 8, 15610 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms15610</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The accurate determination and control of the wavelength of light is
fundamental to many fields of science. Speckle patterns resulting from the
interference of multiple reflections in disordered media are well-known to
scramble the information content of light by complex but linear processes.
However, these patterns are, in fact, exceptionally rich in information about
the illuminating source. We use a fibre-coupled integrating sphere to generate
wavelength-dependent speckle patterns, in combination with algorithms based on
the transmission matrix method and principal component analysis, to realize a
broadband and sensitive wavemeter. We demonstrate sub-femtometre wavelength
resolution at a centre wavelength of 780 nm and a broad calibrated measurement
range from 488 to 1064 nm. This is comparable with or exceeding the performance
of conventional wavemeters. Using this speckle wavemeter as part of a feedback
loop, we stabilize a 780 nm diode laser to achieve a linewidth better than 1
MHz.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02392</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02392</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>Thi Phuc Tan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krivitsky</keyname><forenames>Leonid</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kwek</keyname><forenames>Leong Chuan</forenames></author></authors><title>Coupled Mode Theory of Microtoroidal Resonators with a One-dimensional
  Waveguide</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the transmission of light through a system consisting of an
arbitrary number $N$ of microtoroidal resonators coupled to a one-dimensional
(1D) waveguide. The transmission $T$ through such a system and its full-width
at half-maximum (FWHM) are calculated for various values of $N$ and mutual-mode
coupling coefficients. We found that at small mutual-mode coupling, the minimum
transmission vanishes exponentially with $N$ while the FWHM is proportional to
$\sqrt{N}$. At big mutual-mode coupling, as the number of resonators increases,
the mode-splitting is reduced. Our findings contribute to better understanding
of novel interfaces between quantum emitters and resonant photonic structures
for quantum information processing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02406</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02406</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Sugimoto</keyname><forenames>Akira</forenames><affiliation>Graduate School of Integrated Arts and Sciences, Hiroshima University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ekino</keyname><forenames>Toshikazu</forenames><affiliation>Graduate School of Integrated Arts and Sciences, Hiroshima University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Gabovich</keyname><forenames>Alexander M.</forenames><affiliation>Institute of Physics, National Academy of Sciences of Ukraine</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sekine</keyname><forenames>Ryotaro</forenames><affiliation>Department of Applied Electronics, Tokyo University of Science</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tanabe</keyname><forenames>Kenji</forenames><affiliation>Department of Applied Electronics, Tokyo University of Science</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tokiwa</keyname><forenames>Kazuyasu</forenames><affiliation>Department of Applied Electronics, Tokyo University of Science</affiliation></author></authors><title>Multilayered cuprate superconductor
  Ba$_2$Ca$_5$Cu$_6$O$_{12}$(O$_{1-x}$,F$_x$)$_2$ studied by
  temperature-dependent scanning tunneling microscopy and spectroscopy</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>14 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>PRB 95, 174508 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.174508</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Scanning tunneling microscopy/spectroscopy (STM/STS) measurements were
carried out on a multi-layered cuprate superconductor
Ba$_2$Ca$_5$Cu$_6$O$_{12}$(O$_{1-x}$,F$_x$)$_2$. STM topography revealed random
spot structures with the characteristic length $\le 0.5$ nm. The conductance
spectra dI/dV(V) show the coexistence of smaller gaps $\Delta_S$ and large gaps
(pseudogaps) $\Delta_L$. The pseudogap-related features in the superconducting
state were traced with the spatial resolution of $\sim$ 0.07 nm. Here, $I$ and
$V$ are the tunnel current and bias voltage, respectively. The temperature,
$T$, dependence of $\Delta_S$ follows the reduced Bardeen-Cooper-Schrieffer
(BCS) dependence. The hallmark ratio 2$\Delta_{S}(T=0)/k_B T_c$ equals to 4.9,
which is smaller than those of other cuprate superconductors. Here, $T_c$ is
the superconducting critical temperature and $k_B$ is the Boltzmann constant.
The larger gap $\Delta_L$ survives in the normal state and even increases with
$T$ above $T_c$. The $T$ dependences of the spatial distributions for both
relevant gaps ($\Delta$ map), as well as for each gap separately ($\Delta_S$
and $\Delta_L$) were obtained. From the histogram of $\Delta$ map, the averaged
gap values were found to be $\bar \Delta_S = \sim 24$ meV and $\bar \Delta_L =
\sim 79$ meV. The smaller gap $\Delta_S$ shows a spatially homogeneous
distribution while the larger gap $\Delta_L$ is quite inhomogeneous, indicating
that rather homogeneous superconductivity coexists with the patchy distributed
pseudogap. The spatial variation length $\xi_{\Delta_L}$ of $\Delta_L$
correlates with the scale of the topography spot structures, being
approximately 0.4 nm. This value is considerably smaller than the coherence
length of this class of superconductors, suggesting that $\Delta_L$ is strongly
affected by the disorder of the apical O/F.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02407</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02407</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Mansuripur</keyname><forenames>Masud</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical Angular Momentum in Classical Electrodynamics</title><categories>physics.optics physics.class-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 3 figures, 43 equations, 34 references</comments><journal-ref>Physica Scripta 92, 065501, pp 1-9 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1402-4896/aa6fa4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Invoking Maxwell's classical equations in conjunction with expressions for
the electromagnetic (EM) energy, momentum, force, and torque, we use a few
simple examples to demonstrate the nature of the EM angular momentum. The
energy and the angular momentum of an EM field will be shown to have an
intimate relationship; a source radiating EM angular momentum will, of
necessity, pick up an equal but opposite amount of mechanical angular momentum;
and the spin and orbital angular momenta of the EM field, when absorbed by a
small particle, will be seen to elicit different responses from the particle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02411</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02411</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Panella</keyname><forenames>Jessica R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trump</keyname><forenames>Benjamin A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marcus</keyname><forenames>Guy G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McQueen</keyname><forenames>Tyrel M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Seeded Chemical Vapor Transport Growth of Cu$_{2}$OSeO$_{3}$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an optimized seeded chemical vapor transport method for the growth
of Cu$_{2}$OSeO$_{3}$ that allows for chemical control in a system with many
stable phases to selectively produce large phase pure single crystals. This
method is shown to consistently produce single crystals in the range of 120 to
180 mg. A Wulff construction model of a representative crystal shows that the
minimum energy surface is {1 1 0}, followed by {1 0 0}. Analysis of the lowest
index planes revealed that cleavage of Se-O bonds has a large energy cost,
leading to an overall high surface energy. The seeded chemical vapor transport
demonstrated here shows promise for large single crystal growth of other
functional materials such as Weyl semimetals, frustrated magnets, and
superconductors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02433</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02433</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>Masaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoshimatsu</keyname><forenames>Kohei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mitsuhashi</keyname><forenames>Taichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kitamura</keyname><forenames>Miho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakai</keyname><forenames>Enju</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yukawa</keyname><forenames>Ryu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Minohara</keyname><forenames>Makoto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujimori</keyname><forenames>Atsushi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horiba</keyname><forenames>Koji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumigashira</keyname><forenames>Hiroshi</forenames></author></authors><title>Emergence of quantum critical behavior in metallic quantum-well states
  of strongly correlated oxides</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Controlling quantum critical phenomena in strongly correlated electron
systems, which emerge in the neighborhood of a quantum phase transition, is a
major challenge in modern condensed matter physics. Quantum critical phenomena
are generated from the delicate balance between long-range order and its
quantum fluctuation. So far, the nature of quantum phase transitions has been
investigated by changing a limited number of external parameters such as
pressure and magnetic field. We propose a new approach for investigating
quantum criticality by changing the strength of quantum fluctuation that is
controlled by the dimensional crossover in metallic quantum well (QW)
structures of strongly correlated oxides. With reducing layer thickness to the
critical thickness of metal-insulator transition, crossover from a Fermi liquid
to a non-Fermi liquid has clearly been observed in the metallic QW of SrVO$_3$
by \textit{in situ} angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy. Non-Fermi liquid
behavior with the critical exponent ${\alpha} = 1$ is found to emerge in the
two-dimensional limit of the metallic QW states, indicating that a quantum
critical point exists in the neighborhood of the thickness-dependent Mott
transition. These results suggest that artificial QW structures provide a
unique platform for investigating novel quantum phenomena in strongly
correlated oxides in a controllable fashion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02460</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02460</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Ping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hsiao</keyname><forenames>Y. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geng</keyname><forenames>C. Q.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pentaquarks in semileptonic $\Lambda_b$ decays</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>11 pages, 3 figures, accepted by Annals of Physics</comments><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2017.06.001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In terms of ${\cal P}_{c1,c2}={\cal P}_c(4380,4450)^+$ as the hidden charm
pentaquark states to consist of $c\bar c uud$, we study the semileptonic
$\Lambda_b\to ({\cal P}_{c1,c2}\to)J/\psi p \ell^-\bar \nu_\ell$ decays. In our
discussion, while the main contribution to $\Lambda_b\to K^-J/\psi p$ is from
the non-perturbative process via the doubly charmful $b\to c\bar cs$
transition, we propose that the $\Lambda_b\to {\cal P}_{c1,c2}\to J/\psi p$
transitions are partly contribute to the $\Lambda_b\to K^-({\cal
P}_{c1,c2}\to)J/\psi p$ decays, in which the required $c\bar c$ pair is formed
by the sea quarks, intrinsic charm, or both. We predict that ${\cal
B}(\Lambda_b\to J/\psi p \ell^-\bar
\nu_\ell)=(2.04^{+4.82}_{-1.57},1.75^{+4.14}_{-1.35})\times 10^{-6}$ for
$\ell=(e,\mu)$, which are about two orders of magnitude smaller than the
observed decay of $\Lambda_b\to p\mu\bar \nu_\mu$. We also explore the angular
correlations for the $J/\psi p$ and $\ell^-\bar \nu_\ell$ pairs. Our results of
the decay branching ratios and angular asymmetries in $\Lambda_b\to J/\psi p
\ell^-\bar \nu_\ell$, accessible to the ongoing experiments at the LHCb, can be
used to improve the understanding of the hidden charm pentaquark states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02461</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02461</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Wagner</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pire</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szymanowski</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>On neutrino production of a charmed meson</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>5 pages, 8 figures, contribution to DIS 2017, XXV International
  Workshop on Deep-Inelastic Scattering and Related Subjects, 3-7 April 2017,
  University of Birmingham, UK</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate in the framework of the collinear QCD approach the amplitude for
exclusive neutrino-production of a pseudoscalar charmed $D$ meson. This process
allows to access gluon and both chiral-odd and chiral-even quark generalized
parton distributions (GPDs), which contribute in specific ways to the amplitude
for different polarization states of the $W$ boson. The energy dependence of
the cross section allows to separate different contributions and the
measurement of the azimuthal dependence helps to single out the transversity
chiral-odd GPDs contributions. The flavor dependence, and in particular the
difference between $D^+$ and $D^0$ production rates, allows to test the
importance of gluonic contributions. The behaviour of the proton and neutron
target cross sections enables to separate the $u$ and $d$ quark contributions.
Planned medium and high energy neutrino facilities will thus allow some
important progress in the realm of hadronic physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02500</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02500</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Xuzhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zeng</keyname><forenames>Jianhua</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-dimensional matter-wave solitons and vortices in competing
  cubic-quintic nonlinear lattices</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.quant-gas nlin.PS</categories><comments>8 pages,7 figures, Frontiers of Physics (In Press)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The nonlinear lattice---a new and nonlinear class of periodic
potentials---was recently introduced to generate various nonlinear localized
modes. Several attempts failed to stabilize two-dimensional (2D) solitons
against their intrinsic critical collapse in Kerr media. Here, we provide a
possibility for supporting 2D matter-wave solitons and vortices in an extended
setting---the cubic and quintic model---by introducing another nonlinear
lattice whose period is controllable and can be different from its cubic
counterpart, to its quintic nonlinearity, therefore making a fully `nonlinear
quasi-crystal'.
  A variational approximation based on Gaussian ansatz is developed for the
fundamental solitons and in particular, their stability exactly follows the
inverted \textit{Vakhitov-Kolokolov} stability criterion, whereas the vortex
solitons are only studied by means of numerical methods. Stability regions for
two types of localized mode---the fundamental and vortex solitons---are
provided. A noteworthy feature of the localized solutions is that the vortex
solitons are stable only when the period of the quintic nonlinear lattice is
the same as the cubic one or when the quintic nonlinearity is constant, while
the stable fundamental solitons can be created under looser conditions. Our
physical setting (cubic-quintic model) is in the framework of the
Gross-Pitaevskii equation (GPE) or nonlinear Schr\&quot;{o}dinger equation, the
predicted localized modes thus may be implemented in Bose-Einstein condensates
and nonlinear optical media with tunable cubic and quintic nonlinearities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02505</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02505</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Turolla</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zane</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taverna</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caniulef</keyname><forenames>D. Gonzalez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mignani</keyname><forenames>R. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Testa</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Comment on &quot;A note on polarized light from Magnetars: QED effects and
  axion-like particles&quot; by L.M. Capparelli, L. Maiani and A.D. Polosa</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>10 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The recent detection of a large polarization degree in the optical emission
of an isolated neutron star led to the suggestion that this has been the first
evidence of vacuum polarization in a strong magnetic field, an effect predicted
by quantum electrodynamics but never observed before. This claim was challanged
in a paper by Capparelli, Maiani &amp; Polosa (2017), according to whom a much
higher polarization degree would be necessary to positively identify vacuum
polarization. Here we show that their conclusions are biased by several
inadequate assumptions and have no impact on the original claim.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02514</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02514</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Sarma</keyname><forenames>Bijita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarma</keyname><forenames>Amarendra K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Single Photon Generation in a Cavity Optomechanical System induced by a
  Nonlinear Photonic Crystal</title><categories>physics.optics quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a novel scheme for realizing single-photon blockade in a weakly
driven hybrid cavity optomechanical system consisting of a nonlinear photonic
crystal. Sub-Poissonian statistics is realized even when the single-photon
optomechanical coupling strength is smaller than the decay rate of the optical
mode. The scheme relaxes the requirement of strong coupling for photon blockade
in optomechanical systems. It is shown that photon blockade could be generated
at the telecommunication wavelength.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02535</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02535</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Belokolos</keyname><forenames>Eugene D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Mendeleev Table: a Proof of Madelung Rule and Atomic Tietz Potential</title><categories>physics.atom-ph math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><proxy>Sigma</proxy><journal-ref>SIGMA 13 (2017), 038, 15 pages</journal-ref><doi>10.3842/SIGMA.2017.038</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  We prove that a neutral atom in mean-field approximation has ${\rm O}(4)$
symmetry and this fact explains the empirical $[n+l,n]$-rule or Madelung rule
which describes effectively periods, structure and other properties of the
Mendeleev table of chemical elements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02537</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02537</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Rezaei</keyname><forenames>Mehdi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malekjani</keyname><forenames>Mohammad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Basilakos</keyname><forenames>Spyros</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mehrabi</keyname><forenames>Ahmad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mota</keyname><forenames>David F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Constraints to dark energy using PADE parameterisations</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>15 pages, 6 figures and 5 tables. Accepted in ApJ</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We put constraints on dark energy properties using the PADE parameterisation,
and compare it to the same constraints using Chevalier-Polarski-Linder (CPL)
and $\Lambda$CDM, at both the background and the perturbation levels. The dark
energy equation of state parameter of the models is derived following the
mathematical treatment of PADE expansion. Unlike CPL parameterisation, the PADE
approximation provides different forms of the equation of state parameter which
avoid the divergence in the far future. Initially, we perform a likelihood
analysis in order to put constraints on the model parameters using solely
background expansion data and we find that all parameterisations are consistent
with each other. Then, combining the expansion and the growth rate data we test
the viability of PADE parameterisations and compare them with CPL and
$\Lambda$CDM models respectively. Specifically, we find that the growth rate of
the current PADE parameterisations is lower than $\Lambda$CDM model at low
redshifts, while the differences among the models are negligible at high
redshifts. In this context, we provide for the first time growth index of
linear matter perturbations in PADE cosmologies. Considering that dark energy
is homogeneous we recover the well known asymptotic value of the growth index,
namely $\gamma_{\infty}=\frac{3(w_{\infty}-1)}{6w_{\infty}-5}$, while in the
case of clustered dark energy we obtain $\gamma_{\infty}\simeq
\frac{3w_{\infty}(3w_{\infty}-5)}{(6w_{\infty}-5)(3w_{\infty}-1)}$. Finally, we
generalize the growth index analysis in the case where $\gamma$ is allowed to
vary with redshift and we find that the form of $\gamma(z)$ in PADE
parameterisation extends that of the CPL and $\Lambda$CDM cosmologies
respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02541</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02541</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Malsagov</keyname><forenames>M. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karandashev</keyname><forenames>I. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kryzhanovsky</keyname><forenames>B. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Analytical Expressions for a Finite-Size 2D Ising Model</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Numerical methods are used to examine the thermodynamic characteristics of
the two-dimensional Ising model as a function of the number of spins N.
Onsager's solution is generalized to a finite-size lattice, and experimentally
validated analytical expressions for the free energy and its derivatives are
computed. The heat capacity at the critical point is shown to grow
logarithmically with N. Due to the finite extent of the system the critical
temperature can only be determined to some accuracy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02548</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02548</id><created>2017-06-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Samarasekara</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Basnayaka</keyname><forenames>B. M. M. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dehipawala</keyname><forenames>Sunil</forenames></author></authors><title>Photocurrent enhancement of spin coated CdS thin films by adding Cu</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>12 pages, 2 tables, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cu added CdS films were synthesized using spin coating technique at different
spin speeds for different time durations. Films were subsequently annealed at
different temperatures for different time periods in air to crystallize the
phase of CdS in thin film form. Films were characterized using XRD, UV- visible
spectrometer and solar simulator. According to XRD patterns, addition of trace
amount of Cu did not change the structure of CdS. However, the optical band gap
gradually decreases with percentage of Cu as expected. As a result, the
photocurrent, fill factor and efficiency measured in KI/I2 electrolyte
gradually increase with the amount of Cu. Photovoltaic properties could be
improved without altering the structure of CdS. Efficiency enhanced CdS films
find potential applications in solar cell industry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02565</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02565</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Aasgrav</keyname><forenames>Elin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnsen</keyname><forenames>Sverre Gullikstad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simonsen</keyname><forenames>Are Johan</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>Bernhard</forenames></author></authors><title>CFD simulations of turbulent flow in the human upper airways</title><categories>physics.med-ph physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on CFD in Oil &amp; Gas,
  Metallurgical and Process Industries, Trondheim, Norway, May 30th - June 1st,
  2017, 6 apges, 9 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, investigations are conducted using Reynolds-averaged
Navier-Stokes (RANS) turbulence models to investigate the importance of
turbulence modelling for nasal inspiration at a constant flow rate of 250 ml/s.
Four different, standard turbulence models are tested in a model geometry based
on pre-operative CT images of a selected obstructive sleep-apnea syndrome
(OSAS) patient. The results show only minor differences between them.
Furthermore, the turbulence models do not give significantly different results
than a laminar flow model. Thus, the main conclusion is that effects of
turbulence are insignificant in CFD modelling of the airflow in the
pre-operative model of the upper airways of the chosen patient.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02566</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02566</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Musiolik</keyname><forenames>Grzegorz</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Beule</keyname><forenames>Caroline</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wurm</keyname><forenames>Gerhard</forenames></author></authors><title>Analog Experiments on Tensile Strength of Dusty and Cometary Matter</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><journal-ref>Icarus, Volume 296, 1 November 2017, Pages 110-116, ISSN 0019-1035</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.icarus.2017.05.009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The tensile strength of small dusty bodies in the solar system is determined
by the interaction between the composing grains. In the transition regime
between small and sticky dust ($\rm \mu m$) and non cohesive large grains (mm),
particles still stick to each other but are easily separated. In laboratory
experiments we find that thermal creep gas flow at low ambient pressure
generates an overpressure sufficient to overcome the tensile strength. For the
first time it allows a direct measurement of the tensile strength of
individual, very small (sub)-mm aggregates which consist of only tens of grains
in the (sub)-mm size range. We traced the disintegration of aggregates by
optical imaging in ground based as well as microgravity experiments and present
first results for basalt, palagonite and vitreous carbon samples with up to a
few hundred Pa. These measurements show that low tensile strength can be the
result of building loose aggregates with compact (sub)-mm units. This is in
favour of a combined cometary formation scenario by aggregation to compact
aggreates and gravitational instability of these units.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02569</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02569</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Franklin</keyname><forenames>Erick de Moraes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ayek</keyname><forenames>Guilherme Augusto</forenames></author></authors><title>The perturbation of a turbulent boundary layer by a two-dimensional hill</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>This manuscript version is made available under the CC-BY-NC-ND 4.0
  license http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/. Accepted
  Manuscript for the Journal of the Brazilian Society of Mechanical Sciences
  and Engineering, v. 35, p. 337-346, 2013</comments><journal-ref>Journal of the Brazilian Society of Mechanical Sciences and
  Engineering, v. 35, p. 337-346 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s40430-013-0024-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Turbulent boundary layers over flat walls in the presence of a hill are
frequently found in nature and industry. Some examples are the air flows over
hills and desert dunes, but also water flows over aquatic dunes inside closed
conduits. The perturbation of a two-dimensional boundary layer by a hill
introduces new scales in the problem, changing the way in which velocities and
stresses are distributed along the flow. When in the presence of sediment
transport, the stress distribution along the hill is strongly related to bed
instabilities. This paper presents an experimental study on the perturbation of
a fully-developed turbulent boundary layer by a two-dimensional hill. Water
flows were imposed over a hill fixed on the bottom wall of a closed conduit and
the flow field was measured by Particle Image Velocimetry. From the flow
measurements, mean and fluctuation fields were computed. The general behaviors
of velocities and stresses are compared to published asymptotic analyses and
the surface shear stress is analyzed in terms of instabilities of a granular
bed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02575</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02575</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Jordal</keyname><forenames>Maria Rolstad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnsen</keyname><forenames>Sverre Gullikstad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dahl</keyname><forenames>Sigrid Kaarstad</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>Bernhard</forenames></author></authors><title>Patient specific numerical simulation of flow in the human upper airways
  for assessing the effect of nasal surgery</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><comments>Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on CFD in Oil &amp; Gas,
  Metallurgical and Process Industries, Trondheim, Norway, May 30th - June 1st,
  2017, 11 pages, 13 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The study is looking into the potential of using computational fluid dynamics
(CFD) as a tool for predicting the outcome of surgery for alleviation of
obstructive sleep apnea syndrome (OSAS). From pre- and post-operative computed
tomography (CT) of an OSAS patient, the pre- and post-operative geometries of
the patient's upper airways were generated. CFD simulations of laminar flow in
the patient's upper airway show that after nasal surgery the mass flow is more
evenly distributed between the two nasal cavities and the pressure drop over
the nasal cavity has increased. The pressure change is contrary to clinical
measurements that the CFD results have been compared with, and this is most
likely related to the earlier steps of modelling - CT acquisition and geometry
retrieval.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02580</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02580</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Kov&#xe1;cs</keyname><forenames>S. T. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herczku</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Juh&#xe1;sz</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarkadi</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guly&#xe1;s</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sulik</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ionization of small molecules induced by H$^+$, He$^+$ and N$^+$
  projectiles: comparison of experiment with quantum and classical calculations</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the energy and angular distribution of ejected electrons from
CH$_4$ and H$_{2}$O molecules impacted by 1 MeV H$^+$, He$^+$ and 650 keV N$^+$
ions. Spectra were measured at different observation angles, from 2 eV to 2000
eV. The obtained absolute double-differential-electron-emission cross sections
(DDCS) were compared with the results of CTMC and CDW-EIS calculations. For the
bare H+ projectile both theories show remarkable agreement with the experiment
at all observed angles and energies. The CTMC results are in similarly good
agreement with the DDCS spectra obtained for impact by dressed He$^+$ and N$^+$
ions, where screening effects and electron loss from the projectile gain
importance. The CDW-EIS calculations slightly overestimate the electron loss
for 1 MeV He$^+$ impact, and overestimate both the target and projectile
ionization at low emitted electron energies for 650 keV N$^+$ impact. The
contribution of multiple electron scattering by the projectile and target
centers (Fermi-shuttle) dominates the N$^+$-impact spectra at higher electron
energies, and it is well reproduced by the non-perturbative CTMC calculations.
The contributions of different processes in medium velocity collisions of
dressed ions with molecules are determined.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02589</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02589</id><created>2017-06-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Bhattacharya</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saha</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fine Structure Constant and Fractal Potential</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>7pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The variation of fine structure constant with the variation of velocity of
light has been studied considering contribution to the permeability and
permittivity of the vacuum and incorporating contribution of fractal potential
originated from the non-differentiability of fractal fluctuation. The time
variation of $\alpha$ is found to depend on the complex velocity field
characteristics of fractal nature of space time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02600</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02600</id><created>2017-06-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Changshi</forenames></author></authors><title>Precise determination of reliable work function in according to the
  definition from photoelectric effect</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The strategy of using the definition of work function from photoelectric
effect to determine precise and reliable work function by the contribution of
frequency to photoelectric yield is investigated theoretically in this paper.
Based on the Fermi-Dirac distribution and the definition of work function
proposed by Einstein in photoelectric effect, a typical numerical method is
pursed step by step to quantitatively analyze the frequency-dependent
photoelectric yield. Supplementing applications to In14 cluster and three kinds
of metals, the simulations agree well with the observed spectra (photoelectric
yield-frequency). At the same time, the threshold frequency of light-dependent
the work function is theoretically explained successfully via one equation so
that the work function can be predicted precisely and reliably. These results
suggest that the formalism pursed in this paper, which is straight forward and
physical, may be of significant utility in metal cluster spectroscopy. It is
hoped also that the results will encourage a comprehensive theoretical analysis
of the applicability of bulk-derived models to cluster photo-ionization
behavior, and of the transition from atomic and molecular-type to surface-type
photoemission.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02611</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02611</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Linnik</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bus</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deveaux</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Doering</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kudejova</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wagner</keyname><forenames>F. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yazgili</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stroth</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Radiation damage caused by cold neutrons in boron doped CMOS active
  pixel sensors</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>This is an author-created, un-copyedited version of an article
  published in Journal of Statistical Mechanics: Theory and Experiment. IOP
  Publishing Ltd is not responsible for any errors or omissions in this version
  of the manuscript or any version derived from it. The Version of Record is
  available online at the link below.</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Instrumentation, Volume 12, May 2017, p. C05011</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1748-0221/12/05/C05011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  CMOS Monolithic Active Pixel Sensors (MAPS) are considered as an emerging
technology in the field of charged particle tracking. They will be used in the
vertex detectors of experiments like STAR, CBM and ALICE and are considered for
the ILC and the tracker of ATLAS. In those applications, the sensors are
exposed to sizeable radiation doses.
  While the tolerance of MAPS to ionizing radiation and fast hadrons is well
known, the damage caused by low energy neutrons was not studied so far. Those
slow neutrons may initiate nuclear fission of $^{10}$B dopants found in the
B-doped silicon active medium of MAPS. This effect was expected to create an
unknown amount of radiation damage beyond the predictions of the NIEL (Non
Ionizing Energy Loss) model for pure silicon.
  We estimate the impact of this effect by calculating the additional NIEL
created by this fission. Moreover, we show first measured data for CMOS sensors
which were irradiated with cold neutrons. The empirical results contradict the
prediction of the updated NIEL model both, qualitatively and quantitatively:
The sensors irradiated with slow neutrons show an unexpected and strong
acceptor removal, which is not observed in sensors irradiated with MeV
neutrons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02636</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02636</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Da-wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>M. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>How isolated is enough for an &quot;isolated&quot; system in statistical
  mechanics?</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Irreversible processes are frequently adopted to account for the entropy
increase in classical thermodynamics. However, the corresponding physical
origins are not always clear, e.g. in a free expansion process, a typical model
in textbooks. In this letter, we study the entropy change during free expansion
for a particle with the thermal de Broglie wavelength ($\lambda_{T}$) in a
one-dimensional square trap with size $L$. By solely including quantum
dephasing as an irreversible process, we recover classical result of entropy
increase in the classical region ($L\gg\lambda_{T}$), while predict prominent
discrepancies in the quantum region ($L\ll\lambda_{T}$) because of
non-equilibrium feature of trapped atoms after expansion. It is interesting to
notice that the dephasing, though absent in classical system, is critical to
clarify mysteries in classical thermodynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02642</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02642</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Suetin</keyname><forenames>D. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shein</keyname><forenames>I. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electronic structure for new layered high-temperature superconductors
  CaAFe4As4 (A=K, Rb, Cs): FLAPW-GGA calculations</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>15 pagers, 6 tables, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, new FeAs based high-temperature superconductors CaAFe4As4 (A=K, Rb,
Cs) with a layered tetragonal crystal structure were synthesized (TC ~ 30 K).
In this Letter, we report for the first time the band structures, Fermi surface
topology, total and partial densities of electronic states and interatomic
interactions for CaAFe4As4 as estimated by means of the first-principles
FLAPW-GGA calculations. The interatomic bonding picture can be represented as a
highly anisotropic mixture of metallic, covalent, and ionic contributions,
which are realized inside Fe4As4 layered blocks and between these blocks and
Ca, A atomic sheets. The Fermi surfaces of these systems have a multisheet
character and are compiled of a large number of cylinders at the edges and in
the central part of the Brillouin zone. It is established that the
high-temperature superconductivity in CaAFe4As4 compounds as in other related
systems correlates well with such structure parameters as bond angles and anion
height.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02644</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02644</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Buta</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames><affiliation>University of Alabama</affiliation></author></authors><title>Galactic Rings Revisited. II. Dark Gaps and the Locations of Resonances
  in Early-to-Intermediate Type Disk Galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical
  Society (50 pages with 23 figures and 18 tables)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dark gaps are commonly seen in early-to-intermediate type barred galaxies
having inner and outer rings or related features. In this paper, the
morphologies of 54 barred and oval ringed galaxies have been examined with the
goal of determining what the dark gaps are telling us about the structure and
evolution of barred galaxies. The analysis is based mainly on galaxies selected
from the Galaxy Zoo 2 database and the Catalogue of Southern Ringed Galaxies.
The dark gaps between inner and outer rings are of interest because of their
likely association with the L4 and L5 Lagrangian points that would be present
in the gravitational potential of a bar or oval. Since the points are
theoretically expected to lie very close to the corotation resonance (CR) of
the bar pattern, the gaps provide the possibility of locating corotation in
some galaxies simply by measuring the radius rgp of the gap region and setting
rCR=rgp. With the additional assumption of generally flat rotation curves, the
locations of other resonances can be predicted and compared with observed
morphological features. It is shown that this &quot;gap method&quot; provides remarkably
consistent interpretations of the morphology of early-to-intermediate type
barred galaxies. The paper also brings attention to cases where the dark gaps
lie inside an inner ring, rather than between inner and outer rings. These may
have a different origin compared to the inner/outer ring gaps.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02658</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02658</id><created>2017-06-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Anderson</keyname><forenames>Benjamin R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gunawidjaja</keyname><forenames>Ray</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eilers</keyname><forenames>Hergen</forenames></author></authors><title>Dy$^{3+}$-doped Yttrium Complex Molecular Crystals for Two-color
  Thermometry in Heterogeneous Materials</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>11 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Lumin. 188, 238-245 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jlumin.2017.04.020</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop Dy$^{3+}$-doped yttrium complexes for use as two-color thermometry
(TCT) phosphor molecular crystals in heterogeneous materials. These complexes
include: Dy:Y(acac)$_3$(phen), Dy:Y(hfa)$_3$(DPEPO), Dy:Y(4-BBA)$_3$(TPPO),
Dy:Y(acac)$_3$, and Dy:Y(acac)$_3$(DPEPO), where the Dy/Y ratio is 1:9. We
characterize the materials' photoluminescence at different temperatures to
determine the TCT calibration parameters and the degree to which thermal
quenching influences the emission. From this data we observe a link between the
excited state lifetime at room temperature and the degree to which the material
is susceptible to thermal quenching (i.e. materials having long room
temperature lifetimes are more resistant to thermal quenching than materials
with short room temperature lifetimes). Of the five complexes tested we find
that Dy:Y(acac)$_3$(DPEPO) has the best thermal performance, with the most
likely source of improvement being DPEPO's compact rigid structure. This
rigidity helps with energy transfer to the Dy$^{3+}$ ion, suppresses
non-radiative loss modes, and reduces exciplex formation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02659</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02659</id><created>2017-06-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Anderson</keyname><forenames>Benjamin R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gunawidjaja</keyname><forenames>Ray</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eilers</keyname><forenames>Hergen</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-color Thermosensors based on
  [Y$_{1-X}$Dy$_X$(acetylacetonate)$_3$(1,10-phenanthroline) Molecular Crystals</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.optics</categories><comments>16 pages, 17 figures</comments><journal-ref>App. Phys. B 123, 62 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00340-017-6638-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a two-color thermometry (TCT) phosphor based on
[Y$_{1-x}$Dy$_x$(acetylacetonate)$_3$(1,10-phenanthroline)]
([Y$_{1-x}$Dy$_x$(acac)$_3$(phen)]) molecular crystals for use in heterogeneous
materials. We characterize the optical properties of
[Y$_{1-x}$Dy$_x$(acac)$_3$(phen)] crystals at different temperatures and Dy
concentrations and find that the emission is strongly quenched by increasing
temperature and concentration. We also observe a broad background emission (due
to the ligands) and find that [Y$_{1-x}$Dy$_x$(acac)$_3$(phen)] photodegrades
under 355 nm illumination with the photodegradation resulting in decreased
luminescence intensity. However, while decreasing the overall emission
intensity, photodegradation is not found to influence the integrated intensity
ratio of the ${}^4I_{15/2} \rightarrow {}^6H_{15/2}$ and ${}^4F_{9/2}
\rightarrow {}^6H_{15/2}$ transitions. This ratio allows us to compute the
temperature of the complex Based on the temperature dependence of these ratios
we calculate that [Y$_{1-x}$Dy$_x$(acac)$_3$(phen)] has a maximum sensitivity
of 1.5 \% K$^{-1}$ and our TCT system has a minimum temperature resolution of
1.8 K. Finally, we demonstrate the use of [Y$_{1-x}$Dy$_x$(acac)$_3$(phen)] as
a TCT phosphor by determining a dynamic temperature profile using the emission
from [Y$_{1-x}$Dy$_x$(acac)$_3$(phen)].
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02680</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02680</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>Souradeep</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kua</keyname><forenames>Harn Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pang</keyname><forenames>Sze Dai</forenames></author></authors><title>Autonomous Repair in Cementitous Material by Combination of
  Superabsorbent Polymers and Polypropylene Fibres: A Step Towards Sustainable
  Infrastructure</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>World Sustainable Built Environment Confernece</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Manual maintenance and repair of cracks in concrete structures are often
unsustainable because of associated labor, capital and environmental damage.
Introduction of microfibers and superabsorbent polymers is a material solution
to restrict crack propagation and enhance self-healing efficiency. Therefore,
the study proposes a combination of polypropylene(PP) fibers and superabsorbent
polymers (SAP) which would facilitate autonomous healing and recover original
mechanical and durability properties of mortar. Mechanical strength, sorptivity
and water penetration of healed mortars were compared to that of undamaged
mortar at same age to estimate recovery of original properties while crack
sealing was investigated by means of optical microscopy. Experimental results
show mortar with combination of PP fibers and SAP showed full recovery of
mechanical strength after healing while recovery in durability up to 90% was
recorded. Microscopic images show that average crack-sealing ratio of 85% could
be achieved under moist condition by combination of SAP and PP fibers while
sealing under drier air curing condition is also significantly higher than
reference samples with only fibers. Crack width up to 330{\mu}m has been found
to be completely sealed by carbonate crystals. Furthermore, mortar with SAP and
PP fibers retain about 70% of their original 28-day strength after three cycles
of loading while reference mortar samples were found to retain only about
40-50% of their original strength. Effective crack sealing and high recovery of
original properties in mortars with SAP and fibers suggest that this material
combination would reduce the need for environmentally damaging and expensive
repairs during the service life.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02683</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02683</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Hare</keyname><forenames>Trent M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rossi</keyname><forenames>Angelo P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frigeri</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marmo</keyname><forenames>Chiara</forenames></author></authors><title>Interoperability in Planetary Research for Geospatial Data Analysis</title><categories>astro-ph.IM physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 3 figures, from American Geophysical Union 2015 invited
  talk, In Press</comments><doi>10.1016/j.pss.2017.04.004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For more than a decade there has been a push in the planetary science
community to support interoperable methods for accessing and working with
geospatial data. Common geospatial data products for planetary research include
image mosaics, digital elevation or terrain models, geologic maps, geographic
location databases (e.g., craters, volcanoes) or any data that can be tied to
the surface of a planetary body (including moons, comets or asteroids). Several
U.S. and international cartographic research institutions have converged on
mapping standards that embrace standardized geospatial image formats, geologic
mapping conventions, U.S. Federal Geographic Data Committee (FGDC) cartographic
and metadata standards, and notably on-line mapping services as defined by the
Open Geospatial Consortium (OGC).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02685</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02685</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>de la Calleja</keyname><forenames>Elsa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bazoni</keyname><forenames>R. F</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rocha</keyname><forenames>M. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barbosa</keyname><forenames>Marcia</forenames></author></authors><title>Topology of DNA: a honeycomb stable structure under salt effect</title><categories>cond-mat.soft nlin.AO</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Atomic Force Microscopy analysis is employed to study the geometrical and
topological properties of $3000$kbp DNA molecules fixed in mica substrates with
$MgCl_{2}$. We found that the aggregates on the substrate surface for certain
salt concentrations form a honeycomb stable structure with the addition of
salt. The honeycomb, and the transition to other structures, were characterized
by the \emph{Betti numbers}, which is a topological invariant property and by
\emph{Hausdorff-Besicovitch fractal dimension}.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02700</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02700</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Wong</keyname><forenames>Joeson</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jariwala</keyname><forenames>Deep</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tagliabue</keyname><forenames>Giulia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tat</keyname><forenames>Kevin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davoyan</keyname><forenames>Artur R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sherrott</keyname><forenames>Michelle C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Atwater</keyname><forenames>Harry A.</forenames></author></authors><title>High Photovoltaic Quantum Efficiency in Ultrathin van der Waals
  Heterostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.app-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>ACS Nano, 2017. Manuscript (25 pages, 7 figures) plus supporting
  information (7 pages, 4 figures)</comments><doi>10.1021/acsnano.7b03148</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report experimental measurements for ultrathin (&lt; 15 nm) van der Waals
heterostructures exhibiting external quantum efficiencies exceeding 50%, and
show that these structures can achieve experimental absorbance &gt; 90%. By
coupling electromagnetic simulations and experimental measurements, we show
that pn WSe2/MoS2 heterojunctions with vertical carrier collection can have
internal photocarrier collection efficiencies exceeding 70%.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:astro-ph/0501522</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>astro-ph/0501522</id><created>2005-01-24</created><updated>2005-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mackay</keyname><forenames>Tom G.</forenames><affiliation>University of Edinburgh</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lakhtakia</keyname><forenames>Akhlesh</forenames><affiliation>Pennsylvania State University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Setiawan</keyname><forenames>Sandi</forenames><affiliation>University of Edinburgh</affiliation></author></authors><title>Mapping of electromagnetic negative-phase-velocity propagation in the
  ergosphere of a rotating black hole</title><categories>astro-ph gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>Typographical error in eq (51) of NJP version is corrected in arxiv
  version</comments><journal-ref>New Journal of Physics 7 (2005) 171</journal-ref><abstract>  We report on the occurrence of negative-phase-velocity (NPV) planewave
propagation in the ergosphere of a rotating black hole. By implementing the
Kerr metric, it is demonstrated that regions of NPV propagation are
concentrated at the equator of the ergosphere, while NPV propagation is less
common towards the polar regions. Increasing the angular velocity of the black
hole exaggerates the NPV concentration at the equator. NPV propagation is not
observed outside the stationary limit surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
