<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T11:13:32Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-06-12" from="2017-06-12" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1404.6625</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1404.6625</id><created>2014-04-26</created><updated>2015-09-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Finster</keyname><forenames>Felix</forenames></author></authors><title>The Chiral Index of the Fermionic Signature Operator</title><categories>math-ph math.DG math.MP</categories><comments>21 pages, LaTeX, 3 figures, minor corrections (published version)</comments><journal-ref>Math. Res. Lett. 24 (2017) 37-66</journal-ref><doi>10.4310/MRL.2017.v24.n1.a3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We define an index of the fermionic signature operator on even-dimensional
globally hyperbolic spin manifolds of finite lifetime. The invariance of the
index under homotopies is studied. The definition is generalized to causal
fermion systems with a chiral grading. We give examples of space-times and
Dirac operators thereon for which our index is non-trivial.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.01915</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.01915</id><created>2015-02-05</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Maurya</keyname><forenames>S. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>Y. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ray</keyname><forenames>Saibal</forenames></author></authors><title>All spherically symmetric charged anisotropic solutions for compact star</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>28 pages, 15 figures, major changes in the text. arXiv admin note:
  text overlap with arXiv:1408.5126 by other authors</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2017) 77:360</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4917-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the present paper we develop an algorithm for all spherically symmetric
anisotropic charged fluid distribution. Considering a new source function
$\nu(r)$ we find out a set of solutions which is physically well behaved and
represent compact stellar models. A detailed study specifically shows that the
models actually correspond to strange stars in terms of their mass and radius.
In this connection we investigate about several physical properties like energy
conditions, stability, mass-radius ratio, electric charge content, anisotropic
nature and surface redshift through graphical plots and mathematical
calculations. All the features from these studies are in excellent agreement
with the already available evidences in theory as well as observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.04293</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.04293</id><created>2015-02-15</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jora</keyname><forenames>Renata</forenames></author></authors><title>Abelian Higgs model and its phase transitions revisited</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>6 pages, version publsihed</comments><journal-ref>Rom. Rep. Phys. 69, 106 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The abelian Higgs model and its phase structure are discussed from the
perspective that the gauge and scalar fields admit a dual description in terms
of fermion variables. The results which indicate the presence of three main
phases: Coulomb, Higgs and confinement agree well with those in the literature
although a nonstandard order parameter is employed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.01435</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.01435</id><created>2015-03-03</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tulchinsky</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gat</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Viscous-poroelastic interaction as mechanism to create adhesion in
  frogs' toe pads</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.bio-ph physics.flu-dyn</categories><doi>10.1017/jfm.2015.293</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The toe pads of frogs consist of soft hexagonal structures and a viscous
liquid contained between and within the hexagonal structures. It has been
hypothesized that this configuration creates adhesion by allowing for long
range capillary forces, or alternatively, by allowing for exit of the liquid
and thus improving contact of the toe pad. In this work we suggest interaction
between viscosity and elasticity as a mechanism to create temporary adhesion,
even in the absence of capillary effects or van der Waals forces. We initially
illustrate this concept experimentally by a simplified configuration consisting
of two surfaces connected by a liquid bridge and elastic springs. We then
utilize poroelastic mixture theory and model frog's toe pads as an elastic
porous medium, immersed within a viscous liquid and pressed against a rigid
rough surface. The flow between the surface and the toe pad is modeled by the
lubrication approximation. Inertia is neglected and analysis of the
elastic-viscous dynamics yields a governing partial differential equation
describing the flow and stress within the porous medium. Several solutions of
the governing equation are presented and show a temporary adhesion due to
stress created at the contact surface between the solids. This work thus may
explain how some frogs (such as the torrent frog) maintain adhesion underwater
and the reason for the periodic repositioning of frogs' toe pads during
adhesion to surfaces.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.07213</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.07213</id><created>2015-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Millot</keyname><forenames>Guy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pitois</keyname><forenames>St&#xe9;phane</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hovannysyan</keyname><forenames>Tatevik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bendahmane</keyname><forenames>Abdelkrim</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xe4;nsch</keyname><forenames>Theodor W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Picqu&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Nathalie</forenames></author></authors><title>Frequency-agile dual-comb spectroscopy</title><categories>physics.optics physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature Photonics 10, 27-30, (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nphoton.2015.250</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a new approach to near-infrared molecular spectroscopy, harnessing
advanced concepts of optical telecommunications and supercontinuum photonics.
We generate, without mode-locked lasers, two frequency combs of slightly
different repetition frequencies and moderate, but rapidly tunable, spectral
span. The output of a frequency-agile continuous wave laser is split and sent
into two electro-optic intensity modulators. Flat-top low-noise frequency combs
are produced by wave-breaking in a nonlinear optical fiber of normal
dispersion. With a dual-comb spectrometer, we record Doppler-limited spectra
spanning 60 GHz within 13 microseconds and 80-kHz refresh rate, at a tuning
speed of 10 nm.s^(-1). The sensitivity for weak absorption is enhanced by a
long gas-filled hollow-core fiber.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.07332</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.07332</id><created>2015-05-20</created><updated>2017-05-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Johnson</keyname><forenames>Samuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>Nick S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Looplessness in networks is linked to trophic coherence</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>Manuscript plus SI</comments><journal-ref>PNAS 114, 5618-5623 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1073/pnas.1613786114</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many natural, complex systems are remarkably stable thanks to an absence of
feedback acting on their elements. When described as networks, these exhibit
few or no cycles, and associated matrices have small leading eigenvalues. It
has been suggested that this architecture can confer advantages to the system
as a whole, such as `qualitative stability', but this observation does not in
itself explain how a loopless structure might arise. We show here that the
number of feedback loops in a network, as well as the eigenvalues of associated
matrices, are determined by a structural property called trophic coherence, a
measure of how neatly nodes fall into distinct levels. Our theory correctly
classifies a variety of networks -- including those derived from genes,
metabolites, species, neurons, words, computers and trading nations -- into two
distinct regimes of high and low feedback, and provides a null model to gauge
the significance of related magnitudes. Since trophic coherence suppresses
feedback, whereas an absence of feedback alone does not lead to coherence, our
work suggests that the reasons for `looplessness' in nature should be sought in
coherence-inducing mechanisms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.00079</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.00079</id><created>2015-05-30</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fariborz</keyname><forenames>Amir H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jora</keyname><forenames>Renata</forenames></author></authors><title>A solution to the naturalness problem</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, version published</comments><journal-ref>Rom. J. Phys. 62, 106 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a solution to the naturalness problem of the electroweak scale
based on a change of variable in the Fourier space of non supersymmetric nature
that transforms a boson into a fermion and viceversa. This is exemplified for
that part of the standard model Lagrangian that contains a Dirac fermion
coupled with the Higgs field. The full Lagrangian which contains both the
initial particles and the partners obtained through this method is invariant
under the symmetry associated to this change of variables and is free of
quadratic divergences to the scalar particles present in the Lagrangian. The
partners appear mostly as &quot;off-shell&quot; states thus explaining their experimental
absence at any particle accelerators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.02638</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.02638</id><created>2015-07-09</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gol&#xe9;nia</keyname><forenames>Sylvain</forenames><affiliation>IMB</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Truc</keyname><forenames>Fran&#xe7;oise</forenames><affiliation>IF</affiliation></author></authors><title>The magnetic Laplacian acting on discrete cusps</title><categories>math.SP math-ph math.FA math.MP</categories><comments>In this new version we correct some mistakes and we provide more
  detailed proofs. Some results are also improved</comments><proxy>ccsd</proxy><report-no>IF\_PREPUB</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce the notion of discrete cusp for a weighted graph. In this
context, we provethat the form-domain of the magnetic Laplacian and that of
thenon-magnetic Laplacian can be different. We establish the emptiness of the
essential spectrum and compute theasymptotic of eigenvalues for the magnetic
Laplacian.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.00723</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.00723</id><created>2015-08-04</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Lihua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Depeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hung</keyname><forenames>Hsiang-Hsuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yong-Jun</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase diagram of a frustrated asymmetric ferromagnetic spin ladder</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>14 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. B (2017) 90: 105</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2017-70716-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We perform a systematic investigation on the ground state of an asymmetric
two-leg spin ladder (where exchange couplings of the legs are unequal) with
ferromagnetic (FM) nearest-neighbor interaction and diagonal anti-ferromagnetic
frustration using the Density Matrix Renormalization Group (DMRG) method. When
the ladder is strongly asymmetric with moderate frustration, a magnetic canted
state is observed between a FM state and a singlet dimerized state. The phase
boundaries are dependent on the asymmetric strength $\alpha_{a}$. On the other
hand, when the asymmetric strength is intermediate, a so-called spin-stripe
state (spins align parallel on same legs, but antiparallel on rungs) is
discovered, and the system experiences a first-order phase transition from the
FM state to the spin-stripe state upon increasing frustration. We present
numerical evidence to interpret the phase diagram in terms of frustration and
the asymmetric strength.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.03122</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.03122</id><created>2016-02-09</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lasota</keyname><forenames>Miko&#x142;aj</forenames></author><author><keyname>Filip</keyname><forenames>Radim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Usenko</keyname><forenames>Vladyslav C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Robustness of quantum key distribution with discrete and continuous
  variables to channel noise</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 062312 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.062312</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the robustness of quantum key distribution protocols using discrete
or continuous variables to the channel noise. We introduce the model of such
noise based on coupling of the signal to a thermal reservoir, typical for
continuous-variable quantum key distribution, to the discrete-variable case.
Then we perform a comparison of the bounds on the tolerable channel noise
between these two kinds of protocols using the same noise parametrization, in
the case of implementation which is perfect otherwise. Obtained results show
that continuous-variable protocols can exhibit similar robustness to the
channel noise when the transmittance of the channel is relatively high.
However, for strong loss discrete-variable protocols are superior and can
overcome even the infinite-squeezing continuous-variable protocol while using
limited nonclassical resources. The requirement on the probability of a
single-photon production which would have to be fulfilled by a practical source
of photons in order to demonstrate such superiority is feasible thanks to the
recent rapid development in this field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04047</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04047</id><created>2016-02-12</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gravejat</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames><affiliation>AGM</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lewin</keyname><forenames>Mathieu</forenames><affiliation>CEREMADE</affiliation></author><author><keyname>S&#xe9;r&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>&#xc9;ric</forenames><affiliation>CEREMADE</affiliation></author></authors><title>Derivation of the magnetic Euler-Heisenberg energy</title><categories>math-ph math.AP math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>Final version to appear in J. Math. Pure Appl</comments><proxy>ccsd</proxy><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In quantum field theory, the vacuum is a fluctuating medium which behaves as
a nonlinear polarizable material. In this article, we perform the first
rigorous derivation of the magnetic Euler-Heisenberg effective energy, a
nonlinear functional that describes the effective fluctuations of the quantum
vacuum in a classical magnetic field. We start from a classical magnetic field
in interaction with a quan-tized Dirac field in its ground state, and we study
a limit in which the classical magnetic field is slowly varying. After a change
of scales, this is equivalent to a semi-classical limit $\hbar\to0$, with a
strong magnetic field of order $1/\hbar$. In this regime, we prove that the
energy of Dirac's polarized vacuum converges to the Euler-Heisenberg
functional. The model has ultraviolet divergences, which we regularize using
the Pauli-Villars method. We also discuss how to remove the regularization of
the Euler-Heisenberg effective Lagrangian, using charge renormaliza-tion,
perturbatively to any order of the coupling constant.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.06146</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.06146</id><created>2016-02-19</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jora</keyname><forenames>Renata</forenames></author></authors><title>Vacuum energy in some particular quantum field theories</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>7 pages, version published</comments><journal-ref>Proc. Romanian Academy A, 18, no. 2, 124-130 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the properties of a class of quantum field theories endowed with an
equal number of anti commuting and commuting field variables, the most common
example being the supersymmetric models. Based on the scaling properties of the
partition function we find that these theories have the quantum energy momentum
tensor associated to dilatations and thus the vacuum energy equal to zero.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02326</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02326</id><created>2016-02-19</created><updated>2016-03-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cheremisin</keyname><forenames>M. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Surprising coincidence of the apparent 2D metal-to-insulator transition
  data with Fermi-gas based model results</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>4 pages, changes in fig.3</comments><journal-ref>Solid State Commun 253, 46-50 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ssc.2017.01.027</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The melting condition for two-dimensional Wigner solid ( P.M. Platzman,
H.Fukuyama, 1974) is shown to contain an error of a factor of $\pi$. The
analysis of experimental data for apparent 2D metal-to-insulator transition
shows that the Wigner solidification (B.Tanatar, D.M.Ceperley, 1989) has been
never achieved. Within routine Fermi gas model both the metallic and insulating
behavior of different 2D system for actual range of carrier densities and
temperatures is explained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03674</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03674</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Meece</keyname><forenames>Gregory R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voit</keyname><forenames>G. Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Shea</keyname><forenames>Brian W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Triggering and Delivery Algorithms for AGN Feedback</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>17 pages, 12 figures, submitted to ApJ</comments><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa6fb1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compare several common sub-grid implementations of AGN feedback, focusing
on the effects of different triggering mechanisms and the differences between
thermal and kinetic feedback. Our main result is that pure thermal feedback
that is centrally injected behaves differently from feedback with even a small
kinetic component. Specifically, pure thermal feedback results in excessive
condensation and smothering of the AGN by cold gas because the feedback energy
does not propagate to large enough radii. We do not see large differences
between implementations of different triggering mechanisms, as long as the
spatial resolution is sufficiently high, probably because all of the
implementations tested here trigger strong AGN feedback under similar
conditions. In order to assess the role of resolution, we vary the size of the
&quot;accretion zone&quot; in which properties are measured to determine the AGN
accretion rate and resulting feedback power. We find that a larger accretion
zone results in steadier jets but can also allow too much cold-gas condensation
in simulations with a Bondi-like triggering algorithm. We also vary the opening
angle of jet precession and find that a larger precession angle causes more of
the jet energy to thermalize closer to the AGN, thereby producing results
similar to pure thermal feedback. Our simulations confirm that AGN can regulate
the thermal state of cool-core galaxy clusters and maintain the core in a state
that is marginally susceptable to thermal instability and precipitation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00062</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00062</id><created>2016-04-30</created><updated>2017-01-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Teng</keyname><forenames>Peiyuan</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalization of the tensor renormalization group approach to 3-D or
  higher dimensions</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>31 pages, 23 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physica A 472 (2017) 117-135</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physa.2016.12.080</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, a way of generalizing the tensor renormalization group(TRG) is
proposed. Mathematically, the connection between patterns of tensor
renormalization group and the concept of truncation sequence in polytope
geometry is discovered. A theoretical contraction framework is therefore
proposed. Furthermore, the canonical polyadic decomposition is introduced to
tensor network theory. A lowest order numerical verification of this method on
the 3-D Ising model is carried out.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01322</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01322</id><created>2016-06-03</created><updated>2017-05-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Zhiyong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Jingfeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferry</keyname><forenames>David K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ducharme</keyname><forenames>Stephen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hong</keyname><forenames>Xia</forenames></author></authors><title>Ferroelectric Domain Patterning Controlled Schottky Junction State in
  Monolayer MoS$_2$</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>18 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 236801 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.236801</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We exploit scanning probe controlled domain patterning in a ferroelectric top
layer to induce nonvolatile modulation of the conduction characteristic of
monolayer MoS$_2$ between a transistor and a junction state. In the presence of
a domain wall, MoS$_2$ exhibits rectified I-V that is well described by the
thermionic emission model. The induced Schottky barrier height varies from 0.38
eV to 0.57 eV and is tunabe by a SiO$_2$ global back-gate, while the tuning
range of depends sensitively on the conduction band tail trapping states. Our
work points to a new route to achieving programmable functionalities in van der
Waals materials and sheds light on the critical performance limiting factors in
these hybrid systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.04303</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.04303</id><created>2016-06-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Bleher</keyname><forenames>Pavel M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dea&#xf1;o</keyname><forenames>Alfredo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yattselev</keyname><forenames>Maxim</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological Expansion in the Complex Cubic Log-Gas Model. One-Cut Case</title><categories>math-ph math.CA math.MP</categories><comments>37 pages, 14 figures</comments><msc-class>33C47, 30E15, 31A25, 15B52</msc-class><journal-ref>J. Statist. Phys., 166(3-4), 784-827 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10955-016-1621-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove the topological expansion for the cubic log-gas partition function
\[ Z_N(t)= \int_\Gamma\cdots\int_\Gamma\prod_{1\leq j&lt;k\leq N}(z_j-z_k)^2
\prod_{k=1}^Ne^{-N\left(-\frac{z^3}{3}+tz\right)}\mathrm dz_1\cdots \mathrm
dz_N, \] where $t$ is a complex parameter and $\Gamma$ is an unbounded contour
on the complex plane extending from $e^{\pi \mathrm i}\infty$ to $e^{\pi
\mathrm i/3}\infty$. The complex cubic log-gas model exhibits two phase regions
on the complex $t$-plane, with one cut and two cuts, separated by analytic
critical arcs of the two types of phase transition: split of a cut and birth of
a cut. The common point of the critical arcs is a tricritical point of the
Painlev\'e I type. In the present paper we prove the topological expansion for
$\log Z_N(t)$ in the one-cut phase region. The proof is based on the
Riemann--Hilbert approach to semiclassical asymptotic expansions for the
associated orthogonal polynomials and the theory of $S$-curves and quadratic
differentials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.04454</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.04454</id><created>2016-06-14</created><updated>2017-04-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cogswell</keyname><forenames>Daniel A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szulczewski</keyname><forenames>Michael L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Simulation of incompressible two-phase flow in porous media with large
  timesteps</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>12 pages, 7 figures, 2 tables</comments><doi>10.1016/j.jcp.2017.06.007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Multiphase flow in porous media occurs in several disciplines including
petroleum reservoir engineering, petroleum systems' analysis, and CO$_2$
sequestration. While simulations often use a fully implicit discretization to
increase the time step size, restrictions on the time step often exist due to
non-convergence of the nonlinear solver (e.g. Newton's method). Here this
problem is addressed for the Buckley-Leverett equations, which model
incompressible, immiscible, two-phase flow with no capillary potential. The
equations are recast as a gradient flow using the phase-field method, and a
convex energy splitting scheme is applied to enable large timesteps, even for
high degrees of heterogeneity in permeability and viscosity. By using the
phase-field formulation as a homotopy map, the underlying hyperbolic flow
equations can be solved with large timesteps. For a heterogeneous test problem,
the new homotopy method allows the timestep to be increased by more than six
orders of magnitude relative to the unmodified equations while maintaining
convergence.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02465</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02465</id><created>2016-07-08</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Misguich</keyname><forenames>Gr&#xe9;goire</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pasquier</keyname><forenames>Vincent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oshikawa</keyname><forenames>Masaki</forenames></author></authors><title>Finite-size scaling of the Shannon-R\'enyi entropy in two-dimensional
  systems with spontaneously broken continuous symmetry</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>15 pages, 3 figures, v2: published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 195161 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.195161</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the scaling of the (basis dependent) Shannon entropy for
two-dimensional quantum antiferromagnets with N\'eel long-range order. We use a
massless free-field description of the gapless spin wave modes and phase space
arguments to treat the fact that the finite-size ground state is rotationally
symmetric, while there are degenerate physical ground states which break the
symmetry. Our results show that the Shannon entropy (and its R\'enyi
generalizations) possesses some universal logarithmic term proportional to the
number $N_\text{NG}$ of Nambu-Goldstone modes. In the case of a torus, we show
that $S_{n&gt;1} \simeq {\rm const.} N+ \frac{N_\text{NG}}{4}\frac{n}{n-1} \ln{N}$
and $S_1 \simeq {\rm const.} N - \frac{N_\text{NG}}{4} \ln{N}$, where $N$ is
the total number of sites and $n$ the R\'enyi index. The result for $n&gt;1$ is in
reasonable agreement with the quantum Monte Carlo results of Luitz et al.
[Phys. Rev. Lett. 112, 057203 (2014)], and qualitatively similar to those
obtained previously for the entanglement entropy. The Shannon entropy of a line
subsystem (embedded in the two-dimensional system) is also considered. Finally,
we present some density-matrix renormalization group (DMRG) calculations for a
spin$\frac{1}{2}$ XY model on the square lattice in a cylinder geometry. These
numerical data confirm our findings for logarithmic terms in the $n=\infty$
R\'enyi entropy (also called $-\ln{p_{\rm max}}$). They also reveal some
universal dependence on the cylinder aspect ratio, in good agreement with the
fact that, in that case, $p_{\rm max}$ is related to a non-compact free-boson
partition function in dimension 1+1.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03563</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03563</id><created>2016-07-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Y. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adhikari</keyname><forenames>R. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yazici</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jeon</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maple</keyname><forenames>M. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dzero</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Almasan</keyname><forenames>Carmen C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiband superconductivity in the correlated electron filled
  skutterudite system Pr(1-x)Ce(x)Pt4Ge12</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>6 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 94, 144502 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.144502</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Studies of superconductivity in multiband correlated electronic systems has
become one of the central topics in condensed matter/materials physics. In this
paper, we present the results of thermodynamic measurements on the
superconducting filled skutterudite system Pr$_{1-x}$Ce$_x$Pt$_4$Ge$_{12}$ ($ 0
\leq x \leq 0.2$) to investigate how substitution of Ce at Pr sites affects
superconductivity. We find that an increase in Ce concentration leads to a
suppression of the superconducting transition temperature from $T_{c}\sim 7.9$
K for $x=0$ to $T_c\sim 0.6$ K for $x=0.14$. Our analysis of the specific heat
data for $x\leq 0.07$ reveals that superconductivity must develop in at least
two bands: the superconducting order parameter has nodes on one Fermi pocket
and remains fully gapped on the other. Both the nodal and nodeless gap values
decrease, with the nodal gap being suppressed more strongly, with Ce
substitution. Ultimately, the higher Ce concentration samples ($x&gt;0.07$)
display a nodeless gap only.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01263</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01263</id><created>2016-08-03</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lewis</keyname><forenames>Antony</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pratten</keyname><forenames>Geraint</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of lensing non-Gaussianity on the CMB power spectra</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures. Minor update to JCAP version, correcting sign of
  Omega term in Eq 2.7 and hence the sign of the correlation bispectrum (with
  very small effect on numerical result)</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 12 (2016) 003</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/12/003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Observed CMB anisotropies are lensed, and the lensed power spectra can be
calculated accurately assuming the lensing deflections are Gaussian. However,
the lensing deflections are actually slightly non-Gaussian due to both
non-linear large-scale structure growth and post-Born corrections. We calculate
the leading correction to the lensed CMB power spectra from the
non-Gaussianity, which is determined by the lensing bispectrum. The
lowest-order result gives $\sim 0.3\%$ corrections to the BB and EE
polarization spectra on small-scales, however we show that the effect on EE is
reduced by about a factor of two by higher-order Gaussian lensing smoothing,
rendering the total effect safely negligible for the foreseeable future. We
give a simple analytic model for the signal expected from skewness of the
large-scale lensing field; the effect is similar to a net demagnification and
hence a small change in acoustic scale (and therefore out of phase with the
dominant lensing smoothing that predominantly affects the peaks and troughs of
the power spectrum).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.02860</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.02860</id><created>2016-08-09</created><updated>2017-05-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wanner</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eckern</keyname><forenames>Ulrich</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xf6;ck</keyname><forenames>Karl-Heinz</forenames></author></authors><title>Theory of invariants-based formulation of ${\bf k}\cdot{\bf p}$
  Hamiltonians with application to strained zinc-blende crystals</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>17 pages (preprint style)</comments><journal-ref>Ann. Phys. (Berlin) 529, 1600218 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/andp.201600218</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Group theoretical methods and ${\bf k}\cdot{\bf p}$ theory are combined to
determine spin-dependent contributions to the effective conduction band
Hamiltonian. To obtain the constants in the effective Hamiltonian, in general
all invariants of the Hamiltonian have to be determined. Hence, we present a
systematic approach to keep track of all possible invariants and apply it to
the ${\bf k}\cdot{\bf p}$ Hamiltonian of crystals with zinc-blende symmetry, in
order to obtain all possible contributions to effective quantities such as
effective mass, g-factor and Dresselhaus constant. Further spin-dependent
contributions to the effective Hamiltonian arise in the presence of strain. In
particular, with regard to the constants $C_3$ and $D$ which describe
spin-splitting linear in the components of ${\bf k}$ and
${\boldsymbol\varepsilon}$, considering all possible terms allowed by symmetry
is crucial.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03485</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03485</id><created>2016-08-11</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zizhu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Sukhwinder</forenames></author><author><keyname>Navascu&#xe9;s</keyname><forenames>Miguel</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement and Nonlocality in Infinite 1D Systems</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>Added a few references to related work. Closer to the published
  version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 230401 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.230401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the problem of detecting entanglement and nonlocality in
one-dimensional (1D) infinite, translation-invariant (TI) systems when just
near-neighbor information is available. This issue is deeper than one might
think a priori, since, as we show, there exist instances of local separable
states (classical boxes) which admit only entangled (nonclassical) TI
extensions. We provide a simple characterization of the set of local states of
multiseparable TI spin chains and construct a family of linear witnesses which
can detect entanglement in infinite TI states from the nearest-neighbor reduced
density matrix. Similarly, we prove that the set of classical TI boxes forms a
polytope and devise a general procedure to generate all Bell inequalities which
characterize it. Using an algorithm based on matrix product states, we show how
some of them can be violated by distant parties conducting identical
measurements on an infinite TI quantum state. All our results can be easily
adapted to detect entanglement and nonlocality in large (finite, not TI) 1D
condensed matter systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03568</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03568</id><created>2016-08-11</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Jing-Yuan</forenames></author></authors><title>Berry Phase Physics in Free and Interacting Fermionic Systems</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el hep-th</categories><comments>PhD Thesis, viii+175 pages. Sections 2&amp;3 are based on the literature
  and the author's original works 1404.5963 and 1502.06966. Section 4 contains
  substantial overlap with the author's original work 1604.07857</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Berry phase plays an important role in many non-trivial phenomena over a
broad range of many-body systems. In this thesis we focus on the Berry phase
due to the change of the particles' momenta, and study its effects in free and
interacting fermionic systems. We start with reviewing the semi-classical
kinetic theory with Berry phase for a non-interacting ensemble of fermions -- a
Berry Fermi gas -- which might be far-from-equilibrium. We particularly review
the famous Berry phase contribution to the anomalous Hall current. We then
provide a concrete and general path integral derivation for the semi-classical
theory. Then we turn to the specific example of Weyl fermion, which exhibits
the profound quantum phenomenon of chiral anomaly; we review how this quantum
effect, and its closely related chiral magnetic effect and chiral vortical
effect, arise from Berry phase in the semi-classical kinetic theory. We also
discuss how Lorentz symmetry in the kinetic theory of Weyl fermion, seemly
violated by the Berry phase term, is realized non-trivially; we provide a
physical interpretation for this non-trivial realization, and discuss its
mathematical foundation in Wigner translation. Next, we turn towards
interacting fermionic systems. We consider Fermi liquid near equilibrium, and
propose the Berry Fermi liquid theory -- the extension to Landau Fermi liquid
theory incorporating Berry phase (and other) effects. In our proposed Berry
Fermi liquid theory, we can show the Berry phase is a Fermi surface property,
qualitatively unmodified by interactions. But there also arise new effects from
interactions, most notably the emergent electric dipole moment which
contributes to the anomalous Hall current in addition to the usual Berry phase
contribution. We prove our proposed Berry Fermi liquid theory from quantum
field theory to all orders in Feynman diagram expansion under very general
assumptions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05034</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05034</id><created>2016-08-17</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ducuara</keyname><forenames>Andr&#xe9;s F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Susa</keyname><forenames>Cristian E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reina</keyname><forenames>John H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Not-Post-Peierls compatibility under noisy channels</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 50 265302 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa72fb</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Pusey-Barrett-Rudolph (PBR) theorem deals with the realism of the quantum
states. It establishes that every pure quantum state is real, in the context of
quantum ontological models. Specifically, by guaranteeing the property of
not-Post-Peierls ($\neg$PP) compatibility (or antidistinguishability) for a
particular set of states $P$, together with the ad hoc postulate known as
Preparation Independence Postulate (PIP), the theorem establishes that these
two properties imply the $\psi$-onticity (realism) of the set of all pure
states. This PBR result has triggered two particular lines of research: On the
one hand, it has been possible to derive similar results without the use of the
PIP, although at the expense of implying weaker properties than
$\psi$-onticity. On the other hand, it has also been proven that the property
of $\neg$PP compatibility alone is an explicit witness of usefulness for the
task known as conclusive exclusion of states. In this work, we explore the
$\neg$PP compatibility of the set of states $P$, when $P$ is under the
interaction of some noisy channels, which would consequently let us identify
some noisy scenarios where it is still possible to perform the task of
conclusive exclusion of states. Specifically, we consider the set $P$ of
$n$-qubit states in interaction with an environment by means of i) individual
and ii) collective couplings. In both cases, we analytically show that the
phenomenon of achieving $\neg$PP compatibility, although reduced, it is still
present. Searching for an optimisation of this phenomenon, we report numerical
experiments up to $n=4$ qubits.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00103</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00103</id><created>2016-09-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>Arnab</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Jiaqiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knolle</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bridges</keyname><forenames>Craig A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stone</keyname><forenames>Matthew B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lumsden</keyname><forenames>Mark D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mandrus</keyname><forenames>David G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tennant</keyname><forenames>David A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moessner</keyname><forenames>Roderich</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nagler</keyname><forenames>Stephen E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Neutron tomography of magnetic Majorana fermions in a proximate quantum
  spin liquid</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>10 pages main text with 4 main figures, 13 Supplementary pages with 9
  figures</comments><journal-ref>Science 356 (6342), 1055-1059 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1126/science.aah6015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum matter provides an effective vacuum out of which arise emergent
particles not corresponding to any experimentally detected elementary particle.
Topological quantum materials in particular have become a focus of intense
research in part because of the remarkable possibility to realize Majorana
fermions, with their potential for new, decoherence-free quantum computing
architectures. In this paper we undertake a study on high-quality single
crystal of $\alpha-RuCl_3$ which has been identified as a material realizing a
proximate Kitaev state, a topological quantum state with magnetic Majorana
fermions. Four-dimensional tomographic reconstruction of dynamical correlations
measured using neutrons is uniquely powerful for probing such magnetic states.
We discover unusual signals, including an unprecedented column of scattering
over a large energy interval around the Brillouin zone center which is
remarkably stable with temperature. This is straightforwardly accounted for in
terms of the Majorana excitations present in Kitaev's topological quantum spin
liquid. Other, more delicate, features in the scattering can be transparently
associated with perturbations to an ideal model. This opens a window on
emergent magnetic Majorana fermions in correlated materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02054</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02054</id><created>2016-09-07</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chakhmakhchyan</keyname><forenames>Levon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teles</keyname><forenames>Tarcisio N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruffo</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>Ensemble inequivalence and absence of quasi-stationary states in
  long-range random networks</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures. Updated version for publication</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. 063204 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/aa73f1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ensemble inequivalence has been previously displayed only for long-range
interacting systems with non-extensive energy. In order to perform the
thermodynamic limit, such systems require an unphysical, so-called, Kac
rescaling of the coupling constant. We here study models defined on long-range
random networks, which avoid such a rescaling. The proposed models have an
extensive energy, which is however non-additive. For such long-range random
networks, pairs of sites are coupled with a probability decaying with the
distance $r$ as $1/r^\delta$. In one dimension and with $0 \leq \delta &lt;1$,
surface energy scales linearly with the network size, while for $\delta &gt;1$ it
is $O(1)$. By performing numerical simulations, we show that a negative
specific heat region is present in the microcanonical ensemble of a Blume-Capel
model, in correspondence with a first-order phase transition in the canonical
one. This proves that ensemble inequivalence is a consequence of
$non$-$additivity$ rather than $non$-$extensivity$. Moreover, since a
mean-field coupling is absent in such networks, relaxation to equilibrium takes
place on an intensive time scale and quasi-stationary states are absent.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04619</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04619</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Virtanen</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heikkil&#xe4;</keyname><forenames>T. T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin pumping and torque statistics in the quantum noise limit</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 237701 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.237701</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the statistics of charge and energy currents and spin torque in a
metallic nanomagnet coupled to a large magnetic metal via a tunnel contact. We
derive a Keldysh action for the tunnel barrier, describing the stochastic
currents in the presence of a magnetization precessing with the rate $\Omega$.
In contrast to some earlier approaches, we include the geometric phases that
affect the counting statistics. We illustrate the use of the action by deriving
spintronic fluctuation relations, the quantum limit of pumped current noise,
and consider the fluctuations in two specific cases: the situation with a
stable precession of magnetization driven by spin transfer torque, and the
torque-induced switching between the minima of a magnetic anisotropy. The
quantum corrections are relevant when the precession rate exceeds the
temperature $T$, i.e., for $\hbar \Omega \gtrsim k_B T$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05970</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05970</id><created>2016-09-19</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shiozaki</keyname><forenames>Ken</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shapourian</keyname><forenames>Hassan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ryu</keyname><forenames>Shinsei</forenames></author></authors><title>Many-body topological invariants in fermionic symmetry protected
  topological phases: Cases of point group symmetries</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el hep-th</categories><comments>60 pages, 15 figures, final version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 205139 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.205139</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose the definitions of many-body topological invariants to detect
symmetry-protected topological phases protected by point group symmetry, using
partial point group transformations on a given short-range entangled quantum
ground state. Partial point group transformations $g_D$ are defined by point
group transformations restricted to a spatial subregion $D$, which is closed
under the point group transformations and sufficiently larger than the bulk
correlation length $\xi$. By analytical and numerical calculations,we find that
the ground state expectation value of the partial point group transformations
behaves generically as $\langle GS | g_D | GS \rangle \sim \exp \Big[ i \theta+
\gamma - \alpha \frac{{\rm Area}(\partial D)}{\xi^{d-1}} \Big]$. Here, ${\rm
Area}(\partial D)$ is the area of the boundary of the subregion $D$, and
$\alpha$ is a dimensionless constant. The complex phase of the expectation
value $\theta$ is quantized and serves as the topological invariant, and
$\gamma$ is a scale-independent topological contribution to the amplitude. The
examples we consider include the $\mathbb{Z}_8$ and $\mathbb{Z}_{16}$
invariants of topological superconductors protected by inversion symmetry in
$(1+1)$ and $(3+1)$ dimensions, respectively, and the lens space topological
invariants in $(2+1)$-dimensional fermionic topological phases. Connections to
topological quantum field theories and cobordism classification of
symmetry-protected topological phases are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.06411</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.06411</id><created>2016-09-20</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kovalev</keyname><forenames>V. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Savenko</keyname><forenames>I. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Paramagnetic resonance in spin-polarized disordered Bose-Einstein
  condensates</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Manuscript: 6 pages, 2x2 figures, published in Scientific Reports 7,
  2076 (2017)</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, 2076 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-01125-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the pseudo-spin density response of a disordered two-dimensional
spin-polarized Bose gas of exciton polaritons to weak alternating magnetic
field, assuming that one of the spin states of the doublet is macroscopically
occupied and Bose-condensed while the occupation of the other state remains
much smaller. We calculate spatial and temporal dispersions of spin
susceptibility of the gas taking into account spin-flip processes due to the
transverse-longitudinal splitting. Further, we use the Bogoliubov theory of
weakly-interacting gases and show that the time-dependent magnetic field power
absorption exhibits double resonance structure corresponding to two particle
spin states (contrast to paramagnetic resonance in regular spin-polarized
electron gas). We analyze the widths of these resonances caused by scattering
on the disorder and show that, in contrast with the ballistic regime, in the
presence of impurities, the polariton scattering on them is twofold: scattering
on the impurity potential directly and scattering on the spatially fluctuating
condensate density caused by the disorder. As a result, the width of the
resonance associated with the Bose-condensed spin state can be surprizingly
narrow in comparison with the width of the resonance associated with the
non-condensed state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03438</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03438</id><created>2016-10-11</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vool</keyname><forenames>Uri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Devoret</keyname><forenames>Michel H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Introduction to Quantum Electromagnetic Circuits</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>59 pages, 14 figures. IJCTA - Special Issue on Quantum Circuits</comments><doi>10.1002/cta.2359</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The article is a short opinionated review of the quantum treatment of
electromagnetic circuits, with no pretension to exhaustiveness. This review,
which is an updated and modernized version of a previous set of Les Houches
School lecture notes, has 3 main parts. The first part describes how to
construct a Hamiltonian for a general circuit, which can include dissipative
elements. The second part describes the quantization of the circuit, with an
emphasis on the quantum treatment of dissipation. The final part focuses on the
Josephson non-linear element and the main linear building blocks from which
superconducting circuits are assembled. It also includes a brief review of the
main types of superconducting artificial atoms, elementary multi-level quantum
systems made from basic circuit elements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05473</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05473</id><created>2016-10-18</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Savenko</keyname><forenames>I. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flayac</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liew</keyname><forenames>T. C. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multivalley engineering in semiconductor microcavities</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Manuscript: 7 pages, 7 figures, published in Scientific Reports 7,
  45243 (2017)</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, 45243 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep45243</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider exciton-photon coupling in semiconductor microcavities in which
separate periodic potentials have been embedded for excitons and photons. We
show theoretically that this system supports degenerate ground-states appearing
at non-zero in-plane momenta, corresponding to multiple valleys in reciprocal
space, which are further separated in polarization corresponding to a
polarization-valley coupling in the system. Aside forming a basis for
valleytronics, the multivalley dispersion is predicted to allow for spontaneous
momentum symmetry breaking and two-mode squeezing under non-resonant and
resonant excitation, respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.06094</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.06094</id><created>2016-10-19</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Johnston</keyname><forenames>Nathaniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kirkland</keyname><forenames>Steve</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plosker</keyname><forenames>Sarah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Storey</keyname><forenames>Rebecca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xiaohong</forenames></author></authors><title>Perfect quantum state transfer using Hadamard diagonalizable graphs</title><categories>quant-ph math.CO</categories><comments>29 pages, 1 figure, minor revisions, fixed typos</comments><msc-class>05C50, 05C76, 15A18, 81P45</msc-class><doi>10.1016/j.laa.2017.05.037</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum state transfer within a quantum computer can be achieved by using a
network of qubits, and such a network can be modelled mathematically by a
graph. Here, we focus on the corresponding Laplacian matrix, and those graphs
for which the Laplacian can be diagonalized by a Hadamard matrix. We give a
simple eigenvalue characterization for when such a graph has perfect state
transfer at time $\pi /2$; this characterization allows one to choose the
correct eigenvalues to build graphs having perfect state transfer. We
characterize the graphs that are diagonalizable by the standard Hadamard
matrix, showing a direct relationship to cubelike graphs. We then give a number
of constructions producing a wide variety of new graphs that exhibit perfect
state transfer, and we consider several corollaries in the settings of both
weighted and unweighted graphs, as well as how our results relate to the notion
of pretty good state transfer. Finally, we give an optimality result, showing
that among regular graphs of degree at most $4$, the hypercube is the sparsest
Hadamard diagonalizable connected unweighted graph with perfect state transfer.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08773</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08773</id><created>2016-10-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Banszerus</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Janssen</keyname><forenames>Hendrik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Otto</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Epping</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taniguchi</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>Kenji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beschoten</keyname><forenames>Bernd</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neumaier</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stampfer</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author></authors><title>Identifying suitable substrates for high-quality graphene-based
  heterostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>2D Materials, Volume 4, 025030 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2053-1583/aa5b0f</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on a scanning confocal Raman spectroscopy study investigating the
strain-uniformity and the overall strain and doping of high-quality chemical
vapour deposited (CVD) graphene-based heterostuctures on a large number of
different substrate materials, including hexagonal boron nitride (hBN),
transition metal dichalcogenides, silicon, different oxides and nitrides, as
well as polymers. By applying a hBN-assisted, contamination free, dry transfer
process for CVD graphene, high-quality heterostructures with low doping
densities and low strain variations are assembled. The Raman spectra of these
pristine heterostructures are sensitive to substrate-induced doping and strain
variations and are thus used to probe the suitability of the substrate material
for potential high-quality graphene devices. We find that the flatness of the
substrate material is a key figure for gaining, or preserving high-quality
graphene.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.00396</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.00396</id><created>2016-11-01</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ashida</keyname><forenames>Yuto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Furukawa</keyname><forenames>Shunsuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ueda</keyname><forenames>Masahito</forenames></author></authors><title>Parity-time-symmetric quantum critical phenomena</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.quant-gas physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>6+10 pages, 4+4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 8, 15791 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms15791</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Synthetic nonconservative systems with parity-time (PT) symmetric gain-loss
structures can exhibit unusual spontaneous symmetry breaking that accompanies
spectral singularity. Recent studies on PT symmetry in optics and weakly
interacting open quantum systems have revealed intriguing physical properties,
yet many-body correlations still play no role. Here by extending the idea of PT
symmetry to strongly correlated many-body systems, we report that a combination
of spectral singularity and quantum criticality yields an exotic universality
class which has no counterpart in known critical phenomena. Moreover, we find
unconventional low-dimensional quantum criticality, where superfluid
correlation is anomalously enhanced owing to non-monotonic renormalization
group flows in a PT-symmetry-broken quantum critical phase, in stark contrast
to the Berezinskii-Kosterlitz-Thouless paradigm. Our findings can be
experimentally tested in ultracold atoms and predict critical phenomena beyond
the Hermitian paradigm of quantum many-body physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.01134</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.01134</id><created>2016-11-03</created><updated>2017-03-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rycerz</keyname><forenames>Adam</forenames></author></authors><title>Pairwise entanglement and the Mott transition for correlated electrons
  in nanochains</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>Minor revisions, typos corrected. RevTeX, 12 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19, 053025 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa6bdd</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Pairwise entanglement, calculated separately for charge and spin degrees of
freedom, is proposed as a ground-state signature of the Mott transition in
correlated nanoscopic systems. Utilizing the exact diagonalization - ab initio
method (EDABI), for chains containing $N\leqslant{}16$ hydrogenic-like atoms
(at the half filling), we find that the vanishing of the nearest-neighbor
charge concurrence indicates the crossover from a partly-localized quantum
liquid to the Mott insulator. Spin concurrence remains nonzero at the
insulating phase, showing that the decopling of spin and charge degrees of
freedom may manifest itself by wavefunctions entangled in spin, but separable
in charge coordinates. At the quarter filling, the analysis for
$N\leqslant{}20$ shows that spin concurrence vanishes immediately when the
charge-energy gap obtained from the scaling with $1/N\rightarrow{}0$ vanishes,
constituting a finite-system version of the Mott transition. Analytic
derivations of the formulas expressing either charge or spin concurrence in
terms of ground-state correlation functions are also provided.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03795</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03795</id><created>2016-11-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Mohler</keyname><forenames>Kathrin J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bohn</keyname><forenames>Bernhard J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xe4;nsch</keyname><forenames>Theodor W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Picqu&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Nathalie</forenames></author></authors><title>Dual-Comb Coherent Raman Spectroscopy with Lasers of 1-GHz Pulse
  Repetition Frequency</title><categories>physics.optics physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Optics Letters 42, 318-321 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.42.000318</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We extend the technique of multiplex coherent Raman spectroscopy with two
femtosecond mode-locked lasers to oscillators of a pulse repetition frequency
of 1 GHz. We demonstrate spectra of liquids, which span 1100 cm$^{-1}$ of Raman
shifts. At a resolution of 6 cm$^{-1}$, their measurement time may be as short
as 5 microseconds for a refresh rate of 2 kHz. The waiting period between
acquisitions is improved ten-fold compared to previous experiments with two
lasers of 100-MHz repetition frequencies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03886</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03886</id><created>2016-10-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Tommasini</keyname><forenames>Mirko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kirillov</keyname><forenames>Oleg N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Misseroni</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bigoni</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author></authors><title>The destabilizing effect of external damping: Singular flutter boundary
  for the Pfluger column with vanishing external dissipation</title><categories>physics.class-ph math.DS</categories><comments>19 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of the Mechanics and Physics of Solids (2016) 91: 204-215</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jmps.2016.03.011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Elastic structures loaded by nonconservative positional forces are prone to
instabilities induced by dissipation: it is well-known in fact that internal
viscous damping destabilizes the marginally stable Ziegler's pendulum and
Pfluger column (of which the Beck's column is a special case), two structures
loaded by a tangential follower force. The result is the so-called
'destabilization paradox', where the critical force for flutter instability
decreases by an order of magnitude when the coefficient of internal damping
becomes infinitesimally small. Until now external damping, such as that related
to air drag, is believed to provide only a stabilizing effect, as one would
intuitively expect. Contrary to this belief, it will be shown that the effect
of external damping is qualitatively the same as the effect of internal
damping, yielding a pronounced destabilization paradox. Previous results
relative to destabilization by external damping of the Ziegler's and Pfluger's
elastic structures are corrected in a definitive way leading to a new
understanding of the destabilizating role played by viscous terms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.07846</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.07846</id><created>2016-11-15</created><updated>2017-03-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>J. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alonso-Lanza</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delgado</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aguilera-Granja</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ayuela</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-Collinearity in Small Magnetic Cobalt-Benzene Molecules</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics 19, 14854 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C7CP00992E</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Organometallic clusters based on transition metal atoms are interesting
because possible applications in spintronics and quantum information. In
addition to the enhanced magnetism at the nanoscale, the organic ligands may
provide a natural shield again unwanted magnetic interactions with the matrices
required for applications. Here we show that the organic ligands may lead to
non-collinear magnetic order as well as the expected quenching of the magnetic
moments. We use different density functional theory (DFT) methods to study the
experimentally relevant three cobalt atoms surrounded by benzene rings
(Co$_3$Bz$_3$). We found that the benzene rings induce a ground state with
non-collinear magnetization, with the magnetic moments localized on the cobalt
centers and lying on the plane formed by the three cobalt atoms. We further
analyze the magnetism of such a cluster using an anisotropic Heisenberg model
where the involved parameters are obtained by a comparison with the DFT
results. These results may also explain the recent observation of null magnetic
moment of Co$_3$Bz$_3^+$. Moreover, we propose an additional experimental
verification based on electron paramagnetic resonance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02504</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02504</id><created>2016-12-07</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fujita</keyname><forenames>Ryuichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Isoyama</keyname><forenames>Soichiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tiec</keyname><forenames>Alexandre Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakano</keyname><forenames>Hiroyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sago</keyname><forenames>Norichika</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanaka</keyname><forenames>Takahiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Hamiltonian Formulation of the Conservative Self-Force Dynamics in the
  Kerr Geometry</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>55 pages, 0 figures, matches the published version</comments><report-no>KUNS-2648,YITP-16-122</report-no><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 34 134001 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6382/aa7342</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We formulate a Hamiltonian description of the orbital motion of a point
particle in Kerr spacetime for generic (eccentric, inclined) orbits, which
accounts for the effects of the conservative part of the gravitational
self-force. This formulation relies on a description of the particle's motion
as geodesic in a certain smooth effective spacetime, in terms of (generalized)
action-angle variables. Clarifying the role played by the gauge freedom in the
Hamiltonian dynamics, we extract the gauge-invariant information contained in
the conservative self-force. We also propose a possible gauge choice for which
the orbital dynamics can be described by an effective Hamiltonian, written
solely in terms of the action variables. As an application of our Hamiltonian
formulation in this gauge, we derive the conservative self-force correction to
the orbital frequencies of Kerr innermost stable spherical (inclined or
circular) orbits. This gauge choice also allows us to establish a &quot;first law of
mechanics&quot; for black-hole-particle binary systems, at leading order beyond the
test-mass approximation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03201</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03201</id><created>2016-12-03</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Changbiao</forenames></author></authors><title>Disproof of a widely-accepted mathematical conjecture</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><comments>This arXiv copy of manuscript is the final version submitted to Optik
  for production. In the Optik produced copy
  (http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijleo.2017.05.003), there are quite a few typos
  in math formulas after copyedited, somehow with author's proof corrections
  not considered. 4 papers, no figures, 8 references</comments><msc-class>78A25, 83</msc-class><journal-ref>Optik 140 (2017) 1110-1113</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ijleo.2017.05.003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A mathematical conjecture is successfully identified, which is used for
relativistic analysis of dielectric Einstein-box thought experiment in a Letter
(Ramos, Rubilar, and Obukhov, Phys. Lett. A 375, 1703 (2011)), where the
authors conjecture (without any citations) that, the symmetry and
divergence-less property of a Lorentz 4-tensor is a sufficient condition for
the time-column space integrals to constitute a Lorentz 4-vector. This
mathematical conjecture has been thought to be &quot;a mathematical fact the
validity of which was shown well&quot; in textbooks. However in this paper, we
indicate that this conjecture has never been proved mathematically. By
enumerating a counterexample, we find that this mathematical conjecture is
flawed, and it is not persuasive to use a flawed mathematical conjecture as a
starting point to resolve Abraham-Minkowski controversy over light momentum in
a dielectric medium. We also indicate that this flawed mathematical conjecture
is actually a widely-accepted conjecture in the dynamics of relativity in
textbooks for many decades. To eliminate a misunderstanding of this flawed
conjecture in the community, we provide a detailed elucidation of why
M{\o}ller's mathematical statement, also called &quot;M{\o}ller's version of von
Laue's theorem&quot;, only defines a trivial zero 4-vector for an electromagnetic
stress-energy Lorentz 4-tensor.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03954</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03954</id><created>2016-12-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Dean</keyname><forenames>David S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Doussal</keyname><forenames>Pierre Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Majumdar</keyname><forenames>Satya N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schehr</keyname><forenames>Gregory</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistics of the maximal distance and momentum in a trapped Fermi gas
  at low temperature</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.quant-gas math-ph math.MP math.PR</categories><comments>28 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2017) 063301</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/aa6dda</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider $N$ non-interacting fermions in an isotropic $d$-dimensional
harmonic trap. We compute analytically the cumulative distribution of the
maximal radial distance of the fermions from the trap center at zero
temperature. While in $d=1$ the limiting distribution (in the large $N$ limit),
properly centered and scaled, converges to the squared Tracy-Widom distribution
of the Gaussian Unitary Ensemble in Random Matrix Theory, we show that for all
$d&gt;1$, the limiting distribution converges to the Gumbel law. These limiting
forms turn out to be universal, i.e., independent of the details of the
trapping potential for a large class of isotropic trapping potentials. We also
study the position of the right-most fermion in a given direction in $d$
dimensions and, in the case of a harmonic trap, the maximum momentum, and show
that they obey similar Gumbel statistics. Finally, we generalize these results
to low but finite temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.06396</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.06396</id><created>2016-12-19</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pugh</keyname><forenames>Christopher J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaiser</keyname><forenames>Sarah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bourgoin</keyname><forenames>Jean-Philippe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Jeongwan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sultana</keyname><forenames>Nigar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agne</keyname><forenames>Sascha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anisimova</keyname><forenames>Elena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Makarov</keyname><forenames>Vadim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Higgins</keyname><forenames>Brendon L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jennewein</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Airborne demonstration of a quantum key distribution receiver payload</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 5 figures, Updated pointing figures, Added references</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Science and Technology, 2, 2, 024009 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2058-9565/aa701f</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Satellite-based quantum terminals are a feasible way to extend the reach of
quantum communication protocols such as quantum key distribution (QKD) to the
global scale. To that end, prior demonstrations have shown QKD transmissions
from airborne platforms to receivers on ground, but none have shown QKD
transmissions from ground to a moving aircraft, the latter scenario having
simplicity and flexibility advantages for a hypothetical satellite. Here, we
demonstrate QKD from a ground transmitter to a receiver prototype mounted on an
airplane in flight. We have specifically designed our receiver prototype to
consist of many components that are compatible with the environment and
resource constraints of a satellite. Coupled with our relocatable ground
station system, optical links with distances of 3-10 km were maintained and
quantum signals transmitted while traversing angular rates similar to those
observed of low-Earth-orbit satellites. For some passes of the aircraft over
the ground station, links were established within 10 s of position data
transmission, and with link times of a few minutes and received quantum bit
error rates typically 3-5%, we generated secure keys up to 868 kb in length. By
successfully generating secure keys over several different pass configurations,
we demonstrate the viability of technology that constitutes a quantum receiver
satellite payload and provide a blueprint for future satellite missions to
build upon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07127</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07127</id><created>2016-12-21</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Michimura</keyname><forenames>Yuta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuwahara</keyname><forenames>Yuya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ushiba</keyname><forenames>Takafumi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsumoto</keyname><forenames>Nobuyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ando</keyname><forenames>Masaki</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical Levitation of a Mirror for Reaching the Standard Quantum Limit</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Optics Express 25, 13799 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.25.013799</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a new method to optically levitate a macroscopic mirror with two
vertical Fabry-P{\'e}rot cavities linearly aligned. This configuration gives
the simplest possible optical levitation in which the number of laser beams
used is the minimum of two. We demonstrate that reaching the standard quantum
limit (SQL) of a displacement measurement with our system is feasible with
current technology. The cavity geometry and the levitated mirror parameters are
designed to ensure that the Brownian vibration of the mirror surface is smaller
than the SQL. Our scheme provides a promising tool for testing macroscopic
quantum mechanics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08790</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08790</id><created>2016-12-27</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hwang</keyname><forenames>Sungmin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Su-Chan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krug</keyname><forenames>Joachim</forenames></author></authors><title>Genotypic complexity of Fisher's geometric model</title><categories>q-bio.PE cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>27 pages, 14 figures, 2 tables, minor changes (published version)</comments><journal-ref>Genetics 206, 1049 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1534/genetics.116.199497</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Fisher's geometric model was originally introduced to argue that complex
adaptations must occur in small steps because of pleiotropic constraints. When
supplemented with the assumption of additivity of mutational effects on
phenotypic traits, it provides a simple mechanism for the emergence of
genotypic epistasis from the nonlinear mapping of phenotypes to fitness. Of
particular interest is the occurrence of reciprocal sign epistasis, which is a
necessary condition for multipeaked genotypic fitness landscapes. Here we
compute the probability that a pair of randomly chosen mutations interacts sign
epistatically, which is found to decrease with increasing phenotypic dimension
$n$, and varies nonmonotonically with the distance from the phenotypic optimum.
We then derive expressions for the mean number of fitness maxima in genotypic
landscapes comprised of all combinations of $L$ random mutations. This number
increases exponentially with $L$, and the corresponding growth rate is used as
a measure of the complexity of the landscape. The dependence of the complexity
on the model parameters is found to be surprisingly rich, and three distinct
phases characterized by different landscape structures are identified. Our
analysis shows that the phenotypic dimension, which is often referred to as
phenotypic complexity, does not generally correlate with the complexity of
fitness landscapes and that even organisms with a single phenotypic trait can
have complex landscapes. Our results further inform the interpretation of
experiments where the parameters of Fisher's model have been inferred from
data, and help to elucidate which features of empirical fitness landscapes can
be described by this model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07287</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07287</id><created>2017-01-25</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shu</keyname><forenames>Fengchun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrov</keyname><forenames>Leonid</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Wu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xia</keyname><forenames>Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Tianyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cui</keyname><forenames>Yuzhu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takefuji</keyname><forenames>Kazuhiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCallum</keyname><forenames>Jamie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lovell</keyname><forenames>Jim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yi</keyname><forenames>Sang-oh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hao</keyname><forenames>Longfei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Wenjun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Zhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jinling</forenames></author></authors><title>VLBI ecliptic plane survey: VEPS-1</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures, 5 tables, accepted by The Astrophysical Journal
  Supplement Series (ApJS)</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal Supplement Series (ApJS), Volume 230,
  Number 2, 13 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4365/aa71a3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present here the results of the first part of the VLBI Ecliptic Plane
Survey (VEPS) program. The goal of the program is to find all compact sources
within $7.5^\circ$ of the ecliptic plane which are suitable as calibrators for
anticipated phase referencing observations of spacecraft and determine their
positions with accuracy at the 1.5~nrad level. We run the program in two modes:
the search mode and the refining mode. In the search mode, a complete sample of
all sources brighter than 50 mJy at 5 GHz listed in the Parkes-MIT-NRAO (PMN)
and Green Bank 6~cm (GB6) catalogs, except those previously detected with VLBI,
is observed. In the refining mode, the positions of all ecliptic plane sources,
including those found in the search mode, are improved. By October 2016,
thirteen 24-hr sessions that targeted all sources brighter than 100~mJy have
been observed and analyzed. Among 3320 observed target sources, 555 objects
have been detected. We also conducted a number of follow-up VLBI experiments in
the refining mode and improved the positions of 249 ecliptic plane sources.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.00514</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.00514</id><created>2017-02-01</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Shu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Qing-Hu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Hang</forenames></author></authors><title>Zeno and anti-Zeno effect in an open quantum system in the
  ultrastrong-coupling regime</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 062109 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.062109</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the quantum Zeno effect (QZE) and quantum anti-Zeno effect (QAZE) of
a two-level system interacting with an environment of harmonic oscillators, the
spin-boson model. By applying a numerically exact method based on matrix
product states, the previously obtained picture on the influence of
counter-rotating terms has to be modified: For physical bath initial states,
the transition from QZE to QAZE with increasing measurement interval is only
absent at weak coupling, while present at strong coupling. Furthermore, we find
that the transition occurs always for the widely used bare bath initial state.
Within a more realistic measurement scheme where only the qubit is projectively
measured, the above scenario for the bare bath initial state remains
qualitatively unchanged, apart from accelerated decay for intermediate
measurement intervals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04204</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04204</id><created>2017-02-14</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barack</keyname><forenames>Leor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giudice</keyname><forenames>Paco</forenames></author></authors><title>Time-domain metric reconstruction for self-force applications</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>21 pages, 7 figures; v3 corrects typo in Eq. (58)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 104033 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.104033</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a new method for calculation of the gravitational self-force (GSF)
in Kerr geometry, based on a time-domain reconstruction of the metric
perturbation from curvature scalars. In this approach, the GSF is computed
directly from a certain scalar-like self-potential that satisfies the
time-domain Teukolsky equation on the Kerr background. The approach is
computationally much cheaper than existing time-domain methods, which rely on a
direct integration of the linearized Einstein's equations and are impaired by
mode instabilities. At the same time, it retains the utility and flexibility of
a time-domain treatment, allowing calculations for any type of orbit (including
highly eccentric or unbound ones) and the possibility of self-consistently
evolving the orbit under the effect of the GSF. Here we formulate our method,
and present a first numerical application, for circular geodesic orbits in
Schwarzschild geometry. We discuss further applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.05429</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.05429</id><created>2017-02-15</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kashuba</keyname><forenames>Alexander B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistical mechanics of gravitating gas like galaxy</title><categories>astro-ph.GA cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>adds stellar distribution function Eq.(24) and galaxy's equation of
  state (31)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The most probable state of an infinite self-gravitating gas in the dynamical
equilibrium is defined by `gravitational haziness', a parameter representing
many-body effects and formally like the temperature in the case of thermal
equilibrium. A kinetic equation is constructed using a concept of statistical
equipartition of the virial among subsystems of the self-gravitating gas. A
closed equation for the gravitational potential is conjectured as a special
property of the kinetic equation. An equilibrium particle distribution function
in the phase space, an analog of the Maxwell-Boltzmann weight, and a galaxy
equation of state are found for all `gravitational haziness'. The first law of
a `hazydynamics' (thermodynamics) states that the total mass of an astronomical
stellar collection is the sum of the Archimedes displaced mass and an excess
`gobbled' mass determined by the `gravitational haziness' and history.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.07532</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.07532</id><created>2017-02-24</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nishida</keyname><forenames>Yusuke</forenames></author></authors><title>Semisuper Efimov effect of two-dimensional bosons at a three-body
  resonance</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas nucl-th</categories><comments>5 pages; published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 230601 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.230601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Wave-particle duality in quantum mechanics allows for a halo bound state
whose spatial extension far exceeds a range of the interaction potential. What
is even more striking is that such quantum halos can be arbitrarily large on
special occasions. The two examples known so far are the Efimov effect and the
super Efimov effect, which predict that spatial extensions of higher excited
states grow exponentially and double exponentially, respectively. Here, we
establish yet another new class of arbitrarily large quantum halos formed by
spinless bosons with short-range interactions in two dimensions. When the
two-body interaction is absent but the three-body interaction is resonant, four
bosons exhibit an infinite tower of bound states whose spatial extensions scale
as $R_n\sim e^{(\pi n)^2/27}$ for a large $n$. The emergent scaling law is
universal and is termed a semisuper Efimov effect, which together with the
Efimov and super Efimov effects constitutes a trio of few-body universality
classes allowing for arbitrarily large quantum halos.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.08257</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.08257</id><created>2017-02-27</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Eleuch</keyname><forenames>Hichem</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rotter</keyname><forenames>Ingrid</forenames></author></authors><title>Gain and loss in open quantum systems</title><categories>physics.bio-ph physics.chem-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>Quality of figures is improved; a few improvements in the text. Paper
  is published in Phys. Rev. E</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 95, 062109 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.062109</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Photosynthesis is the basic process used by plants to convert light energy in
reaction centers into chemical energy. The high efficiency of this process is
not yet understood today. Using the formalism for the description of open
quantum systems by means of a non-Hermitian Hamilton operator, we consider
initially the interplay of gain (acceptor) and loss (donor). Near singular
points it causes fluctuations of the cross section which appear without any
excitation of internal degrees of freedom of the system. This process occurs
therefore very quickly and with high efficiency. We then consider the
excitation of resonance states of the system by means of these fluctuations.
This second step of the whole process takes place much slower than the first
one, because it involves the excitation of internal degrees of freedom of the
system. The two-step process as a whole is highly efficient and the decay is
bi-exponential. We provide, if possible, the results of analytical studies,
otherwise characteristic numerical results. The similarities of the obtained
results to light harvesting in photosynthetic organisms are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.08307</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.08307</id><created>2017-02-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Bao</keyname><forenames>Changhua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Eryin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Chaoyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Avila</keyname><forenames>Jos&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asensio</keyname><forenames>Maria C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Shuyun</forenames></author></authors><title>Stacking-dependent electronic structure of trilayer graphene resolved by
  nanospot angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Nano letters, 17(3): 1564-1568 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.6b04698</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The crystallographic stacking order in multilayer graphene plays an important
role in determining its electronic structure. In trilayer graphene,
rhombohedral stacking (ABC) is particularly intriguing, exhibiting a flat band
with an electric-field tunable band gap. Such electronic structure is distinct
from simple hexagonal stacking (AAA) or typical Bernal stacking (ABA), and is
promising for nanoscale electronics, optoelectronics applications. So far clean
experimental electronic spectra on the first two stackings are missing because
the samples are usually too small in size (um or nm scale) to be resolved by
conventional angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy (ARPES). Here by using
ARPES with nanospot beam size (NanoARPES), we provide direct experimental
evidence for the coexistence of three different stackings of trilayer graphene
and reveal their distinctive electronic structures directly. By fitting the
experimental data, we provide important experimental band parameters for
describing the electronic structure of trilayer graphene with different
stackings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.08861</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.08861</id><created>2017-02-28</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Baxter</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crisler</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cwiok</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dahl</keyname><forenames>C. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grimsted</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Puig</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Temples</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>First Demonstration of a Scintillating Xenon Bubble Chamber for
  Detecting Dark Matter and Coherent Elastic Neutrino-Nucleus Scattering</title><categories>physics.ins-det astro-ph.CO hep-ex</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures. Published version</comments><report-no>FERMILAB-PUB-17-062-AE-E-PPD</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 231301 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.231301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A 30-g xenon bubble chamber, operated at Northwestern University in June and
November 2016, has for the first time observed simultaneous bubble nucleation
and scintillation by nuclear recoils in a superheated liquid. This chamber is
instrumented with a CCD camera for near-IR bubble imaging, a solar-blind
photomultiplier tube to detect 175-nm xenon scintillation light, and a
piezoelectric acoustic transducer to detect the ultrasonic emission from a
growing bubble. The time of nucleation determined from the acoustic signal is
used to correlate specific scintillation pulses with bubble-nucleating events.
We report on data from this chamber for thermodynamic &quot;Seitz&quot; thresholds from
4.2 to 15.0 keV. The observed single- and multiple-bubble rates when exposed to
a $^{252}$Cf neutron source indicate that, for an 8.3-keV thermodynamic
threshold, the minimum nuclear recoil energy required to nucleate a bubble is
$19\pm6$ keV (1$\sigma$ uncertainty). This is consistent with the observed
scintillation spectrum for bubble-nucleating events. We see no evidence for
bubble nucleation by gamma rays at any of the thresholds studied, setting a 90%
C.L. upper limit of $6.3\times10^{-7}$ bubbles per gamma interaction at a
4.2-keV thermodynamic threshold. This indicates stronger gamma discrimination
than in CF$_3$I bubble chambers, supporting the hypothesis that scintillation
production suppresses bubble nucleation by electron recoils while nuclear
recoils nucleate bubbles as usual. These measurements establish the
noble-liquid bubble chamber as a promising new technology for the detection of
weakly interacting massive particle dark matter and coherent elastic
neutrino-nucleus scattering.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.01082</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.01082</id><created>2017-03-03</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cui</keyname><forenames>Ke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Xiangyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Zongkai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Rihong</forenames></author></authors><title>Towards implementing multi-channels, ring-oscillator-based, Vernier
  time-to-digital converter in FPGAs: key design points and construction method</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><comments>9 pages,9 figures, 4 tables; published on IEEE Transactions on
  Radiation and Plasma Medical Sciences</comments><doi>10.1109/TRPMS.2017.2712260</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For TOF positron emission tomography (TOF PET) detectors, time-to-digital
converters (TDCs) are essential to resolve the coincidence time of the photon
pairs. Recently, an efficient TDC structure called ring-oscillator-based
(RO-based) Vernier TDC using carry chains was reported by our team. The method
is very promising due to its low linearity error and low resource cost.
However, the implementation complexity is rather high especially when moving to
multi-channels TDC designs, since this method calls for a manual intervention
to the initial fitting results of the compilation software. In this paper, we
elaborate the key points toward implementing high performance multi-channels
TDCs of this kind while keeping the least implementation complexity.
Furthermore, we propose an efficient fine time interpolator construction method
called the period difference recording which only needs at most 31 adjustment
trials to obtain a targeted TDC resolution. To validate the techniques proposed
in this paper, we built a 32-channels TDC on a Stratix III FPGA chip and fully
evaluated its performance. Code density tests show that the obtained resolution
results lie in the range of (23 ps ~ 37 ps), the differential nonlinearity
(DNL) results lie in the range of (-0.4 LSB ~ 0.4 LSB) and the integral
nonlinearity (INL) results lie in the range of (-0.7 LSB ~ 0.7 LSB) for each of
the 32 TDC channels. This paper greatly eases the designing difficulty of the
carry chain RO-based TDCs and can significantly propel their development in
practical use.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.01214</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.01214</id><created>2017-03-03</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bazhanova</keyname><forenames>Z. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roizen</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oganov</keyname><forenames>A. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>High-pressure behavior of the Fe-S system and composition of the Earth's
  inner core</title><categories>physics.geo-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><doi>10.3367/UFNe.2017.03.038079</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using evolutionary crystal structure prediction algorithm USPEX, we identify
the compositions and crystal structures of stable compounds in the Fe-S system
at pressures in the range 100-400 GPa. We find that at pressures of the Earth's
solid inner core (330-364 GPa) two compounds are stable - Fe2S and FeS. In
equilibrium with iron, only Fe2S can exist in the inner core. Using the
equation of state of Fe2S, we find that in order to reproduce the density of
the inner core by adding sulfur alone, 10.6-13.7 mol.% (6.4-8.4 wt.%) sulfur is
needed. Analogous calculation for silicon (where the only stable compound at
inner core pressures is FeSi) reproduces the density of the inner core with
9.0-11.8 mol.% (4.8-6.3 wt.%) silicon. In both cases, a virtually identical
mean atomic mass M in the range 52.6-53.3 results for in the inner core, which
is much higher than M = 49.3 determined for the inner core from Birch's law.
For oxygen (where the relevant stable oxide at conditions of the inner core is
Fe2O) we find the matching concentration in the range 13.2-17.2 mol.% (4.2-5.6
wt.%), which corresponds to M in the range 49.0-50.6. Combining our results and
previous works, we find that inner core density and M can be explained by only
four models (in atomic %): (a) 86%(Fe+Ni) + 14%C, (b) 84%(Fe+Ni) + 16%O, (c)
84%(Fe+Ni) + 7%S + 9%H, (d) 85%(Fe+Ni) + 6%Si + 9%H, and some of their linear
combinations (primarly, models (c) and (d)).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.01766</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.01766</id><created>2017-03-06</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ciezarek</keyname><forenames>Gregory</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sevilla</keyname><forenames>Manuel Franco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hamilton</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kowalewski</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuhr</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xfc;th</keyname><forenames>Vera</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sato</keyname><forenames>Yutaro</forenames></author></authors><title>A Challenge to Lepton Universality in B Meson Decays</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures. Accepted for publication in Nature</comments><doi>10.1038/nature22346</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One of the key assumptions of the Standard Model of fundamental particles is
that the interactions of the charged leptons, namely electrons, muons, and
taus, differ only because of their different masses. While precision tests
comparing processes involving electrons and muons have not revealed any
significant violation of this assumption, recent studies involving the
higher-mass tau lepton have resulted in observations that challenge lepton
universality at the level of four standard deviations. A confirmation of these
results would point to new particles or interactions, and could have profound
implications for our understanding of particle physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.02142</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.02142</id><created>2017-03-06</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tas</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sasioglu</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Friedrich</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galanakis</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>A first-principles DFT+GW study of spin-filter and spin-gapless
  semiconducting Heusler compounds</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Final version as published</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Magnetism and Magnetic Materials 441, 333 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jmmm.2017.05.062</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Among Heusler compounds, the ones being magnetic semiconductors (also known
as spin-filter materials) are widely studied as they offer novel
functionalities in spintronic/magnetoelectronic devices. The spin-gapless
semiconductors are a special case. They possess a zero or almost-zero energy
gap in one of the two spin channels. We employ the $GW$ approximation, which
allows an elaborate treatment of the electronic correlations, to simulate the
electronic band structure of these materials. Our results suggest that in most
cases the use of $GW$ self energy instead of the usual density functionals is
important to accurately determine the electronic properties of magnetic
semiconductors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.02598</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.02598</id><created>2017-03-07</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Skoruppa</keyname><forenames>Enrico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laleman</keyname><forenames>Michiel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nomidis</keyname><forenames>Stefanos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carlon</keyname><forenames>Enrico</forenames></author></authors><title>DNA elasticity from coarse-grained simulations: the effect of groove
  asymmetry</title><categories>q-bio.BM cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>20 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 146, 214902 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4984039</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is well-established that many physical properties of DNA at sufficiently
long length scales can be understood by means of simple polymer models. One of
the most widely used elasticity models for DNA is the twistable worm-like chain
(TWLC), which describes the double helix as a continuous elastic rod with
bending and torsional stiffness. An extension of the TWLC, which has recently
received some attention, is the model by Marko and Siggia, who introduced an
additional twist-bend coupling, expected to arise from the groove asymmetry. By
performing computer simulations of two available versions of oxDNA, a
coarse-grained model of nucleic acids, we investigate the microscopic origin of
twist-bend coupling. We show that this interaction is negligible in the oxDNA
version with symmetric grooves, while it appears in the oxDNA version with
asymmetric grooves. Our analysis is based on the calculation of the covariance
matrix of equilibrium deformations, from which the stiffness parameters are
obtained. The estimated twist-bend coupling coefficient from oxDNA simulations
is $G=30\pm1$~nm. The groove asymmetry induces a novel twist length scale and
an associated renormalized twist stiffness $\kappa_{\rm t} \approx 80$~nm,
which is different from the intrinsic torsional stiffness $C \approx 110$~nm.
This naturally explains the large variations on experimental estimates of the
intrinsic stiffness performed in the past.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.02831</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.02831</id><created>2017-03-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Frisenda</keyname><forenames>Riccardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dr&#xfc;ppel</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Vasconcellos</keyname><forenames>Steffen Michaelis</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Lara</keyname><forenames>David Perez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bratschitsch</keyname><forenames>Rudolf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rohlfing</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Castellanos-Gomez</keyname><forenames>Andres</forenames></author></authors><title>Biaxial strain tuning of the optical properties of single-layer
  transition metal dichalcogenides</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures, 2 tables, supporting information</comments><journal-ref>npj 2D Materials and Applications 1, 10 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41699-017-0013-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Since their discovery single-layer semiconducting transition metal
dichalcogenides have attracted much attention thanks to their outstanding
optical and mechanical properties. Strain engineering in these two-dimensional
materials aims to tune their bandgap energy and to modify their optoelectronic
properties by the application of external strain. In this paper we demonstrate
that biaxial strain, both tensile and compressive, can be applied and released
in a timescale of a few seconds in a reproducible way on transition metal
dichalcogenides monolayers deposited on polymeric substrates. We can control
the amount of biaxial strain applied by letting the substrate expand or
compress. To do this we change the substrate temperature and choose materials
with a large thermal expansion coefficient. After the investigation of the
substrate-dependent strain transfer, we performed micro-differential
spectroscopy of four transition metal dichalcogenides monolayers (MoS2, MoSe2,
WS2, WSe2) under the application of biaxial strain and measured their optical
properties. For tensile strain we observe a redshift of the bandgap that
reaches a value as large as 95 meV/% in the case of single-layer WS2 deposited
on polypropylene. The observed bandgap shifts as a function of substrate
extension/compression follow the order MoSe2 &lt; MoS2 &lt; WSe2 &lt; WS2. Theoretical
calculations of these four materials under biaxial strain predict the same
trend for the material-dependent rates of the shift and reproduce well the
features observed in the measured reflectance spectra.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.03307</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.03307</id><created>2017-03-09</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Andersen</keyname><forenames>Jorgen Ellegaard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borot</keyname><forenames>Ga&#xeb;tan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chekhov</keyname><forenames>Leonid O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orantin</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author></authors><title>The ABCD of topological recursion</title><categories>math-ph math.AG math.MP math.SG</categories><comments>75 pages, 6 figures ; v2: sl_2 statement corrected, results added on
  quantum Airy structure for semi-simple Lie algebras. v3: missprints
  correction. v4: re-sectioning, a bit more on semi-simple Lie algebras</comments><msc-class>81Qxx, 81S10, 81T40, 14H70</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Kontsevich and Soibelman reformulated and slightly generalised the
topological recursion of math-ph/0702045, seeing it as a quantization of
certain quadratic Lagrangians in $T^*V$ for some vector space $V$. KS
topological recursion is a procedure which takes as initial data a quantum Airy
structure -- a family of at most quadratic differential operators on $V$
satisfying some axioms -- and gives as outcome a formal series of functions in
$V$ (the partition function) simultaneously annihilated by these operators.
Finding and classifying quantum Airy structures modulo gauge group action, is
by itself an interesting problem which we study here. We provide some
elementary, Lie-algebraic tools to address this problem, and give some elements
of classification for ${\rm dim}\,V = 2$. We also describe four more
interesting classes of quantum Airy structures, coming from respectively
Frobenius algebras (here we retrieve the 2d TQFT partition function as a
special case), non-commutative Frobenius algebras, loop spaces of Frobenius
algebras and a $\mathbb{Z}_{2}$-invariant version of the latter. This
$\mathbb{Z}_{2}$-invariant version in the case of a semi-simple Frobenius
algebra corresponds to the topological recursion of math-ph/0702045.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.03741</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.03741</id><created>2017-03-10</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Reiffers-Masson</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames><affiliation>LIA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Labatut</keyname><forenames>Vincent</forenames><affiliation>LIA</affiliation></author></authors><title>Opinion-Based Centrality in Multiplex Networks: A Convex Optimization
  Approach</title><categories>cs.SI cs.GT physics.soc-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Network Science, Cambridge Journals, 5 (2), pp.213-234 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/nws.2017.7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Most people simultaneously belong to several distinct social networks, in
which their relations can be different. They have opinions about certain
topics, which they share and spread on these networks, and are influenced by
the opinions of other persons. In this paper, we build upon this observation to
propose a new nodal centrality measure for multiplex networks. Our measure,
called Opinion centrality, is based on a stochastic model representing opinion
propagation dynamics in such a network. We formulate an optimization problem
consisting in maximizing the opinion of the whole network when controlling an
external influence able to affect each node individually. We find a
mathematical closed form of this problem, and use its solution to derive our
centrality measure. According to the opinion centrality, the more a node is
worth investing external influence, and the more it is central. We perform an
empirical study of the proposed centrality over a toy network, as well as a
collection of real-world networks. Our measure is generally negatively
correlated with existing multiplex centrality measures, and highlights
different types of nodes, accordingly to its definition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.05063</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.05063</id><created>2017-03-15</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sperling</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agudelo</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walmsley</keyname><forenames>I. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogel</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum correlations in composite systems</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Phys. B: At. Mol. Opt. Phys. 50, 134003 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6455/aa7438</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study emerging notions of quantum correlations in compound systems. Based
on different definitions of quantumness in individual subsystems, we
investigate how they extend to the joint description of a composite system.
Especially, we study the bipartite case and the connection of two typically
applied and distinctively different concepts of nonclassicality in quantum
optics and quantum information. Our investigation includes the representation
of correlated states in terms of quasiprobability matrices, a comparative study
of joint and conditional quantum correlations, and an entanglement
characterization. It is, for example, shown that our composition approach
always includes entanglement as one form of quantum correlations. Yet, other
forms of quantum correlations can also occur without entanglement. Finally, we
give an outlook towards multimode systems and temporal correlations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.05771</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.05771</id><created>2017-03-16</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aalsma</keyname><forenames>Lars</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Schaar</keyname><forenames>Jan Pieter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vercnocke</keyname><forenames>Bert</forenames></author></authors><title>Constrained superfields on metastable anti-D3-branes</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>22 pages, 1 figure. v2: fixed typos, matches published version</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP05(2017)089</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the effect of brane polarization on the supersymmetry
transformations of probe anti-D3-branes at the tip of a Klebanov-Strassler
throat geometry. As is well known, the probe branes can polarize into
NS5-branes and decay to a supersymmetric state by brane-flux annihilation. The
effective potential has a metastable minimum as long as the number of
anti-D3-branes is small compared to the number of flux quanta. We study the
reduced four-dimensional effective NS5-brane theory and show that in the
metastable minimum supersymmetry is non-linearly realized to leading order, as
expected for spontaneously broken supersymmetry. However, a strict decoupling
limit of the higher order corrections in terms of a standard nilpotent
superfield does not seem to exist. We comment on the possible implications of
these results for more general low-energy effective descriptions of inflation
or de Sitter vacua.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.06698</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.06698</id><created>2017-03-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Dolai</keyname><forenames>Pritha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Basu</keyname><forenames>Abhik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simha</keyname><forenames>Aditi</forenames></author></authors><title>Universal spatio-temporal scaling of distortions in a drifting lattice</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 95, 052115 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.052115</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the dynamical response to small distortions of a lattice about its
uniform state, drifting through a dissipative medium due to an external force,
and show, analytically and numerically, that the fluctuations, both transverse
and longitudinal to the direction of the drift, exhibit spatiotemporal scaling
belonging to the Kardar-Parisi-Zhang universality class. Further, we predict
that a colloidal crystal drifting in a constant electric field is linearly
stable against distortions and the distortions propagate as underdamped waves.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08430</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08430</id><created>2017-03-20</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sahoo</keyname><forenames>P. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sahoo</keyname><forenames>Parbati</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bishi</keyname><forenames>Binaya K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ayg&#xfc;n</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetized strange quark model with Big Rip singularity in $f(R,T)$
  gravity</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in MPLA</comments><msc-class>83F05, 83C15</msc-class><journal-ref>Modern Physics Letters A, Vol. 32 (2017) 1750105</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S021773231750105X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  LRS (Locally Rotationally symmetric) Bianchi type-I magnetized strange quark
matter cosmological model have been studied based on $f(R,T)$ gravity. The
exact solutions of the field equations are derived with linearly time varying
deceleration parameter which is consistent with observational data (from SNIa,
BAO and CMB) of standard cosmology. It is observed that the model start with
big bang and ends with a Big Rip. The transition of deceleration parameter from
decelerating phase to accelerating phase with respect to redshift obtained in
our model fits with the recent observational data obtained by Farook et al. in
2017. The well known Hubble parameter $H(z)$ and distance modulus $\mu(z)$ are
discussed with redshift.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.09522</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.09522</id><created>2017-03-28</created><updated>2017-05-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Rui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Dong-Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Bin</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological Anderson insulator phase in a Dirac-semimetal thin film</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 245305 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.245305</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The recently discovered topological Dirac semimetal represents a new exotic
quantum state of matter. Topological Dirac semimetals can be viewed as three
dimensional analogues of graphene, in which the Dirac nodes are protected by
crystalline symmetry. It has been found that quantum confinement effect can gap
out Dirac nodes and convert Dirac semimetal to a band insulator. The band
insulator is either normal insulator or quantum spin Hall insulator depending
on the thin film thickness. We present the study of disorder effects in thin
film of Dirac semimetals. It is found that moderate Anderson disorder strength
can drive a topological phase transition from normal band insulator to
topological Anderson insulator in Dirac semimetal thin film. The numerical
calculation based on the model parameters of Dirac semimetal Na$_{3}$Bi shows
that in the topological Anderson insulator phase a quantized conductance
plateau occurs in the bulk gap of band insulator, and the distributions of
local currents further confirm that the quantized conductance plateau arises
from the helical edge states induced by disorder. Finally, an effective medium
theory based on Born approximation fits the numerical data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00914</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00914</id><created>2017-04-04</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Yexin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Ji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>En-Ge</forenames></author><author><keyname>Michaelides</keyname><forenames>Angelos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Xin-Zheng</forenames></author></authors><title>Hydrogenation Facilitates Proton Transfer Through Two-Dimensional
  Honeycomb Crystals</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent experiments have triggered a debate about the ability of protons to
transfer through individual layers of graphene and hexagonal boron nitride
(h-BN). However, calculations have shown that the barriers to proton
penetration can, at more than 3 eV, be excessively high. Here, on the basis of
first principles calculations, we show that the barrier for proton penetration
is significantly reduced, to less than 1 eV, upon hydrogenation even in the
absence of pinholes in the lattice. Analysis reveals that the barrier is
reduced because hydrogenation destabilises the initial state (a deep-lying
chemisorption state) and expands the honeycomb lattice through which the
protons penetrate. This study offers a rationalization of the fast proton
transfer observed in experiments, and highlights the ability of proton
transport through single-layer materials in hydrogen rich solutions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02261</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02261</id><created>2017-04-07</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Quarles</keyname><forenames>Billy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quintana</keyname><forenames>Elisa V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lopez</keyname><forenames>Eric D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schlieder</keyname><forenames>Joshua E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barclay</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Plausible Compositions of the Seven TRAPPIST-1 Planets Using Long-term
  Dynamical Simulations</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figure, 3 tables, accepted to ApJL; Changes made due to
  first review including modification and addition of figures</comments><doi>10.3847/2041-8213/aa74bf</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  TRAPPIST-1 is a nearby ultra-cool dwarf that is host to a remarkable
planetary system consisting of seven transiting planets. The orbital properties
and radii of the planets have been well-constrained, and recently the masses of
the inner six planets have been measured with additional ground and space-based
photometric observations. Large uncertainties in these mass measurements have
prevented a robust analysis of the planetary compositions. Here we perform many
thousands of N-body dynamical simulations with planet properties perturbed from
the observed values and identify those that are stable for millions of years.
This allows us to identify self-consistent orbital solutions that can be used
in future studies. From our range of dynamical masses, we find that most of the
planets are consistent with an Earth-like composition, where TRAPPIST-1f is
likely to have a volatile-rich envelope.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04436</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04436</id><created>2017-04-14</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xue Ping</forenames></author></authors><title>Gevrey estimates of the resolvent and sub-exponential time-decay of
  solutions</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP math.SP</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article, we study a class of non-selfadjoint Schr{\&quot;o}dinger
operators H which are perturbation of some model operator H 0 satisfying a
weighted coercive assumption. For the model operator H 0 , we prove that the
derivatives of the resolvent satisfy some Gevrey estimates at threshold zero.
As application, we establish large time expansions of semigroups e --tH and e
--itH for t &gt; 0 with subexponential time-decay estimates on the remainder,
including possible presence of zero eigenvalue and real resonances.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05054</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05054</id><created>2017-04-16</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pavese</keyname><forenames>Franco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szmyrka-Grzebyk</keyname><forenames>Anna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steur</keyname><forenames>Peter P. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>The ITS-90 after definition of neon isotopic reference composition.
  Extent of the isotopic effect on previous inter-comparison results</title><categories>physics.data-an</categories><comments>19 pages, 4 figures, 4 tables. BIPM, Doc. CCT/17-18</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  Starting from the end of the past century, the importance has been recognized
of the effect of isotopic composition on some of the temperature fixed points
for the most accurate realizations of the ITS-90. In the original definition of
the latter, dating back to 1990, only a generic reference was made to natural
composition of the substances used for the realization of the fixed points,
except for helium. The definition of a reference isotopic composition for three
fixed points, e-H2, Ne and H2O, while eliminating the non-uniqueness of the
Scale in this respect, induced detectable differences in the present and future
realizations of the Scale, at the highest accuracy level, with respect to the
previous realizations, when they affected the results of past key comparisons,
namely the K1 and K1.1, and K2 and K2.1 to K2.5 and the related regional and
supplementary ones. The paper provides evidence of the extent of this effect by
using the results of the relevant key comparisons for Neon archived in the BIPM
KCDB, and of other comparisons existing in the literature: 1979-1984, 2007-2012
and 2009-2010 sealed cell comparisons; and discusses the meaning and the
outcomes of this evaluation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05287</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05287</id><created>2017-04-18</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Endo</keyname><forenames>Motoi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hamaguchi</keyname><forenames>Koichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iwamoto</keyname><forenames>Sho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yanagi</keyname><forenames>Keisuke</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing minimal SUSY scenarios in the light of muon $g-2$ and dark
  matter</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 5 figures; the published version</comments><report-no>UT-17-14, IPMU17-0061, KEK-TH-1973</report-no><journal-ref>Journal of High Energy Physics, 2017(6), 1-16</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP06(2017)031</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study supersymmetric (SUSY) models in which the muon $g-2$ discrepancy and
the dark matter relic abundance are simultaneously explained. The muon $g-2$
discrepancy, or a 3$\sigma$ deviation between the experimental and theoretical
results of the muon anomalous magnetic moment, can be resolved by SUSY models,
which implies at least three SUSY multiplets have masses of
$\mathop{\mathcal{O}}(100)\, \mathrm{GeV}$. In particular, models with the
bino, higgsino and slepton having $\mathop{\mathcal{O}}(100)\, \mathrm{GeV}$
masses are not only capable to explain the muon $g-2$ discrepancy but naturally
contains the neutralino dark matter with the observed relic abundance. We study
constraints and future prospects of such models; in particular, we find that
the LHC search for events with two hadronic taus and missing transverse
momentum can probe this scenario through chargino/neutralino production. It is
shown that almost all the parameter space of the scenario can be probed at the
high-luminosity LHC, and a large part can also be tested at the XENON1T
experiment as well as at the ILC.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05949</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05949</id><created>2017-04-19</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>de Felice</keyname><forenames>Oscar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geipel</keyname><forenames>Jakob</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalised Calibrations in AdS backgrounds from Exceptional
  Sasaki-Einstein Structures</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>Generalised calibrations from exceptional structures in 26 pages.
  Typos corrected</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study generalised calibrations described by Exceptional Sasaki-Einstein
structures on AdS backgrounds in type IIB and M-theory, placing the focus on
the generalised Reeb vectors. The inequalities for the energy bound are derived
by decomposing a $\kappa$-symmetry condition and equivalently, bispinors in
calibration conditions from existing literature. We explain how the closure of
the calibration forms is related to the integrability conditions of the
Exceptional Sasaki-Einstein structure, in particular for AdS space-filling or
point-like branes. Doing so, we show that the form parts of the twisted vector
structure in M-theory provides generalised calibrations, reproducing the result
conjectured in a recent paper. The IIB case yields analogous results. Finally,
we discuss briefly the extension of the conjecture to hypermultiplet structures
and other brane configurations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.00709</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.00709</id><created>2017-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Gozzard</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schediwy</keyname><forenames>Sascha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wallace</keyname><forenames>Bruce</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gamatham</keyname><forenames>Romeo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grainge</keyname><forenames>Keith</forenames></author></authors><title>Characterization of Optical Frequency Transfer Over 154 km of Aerial
  Fiber</title><categories>physics.ins-det astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>4 pages, submitted to Optics Letters</comments><journal-ref>Opt. Lett. 42, 2197-2200 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.42.002197</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present measurements of the frequency transfer stability and analysis of
the noise characteristics of an optical signal propagating over aerial
suspended fiber links up to 153.6 km in length. The measured frequency transfer
stability over these links is on the order of 10^-11 at an integration time of
one second dropping to 10^-12 for integration times longer than 100 s. We show
that wind-loading of the cable spans is the dominant source of short-timescale
noise on the fiber links. We also report an attempt to stabilize the optical
frequency transfer over these aerial links.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.01169</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.01169</id><created>2017-04-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Schediwy</keyname><forenames>Sascha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gozzard</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stobie</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malan</keyname><forenames>Jocias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grainge</keyname><forenames>Keith</forenames></author></authors><title>Stabilized microwave-frequency transfer using optical phase sensing and
  actuation</title><categories>physics.ins-det astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>4 pages, accepted by Optics Letters</comments><journal-ref>Opt. Lett. 42, 1648-1651 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.42.001648</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a stabilized microwave-frequency transfer technique that is based
on optical phase-sensing and optical phase-actuation. This technique shares
several attributes with optical-frequency transfer and therefore exhibits
several advantages over other microwave-frequency transfer techniques. We
demonstrated stabilized transfer of an 8,000 MHz microwave-frequency signal
over a 166 km metropolitan optical fiber network, achieving a fractional
frequency stability of 6.8x10^-14 Hz/Hz at 1 s integration, and 5.0x10^-16
Hz/Hz at 1.6x10^4 s. This technique is being considered for use on the Square
Kilometre Array SKA1-mid radio telescope.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02586</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02586</id><created>2017-05-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Qiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Mengmeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dai</keyname><forenames>Kunzhe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Ke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xue</keyname><forenames>Guangming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tan</keyname><forenames>Xinsheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Haifeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author></authors><title>Extensible 3D architecture for superconducting quantum computing</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 110, 232602 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4985435</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using a multi-layered printed circuit board, we propose a 3D architecture
suitable for packaging supercon- ducting chips, especially chips that contain
two-dimensional qubit arrays. In our proposed architecture, the center strips
of the buried coplanar waveguides protrude from the surface of a dielectric
layer as contacts. Since the contacts extend beyond the surface of the
dielectric layer, chips can simply be flip-chip packaged with on-chip
receptacles clinging to the contacts. Using this scheme, we packaged a
multi-qubit chip and per- formed single-qubit and two-qubit quantum gate
operations. The results indicate that this 3D architecture provides a promising
scheme for scalable quantum computing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05807</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05807</id><created>2017-05-16</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kohli</keyname><forenames>Ikjyot Singh</forenames></author></authors><title>Oscillating Towards the de Sitter Universe</title><categories>gr-qc math.DS</categories><comments>Corrected minor typos</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we consider spatially flat FLRW cosmological models in two
contexts in an attempt to derive a set of conditions that characterize when
such models exhibit oscillatory behaviour. In the first case, we consider a
spatially flat FLRW model with only a minimally-coupled scalar field, described
by a nonnegative scalar field potential. In the second case, we extended this
model to include barotropic matter. We show that for the case of a positive
cosmological constant, spatial flatness, and barotropic matter, oscillatory
solutions are certainly possible. However, these solutions do not oscillate
indefinitely, they decay over time. Interestingly, it is shown that all such
solutions oscillate and decay towards the de Sitter equilibrium point, which
represents an inflationary epoch in such models. This implies that for certain
families of scalar field potentials, the universe may have undergone several
oscillations \emph{before} entering an inflationary epoch.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06432</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06432</id><created>2017-05-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Schweiner</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Main</keyname><forenames>J&#xf6;rg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wunner</keyname><forenames>G&#xfc;nter</forenames></author></authors><title>GOE-GUE-Poisson transitions in the nearest neighbor spacing distribution
  of magnetoexcitons</title><categories>nlin.CD cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 95, 062205 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.062205</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent investigations on the Hamiltonian of excitons by F. Schweiner et al.
[Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 046401 (2017)] revealed that the combined presence of a
cubic band structure and external fields breaks all antiunitary symmetries. The
nearest neighbor spacing distribution of magnetoexcitons can exhibit Poissonian
statistics, the statistics of a Gaussian orthogonal ensemble (GOE) or a
Gaussian unitary ensemble (GUE) depending on the system parameters. Hence,
magnetoexcitons are an ideal system to investigate the transitions between
these statistics. Here we investigate the transitions between GOE and GUE
statistics and between Poissonian and GUE statistics by changing the angle of
the magnetic field with respect to the crystal lattice and by changing the
scaled energy known from the hydrogen atom in external fields. Comparing our
results with analytical formulae for these transitions derived with random
matrix theory, we obtain a very good agreement and thus confirm the Wigner
surmise for the exciton system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06442</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06442</id><created>2017-05-18</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ergin</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sezer</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sano</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamazaki</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fukui</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Recombining Plasma &amp; Gamma-ray Emission in the Mixed-morphology
  Supernova Remnant 3C 400.2</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Accepted to be published in the Astrophysical Journal</comments><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa72ee</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  3C 400.2 belongs to the mixed morphology supernova remnant class, showing
center-filled X-ray and shell-like radio morphology. We present a study of 3C
400.2 with archival Suzaku and Fermi-LAT observations. We find recombining
plasma (RP) in the Suzaku spectra of north-east and south-east regions. The
spectra of these regions are well described by two-component thermal plasma
models: The hard component is in RP, while the soft component is in collisional
ionization equilibrium (CIE) conditions. The RP has enhanced abundances
indicating that the X-ray emission has an ejecta origin, while the CIE has
solar abundances associated with the interstellar material. The X-ray spectra
of north-west and south-west regions are best fitted by a two-component thermal
plasma model: an ionizing and a CIE plasma. We have detected GeV gamma-ray
emission from 3C 400.2 at the level of $\sim$5$\sigma$ assuming a point-like
source model with a power-law (PL) type spectrum. We have also detected a new
GeV source at the level of $\sim$13$\sigma$ assuming a Gaussian extension model
with a PL type spectrum in the neighborhood of the SNR. We report the analysis
results of 3C 400.2 and the new extended gamma-ray source and discuss the
nature of gamma-ray emission of 3C 400.2 in the context of existing NANTEN CO
data, DRAO HI data, and the Suzaku X-ray analysis results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06669</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06669</id><created>2017-05-18</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Supriyo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ofori-Opoku</keyname><forenames>Nana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guyer</keyname><forenames>Jonathan E.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the primary spacing and microsegregation of cellular dendrites in
  laser deposited Ni-Nb alloys</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Modelling and Simulation in Materials Science and Engineering,
  Volume 25, Number 6, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-651X/aa7369</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this study, an alloy phase-field model is used to simulate solidification
microstructures at different locations within a solidified molten pool. The
temperature gradient $G$ and the solidification velocity $V$ are obtained from
a macroscopic heat transfer finite element simulation and provided as input to
the phase-field model. The effects of laser beam speed and the location within
the melt pool on the primary arm spacing and on the extent of Nb partitioning
at the cell tips are investigated. Simulated steady-state primary spacings are
compared with power law and geometrical models. Cell tip compositions are
compared to a dendrite growth model. The extent of non-equilibrium interface
partitioning of the phase-field model is investigated. Although the phase-field
model has an anti-trapping solute flux term meant to maintain local interface
equilibrium, we have found that during simulations it was insufficient at
maintaining equilibrium. This is due to the fact that the additive
manufacturing solidification conditions fall well outside the allowed limits of
this flux term.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.10088</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.10088</id><created>2017-05-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Hua-Xing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steele</keyname><forenames>T. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Shi-Lin</forenames></author></authors><title>Open-flavor charmed/bottom $sq\bar q\bar Q$ and $qq\bar q\bar Q$
  tetraquark states</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, 4 figures, 5 tables, accepted by Phys. Rev. D (in press)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 114005 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.114005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide comprehensive investigations for the mass spectrum of exotic
open-flavor charmed/bottom $sq\bar q\bar c$, $qq\bar q\bar c$, $sq\bar q\bar
b$, $qq\bar q\bar b$ tetraquark states with various spin-parity assignments
$J^P=0^+, 1^+, 2^+$ and $0^-, 1^-$ in the framework of QCD sum rules. In the
diquark configuration, we construct the diquark-antidiquark interpolating
tetraquark currents using the color-antisymmetric scalar and axial-vector
diquark fields. The stable mass sum rules are established in reasonable
parameter working ranges, which are used to give reliable mass predictions for
these tetraquark states. We obtain the mass spectra for the open-flavor
charmed/bottom $sq\bar q\bar c$, $qq\bar q\bar c$, $sq\bar q\bar b$, $qq\bar
q\bar b$ tetraquark states with various spin-parity quantum numbers. In
addition, we suggest searching for exotic doubly-charged tetraquarks, such as
$[sd][\bar u\bar c]\to D_s^{(\ast)-}\pi^-$ in future experiments at facilities
such as BESIII, BelleII, PANDA, LHCb and CMS, etc.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.00230</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.00230</id><created>2017-06-01</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gemmetto</keyname><forenames>Valerio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cardillo</keyname><forenames>Alessio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garlaschelli</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author></authors><title>Irreducible network backbones: unbiased graph filtering via maximum
  entropy</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI physics.pop-ph</categories><comments>Main + SI. (19+8) pages, (8+9) figures, (2+4) tables. Submitted for
  publication</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Networks provide an informative, yet non-redundant description of complex
systems only if links represent truly dyadic relationships that cannot be
directly traced back to node-specific properties such as size, importance, or
coordinates in some embedding space. In any real-world network, some links may
be reducible, and others irreducible, to such local properties. This dichotomy
persists despite the steady increase in data availability and resolution, which
actually determines an even stronger need for filtering techniques aimed at
discerning essential links from non-essential ones. Here we introduce a
rigorous method that, for any desired level of statistical significance,
outputs the network backbone that is irreducible to the local properties of
nodes, i.e. their degrees and strengths. Unlike previous approaches, our method
employs an exact maximum-entropy formulation guaranteeing that the filtered
network encodes only the links that cannot be inferred from local information.
Extensive empirical analysis confirms that this approach uncovers essential
backbones that are otherwise hidden amidst many redundant relationships and
inaccessible to other methods. For instance, we retrieve the hub-and-spoke
skeleton of the US airport network and many specialised patterns of
international trade. Being irreducible to local transportation and economic
constraints of supply and demand, these backbones single out genuinely
higher-order wiring principles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.00404</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.00404</id><created>2017-06-01</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Supriyo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukherjee</keyname><forenames>Arnab</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abinandanan</keyname><forenames>T. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bose</keyname><forenames>Suryasarathi</forenames></author></authors><title>Particles with selective wetting affect spinodal decomposition
  microstructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in PCCP on 24th May 2017</comments><doi>10.1039/C7CP01816A</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have used mesoscale simulations to study the effect of immobile particles
on microstructure formation during spinodal decomposition in ternary mixtures
such as polymer blends. Specifically, we have explored a regime of
interparticle spacings (which are a few times the characteristic spinodal
length scale) in which we might expect interesting new effects arising from
interactions among wetting, spinodal decomposition and coarsening. In this
paper, we report three new effects for systems in which the particle phase has
a strong preference for being wetted by one of the components (say, A). In the
presence of particles, microstructures are not bicontinuous in a symmetric
mixture. An asymmetric mixture, on the other hand, first forms a
non-bicontinuous microstructure which then evolves into a bicontinuous one at
intermediate times. Moreover, while wetting of the particle phase by the
preferred component (A) creates alternating A-rich and B-rich layers around the
particles, curvature-driven coarsening leads to shrinking and disappearance of
the first A-rich layer, leaving a layer of the non-preferred component in
contact with the particle. At late simulation times, domains of the matrix
components coarsen following the Lifshitz-Slyozov-Wagner law, $R_1(t) \sim
t^{1/3}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.00634</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.00634</id><created>2017-06-02</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Turner</keyname><forenames>Jacob</forenames></author></authors><title>A new degree bound for local unitary and $n$-qubit SLOCC Invariants</title><categories>quant-ph math.RT</categories><comments>Proof is flawed</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Deep connections between invariant theory and entanglement have been known
for some time and been the object of intense study. This includes the study of
local unitary equivalence of density operators as well as entanglement that can
be observed in stochastic local operations assisted by classical communication
(SLOCC). An important aspect of both of these areas is the computation of
complete sets of invariants polynomials. For local unitary equivalence as well
as $n$-qubit SLOCC invariants, complete descriptions of these invariants exist.
However, these descriptions give infinite sets; of great interest is finding
generating sets of invariants. In this regard, degree bounds are highly sought
after to limit the possible sizes of such generating sets. In this paper we
give new upper bounds on the degrees of the invariants, both for a certain
complete set of local unitary invariants as well as the $n$-qubit SLOCC
invariants. We show that there exists a complete set of local unitary
invariants of density operators in a Hilbert space $\mathcal{H}$, of dimension
$d$, which are generated by invariants of degree at most $d^4$. This in turn
allows us to show that the $n$-qubit SLOCC invariants are generated by
invariants of degree at most $2^{4n}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02107</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02107</id><created>2017-06-07</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garcia-Hernandez</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectroscopic surveys of massive AGB and super-AGB stars</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Invited Review in &quot;The AGB-Supernovae Mass Transition&quot;, MmSAI (in
  press; 6 pages, 3 Figures, and 1 Table); the reference Perez-Mesa et al.
  (2017, now accepted in A&amp;A) has been updated</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is now about 30 years ago that photometric and spectroscopic surveys of
asymptotic giant branch (AGB) stars in the Magellanic Clouds (MCs) uncovered
the first examples of truly massive (&gt; 3-4 M_s) O-rich AGB stars experiencing
hot bottom burning (HBB). Massive (Li-rich) HBB AGB stars were later identified
in our own Galaxy and they pertain to the Galactic population of obscured OH/IR
stars. High-resolution optical spectroscopic surveys have revealed the massive
Galactic AGB stars to be strongly enriched in Rb compared to other nearby
s-process elements like Zr, confirming that Ne22 is the dominant neutron source
in these stars. Similar surveys of OH/IR stars in the MCs disclosed their
Rb-rich low-metallicity counterparts, showing that these stars are usually
brighter (because of HBB flux excess) than the standard adopted luminosity
limit for AGB stars (Mbol~-7.1) and that they might have stellar masses of at
least ~6-7 M_s. The chemical composition and photometric variability are
efficient separating the massive AGB stars from massive red supergiants (RSG)
but the main difficulty is to distinguish between massive AGB and super-AGB
stars because the present theoretical nucleosynthesis models predict both stars
to be chemically identical. Here I review the available multiwavelength (from
the optical to the far-IR) observations on massive AGB and super-AGB stars as
well as the current caveats and limitations in our undestanding of these stars.
Finally, I underline the expected observations on massive AGB and super-AGB
stars from on-going massive surveys like Gaia and SDSS-IV/APOGEE-2 and future
facilities such as the James Webb Space Telescope.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02560</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02560</id><created>2017-06-06</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pavli&#x10d;ek</keyname><forenames>Niko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Majzik</keyname><forenames>Zsolt</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meyer</keyname><forenames>Gerhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gross</keyname><forenames>Leo</forenames></author></authors><title>Passivation of dangling bonds on hydrogenated Si(100)-2$\times$1: a
  possible method for error correction in hydrogen lithography</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.app-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using combined low temperature scanning tunneling microscopy (STM) and atomic
force microscopy (AFM), we demonstrate hydrogen passivation of individual,
selected dangling bonds (DBs) on a hydrogen-passivated Si(100)-2$\times$1
surface (H-Si) by atom manipulation. This method allows erasing of DBs and thus
provides an error-correction scheme for hydrogen lithography. Si-terminated
tips (Si tips) for hydrogen desorption and H-terminated tips (H tips) for
hydrogen passivation are both created by deliberate contact to the H-Si surface
and are assigned by their characteristic contrast in AFM. DB passivation is
achieved by transferring the H atom that is at the apex of an H tip to the DB,
reestablishing a locally defect-free H-Si surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02702</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02702</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Reinhardt</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burgio</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Campagnari</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ebadati</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heffner</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quandt</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vastag</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogt</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Hamiltonian approach to QCD in Coulomb gauge - a survey of recent
  results</title><categories>hep-th hep-lat hep-ph</categories><comments>Talk given by H. Reinhardt at &quot;5th Winter Workshop on
  Non-Perturbative Quantum Field Theory&quot;, 22-24 March 2017, Sophia-Antipolis,
  France. arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1609.09370,
  arXiv:1510.03286, arXiv:1607.08143</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I report on recent results obtained within the Hamiltonian approach to QCD in
Coulomb gauge. Furthermore this approach is compared to recent lattice data,
which were obtained by an alternative gauge fixing method and which show an
improved agreement with the continuum results. By relating the Gribov
confinement scenario to the center vortex picture of confinement it is shown
that the Coulomb string tension is tied to the spatial string tension. For the
quark sector a vacuum wave functional is used which explicitly contains the
coupling of the quarks to the transverse gluons and which results in
variational equations which are free of ultraviolet divergences. The
variational approach is extended to finite temperatures by compactifying a
spatial dimension. The effective potential of the Polyakov loop is evaluated
from the zero-temperature variational solution. For pure Yang--Mills theory,
the deconfinement phase transition is found to be second order for SU(2) and
first order for SU(3), in agreement with the lattice results. The corresponding
critical temperatures are found to be $275 \, \mathrm{MeV}$ and $280 \,
\mathrm{MeV}$, respectively. When quarks are included, the deconfinement
transition turns into a cross-over. From the dual and chiral quark condensate
one finds pseudo-critical temperatures of $198 \, \mathrm{MeV}$ and $170 \,
\mathrm{MeV}$, respectively, for the deconfinement and chiral transition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02720</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02720</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Sudiarta</keyname><forenames>I Wayan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Angraini</keyname><forenames>Lily Maysari</forenames></author></authors><title>The Finite Difference Time Domain (FDTD) Method to Determine Energies
  and Wave Functions of Two-Electron Quantum Dot</title><categories>physics.comp-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The finite difference time domain (FDTD) method has been successfully applied
to obtain energies and wave functions for two electrons in a quantum dot
modeled by a three dimensional harmonic potential. The FDTD method uses the
time-dependent Schr\&quot;odinger equation (TDSE) in imaginary time. The TDSE is
numerically solved with an initial random wave function and after enough
simulation time, the wave function converges to the ground state wave function.
The excited states are determined by using the same procedure for the ground
state with additional constraints that the wave function must be orthogonal
with all lower energy wave functions. The numerical results for energies and
wave functions for different parameters of confinement potentials are given and
compared with published results using other numerical methods. It is shown that
the FDTD method gives accurate energies and wave functions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02721</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02721</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Soeken</keyname><forenames>Mathias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roetteler</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiebe</keyname><forenames>Nathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Micheli</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author></authors><title>Logic Synthesis for Quantum Computing</title><categories>quant-ph cs.ET</categories><comments>15 pages, 10 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a synthesis framework to map logic networks into quantum circuits
for quantum computing. The synthesis framework is based on LUT networks
(lookup-table networks), which play a key role in conventional logic synthesis.
Establishing a connection between LUTs in a LUT network and reversible
single-target gates in a reversible network allows us to bridge conventional
logic synthesis with logic synthesis for quantum computing, despite several
fundamental differences. We call our synthesis framework LUT-based Hierarchical
Reversible Logic Synthesis (LHRS). Input to LHRS is a classical logic network;
output is a quantum network (realized in terms of Clifford+$T$ gates). The
framework offers to trade-off the number of qubits for the number of quantum
gates. In a first step, an initial network is derived that only consists of
single-target gates and already completely determines the number of qubits in
the final quantum network. Different methods are then used to map each
single-target gate into Clifford+$T$ gates, while aiming at optimally using
available resources. We demonstrate the effectiveness of our method in
automatically synthesizing IEEE compliant floating point networks up to double
precision. As many quantum algorithms target scientific simulation
applications, they can make rich use of floating point arithmetic components.
But due to the lack of quantum circuit descriptions for those components, it
can be difficult to find a realistic cost estimation for the algorithms. Our
synthesized benchmarks provide cost estimates that allow quantum algorithm
designers to provide the first complete cost estimates for a host of quantum
algorithms. Thus, the benchmarks and, more generally, the LHRS framework are an
essential step towards the goal of understanding which quantum algorithms will
be practical in the first generations of quantum computers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02723</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02723</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>Ke</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Chiral Ring and Vacua of ${\cal N}=1$ Adjoint SQCD</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph math.QA</categories><comments>42 pages, 2 figures</comments><report-no>CALT-TH-2017-029</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze classical and quantum chiral ring relations of four dimensional
${\cal N} = 1$ adjoint SQCD with superpotential turned on for the adjoint
field. In particular, for the mass deformed theory we obtain the complete on
shell vacuum expectation value for various gauge invariant chiral operators and
find non-trivial gaugino condensations. When approaching to massless limit
nontrivial flat directions in the moduli space of vacua appear, where the
Coulomb branch can be naturally classified and the Higgs branch receives
quantum corrections. We argue that the solution of the chiral ring is in
one-to-one correspondence with supersymmetric vacua, provided that an
additional Konishi anomaly equation is included.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02726</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02726</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Frayer</keyname><forenames>David T.</forenames><affiliation>Green Bank Observatory</affiliation></author></authors><title>Short Spacing Considerations for the ngVLA</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>22 pages, 21 figures. ngVLA Memo#14</comments><report-no>ngVLA Memo#14</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The next generation Very Large Array project (ngVLA) would represent a major
step forward in sensitivity and resolution for radio astronomy, with ability to
achieve 2 milli-arcsec resolution at 100 GHz (assuming a maximum baseline of
300 km). For science on spatial scales of &gt;~ 1 arcsec, the ngVLA project should
consider the use of a large single dish telescope to provide short-spacing
data. Large single-dish telescopes are complementary to interferometers and are
crucial to providing sensitivity to spatial scales lost by interferometry.
Assuming the current vision of the ngVLA (300 18m dishes) and by studying
possible array configurations, I argue that a single dish with a diameter of &gt;=
45m with approximately 20 element receiver systems would be well matched to the
ngVLA for mapping observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02739</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02739</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Freedman</keyname><forenames>Wendy L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmology at at Crossroads: Tension with the Hubble Constant</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>Invited commentary for Nature Astronomy; 10 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature Astronomy, 1, 0169 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We are at an interesting juncture in cosmology. With new methods and
technology, the accuracy in measurement of the Hubble constant has vastly
improved, but a recent tension has arisen that is either signaling new physics
or as-yet unrecognized uncertainties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02745</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02745</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Christensen</keyname><forenames>Lise</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hjorth</keyname><forenames>Jens</forenames></author></authors><title>A break in the high-redshift stellar mass Tully-Fisher relation</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>12 pages, Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1390</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the stellar-mass Tully-Fisher relation (TFR) between the
stellar mass and the integrated gas velocity dispersion, quantified by the
kinematic estimator S_0.5 measured from strong emission lines in spectra of
galaxies at 0&lt;z&lt;5. We combine luminosity-selected galaxies (`high-luminosity
sample') with galaxies selected in other ways (`low-luminosity sample') to
cover a range in stellar mass that spans almost five orders of magnitude: 7.0 &lt;
log M* &lt; 11.5. We find that the logarithmic power-law slope and normalisation
of the TFR are independent of redshift out to z~3. The scatter in the TFR is
&lt;0.5 dex such that the gas velocity dispersion can be used as a proxy for the
stellar mass of a galaxy independently of its redshift. At z&gt;3 the scatter
increases and the existence of a correlation is not obvious. The
high-luminosity sample exhibits a flatter slope of 1.5$\pm$0.2 at z&lt;3 compared
to the low-luminosity sample slope of 2.9$\pm$0.3, suggesting a turnover in the
TFR. The combined sample is well fit with a break in the TFR at a
characteristic stellar mass scale of M*~10$^{10}$ M$_{\odot}$, with no
significant evolution out to z~3. We demonstrate that a break in the TFR with a
steeper slope at the low-mass end is a natural consequence of galaxy models
with a mass-dependent stellar to halo-mass ratio.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02749</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02749</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Patel</keyname><forenames>Rahul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Millan-Gabet</keyname><forenames>Rafael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krist</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beichman</keyname><forenames>Charles</forenames></author></authors><title>Standard FITS template for simulated astrophysical scenes with the
  WFIRST coronagraph</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>8 pages, white paper</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The science investigation teams (SITs) for the WFIRST coronagraphic
instrument have begun studying the capabilities of the instrument to directly
image reflected light off from exoplanets at contrasts down to contrasts of
~10^-9 with respect to the stellar flux. Detection of point sources at these
high contrasts requires yield estimates and detailed modeling of the image of
the planetary system as it propagates through the telescope optics. While the
SITs might generate custom astrophysical scenes, the integrated model,
propagated through the internal speckle field, is typically done at JPL. In
this white paper, we present a standard file format to ensure a single
distribution system between those who produce the raw astrophysical scenes, and
JPL modelers who incorporate those scenes into their optical modeling. At its
core, our custom file format uses FITS files, and incorporates standards on
packaging astrophysical scenes. This includes spectral and astrometric
information for planetary and stellar point sources, zodiacal light and
extragalactic sources that may appear as contaminants. Adhering to such a
uniform data distribution format is necessary, as it ensures seamless work flow
between the SITs and modelers at JPL for the goals of understanding limits of
the WFIRST coronagraphic instrument.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02754</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02754</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Athari</keyname><forenames>Mir Hadi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhifang</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistically Characterizing the Electrical Parameters of the Grid
  Transformers and Transmission Lines</title><categories>stat.AP physics.data-an</categories><comments>To be published (Accepted) in: The 10th Bulk Power Systems Dynamics
  and Control Symposium (IREP2017), Espinho, Portugal, 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents a set of validation metrics for transmission network
parameters that is applicable in both creation of synthetic power system test
cases and validation of existing models. Using actual data from two real-world
power grids, statistical analyses are performed to extract some useful
statistics on transformers and transmission lines electrical parameters
including per unit reactance, MVA rating, and their X/R ratio. It is found that
conversion of per unit reactance calculated on system common base to
transformer own power base will significantly stabilize its range and remove
the correlation between per unit X and MVA rating. This is fairly consistent
for transformers with different voltage levels and sizes and can be utilized as
a strong validation metric for synthetic models. It is found that transmission
lines exhibit different statistical properties than transformers with different
distribution and range for the parameters. In addition, statistical analysis
shows that the empirical PDF of transmission network electrical parameters can
be approximated with mathematical distribution functions which would help
appropriately characterize them in synthetic power networks. Kullback-Leibler
divergence is used as a measure for goodness of fit for approximated
distributions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02762</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02762</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Athari</keyname><forenames>Mir Hadi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhifang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eylas</keyname><forenames>Seyed Hamid</forenames></author></authors><title>Time-Series Analysis of Photovoltaic Distributed Generation Impacts on a
  Local Distributed Network</title><categories>physics.app-ph</categories><comments>To be published (Accepted) in: 12th IEEE PES PowerTech Conference,
  Manchester, UK, 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Increasing penetration level of photovoltaic (PV) distributed generation (DG)
into distribution networks will have many impacts on nominal circuit operating
conditions including voltage quality and reverse power flow issues. In U.S.
most studies on PVDG impacts on distribution networks are performed for west
coast and central states. The objective of this paper is to study the impacts
of PVDG integration on local distribution network based on real-world settings
for network parameters and time-series analysis. PVDG penetration level is
considered to find the hosting capacity of the network without having major
issues in terms of voltage quality and reverse power flow. Time-series analyses
show that distributed installation of PVDGs on commercial buses has the maximum
network energy loss reduction and larger penetration ratios for them.
Additionally, the penetration ratio thresholds for which there will be no power
quality and reverse power flow issues and optimal allocation of PVDG and
penetration levels are identified for different installation scenarios.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02770</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02770</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Sadeghian</keyname><forenames>Hamidreza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Athari</keyname><forenames>Mir Hadi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhifang</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimized Solar Photovoltaic Generation in a Real Local Distribution
  Network</title><categories>physics.app-ph</categories><comments>To be published (Accepted) in: Proceedings of the IEEE PES Innovative
  Smart Grid Technologies Conference (ISGT), Washington D.C., USA, 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Remarkable penetration of renewable energy in electric networks, despite its
valuable opportunities, such as power loss reduction and loadability
improvements, has raised concerns for system operators. Such huge penetration
can lead to a violation of the grid requirements, such as voltage and current
limits and reverse power flow. Optimal placement and sizing of Distributed
Generation (DG) are one of the best ways to strengthen the efficiency of the
power systems. This paper builds a simulation model for the local distribution
network based on obtained load profiles, GIS information, solar insolation,
feeder and voltage settings, and define the optimization problem of solar PVDG
installation to determine the optimal siting and sizing for different
penetration levels with different objective functions. The objective functions
include voltage profile improvement and energy loss minimization and the
considered constraints include the physical distribution network constraints
(AC power flow), the PV capacity constraint, and the voltage and reverse power
flow constraints.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02772</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02772</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Webber</keyname><forenames>W. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stone</keyname><forenames>E. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cummings</keyname><forenames>A. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heikkila</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lal</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Intensities of Cosmic Ray H and He Nuclei at ~250 MeV/nuc Measured
  by Voyagers 1 and 2 - Using these Intensities to Determine the Solar
  Modulation Parameter in the Inner Heliosphere and the Heliosheath Over a 40
  Year Time Period</title><categories>physics.space-ph</categories><comments>28 pages, 9 Figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have determined the solar modulation potential, phi, vs. time that is
observed at Voyager 1 and 2 from measurements of the H and He nuclei
intensities at a common energy of 250 MeVnuc. The H nuclei have a rigidity 0.7
GV, the He nuclei 1.4 GV. These measurements cover a 40 year time period, which
includes almost 4 cycles of solar 11 year sunspot variations, throughout the
inner heliosphere out to the HTS at distances of 95 AU and 85 AU, respectively
at V1 and V2, and then beyond in the heliosheath. Inside the HTS the modulation
potential vs. time curves at V1 and V2 show a very similar temporal structure
to those observed at the Earth. During a later period of maximum solar
modulation from 2000.0 to 2005.0 when V1 and V2 are in the outer heliosphere
between 60-94 AU, the main temporal features of the modulation potential curves
at all 3 locations match up with appropriate time delays at V1 and V2 if it is
assumed that spatially coherent structures are moving outward past V1 and V2,
with outward speeds of up to 700 Kms negative 1. After 2004.0 V1 and V2 are at
latitudes of positive 35 and negative 30 respectively, placing lower limits on
the latitude extent of these structures. Beyond the HTS in the heliosheath the
modulation potential slowly decreases at both spacecraft with only a weak
evidence of the unusual modulation minimum observed at the Earth in 2009, for
example. A sudden decrease of the modulation potential 50 MV for both H and He
nuclei occurs at V1 just before the heliopause crossing at about 122 AU. This
decrease has not yet been observed at V2, which is now at 113 AU and still
observing a modulation potential 60 MV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02774</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02774</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Druffel</keyname><forenames>Daniel L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuntz</keyname><forenames>Kaci L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Woomer</keyname><forenames>Adam H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alcorn</keyname><forenames>Francis M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Donley</keyname><forenames>Carrie L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Warren</keyname><forenames>Scott C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental Demonstration of an Electride as a 2D Material</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Journal of the American Chemical Society, 138, 16089-16094 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/jacs.6b10114</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Because of their loosely bound electrons, electrides offer physical
properties useful in chemical synthesis and electronics. For these applications
and others, nano-sized electrides offer advantages, but to-date no electride
has been synthesized as a nanomaterial. We demonstrate experimentally that
Ca$_2$N, a layered electride in which layers of atoms are separated by layers
of a 2D electron gas (2DEG), can be exfoliated into two-dimensional (2D)
nanosheets using liquid exfoliation. The 2D flakes are stable in a nitrogen
atmosphere or in select organic solvents for at least one month. Electron
microscopy and elemental analysis reveal that the 2D flakes retain the crystal
structure and stoichiometry of the parent 3D Ca$_2$N. In addition, the 2D
flakes exhibit metallic character and an optical response that agrees with DFT
calculations. Together these findings suggest that the 2DEG is preserved in the
2D material. With this work, we bring electrides into the nano-regime and
experimentally demonstrate a 2D electride, Ca$_2$N.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02779</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02779</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Sromovsky</keyname><forenames>L. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baines</keyname><forenames>K. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fry</keyname><forenames>P. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carlson</keyname><forenames>R. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>A possibly universal red chromophore for modeling color variations on
  Jupiter</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>13 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Icarus 291 (2017) 232-244</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.icarus.2016.12.014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new laboratory-generated chemical compound made from photodissociated
ammonia (NH3) molecules reacting with acetylene (C2H2) was suggested as a
possible coloring agent for Jupiter's Great Red Spot (GRS) by Carlson et al.
(2016, Icarus 274, 106-115). Baines et al. (2016, Icarus, submitted) showed
that the GRS spectrum measured by the visual channels of the Cassini VIMS
instrument in 2000 could be accurately fit by a cloud model in which the
chromophore appeared as a physically thin layer of small particles immediately
above the main cloud layer of the GRS. Here we show that the same chromophore
and same layer location can also provide close matches to the short wave
spectra of many other cloud features on Jupiter, suggesting this material may
be a nearly universal chromophore that could explain the various degrees of red
coloration on Jupiter. This is a robust conclusion, even for 12% changes in
VIMS calibration and large uncertainties in the refractive index of the main
cloud layer due to uncertain fractions of NH4SH and NH3 in its cloud particles.
The chromophore layer can account for color variations among north and south
equatorial belts, equatorial zone, and the Great Red Spot, by varying particle
size from 0.12 microns to 0.29 microns and 1-micron optical depth from 0.06 to
0.76. The total mass of the chromophore layer is much less variable, ranging
from 18 to 30 micrograms/cm^2, except in the equatorial zone, where it is only
10-13 micrograms/cm^2. We also found a depression of the ammonia volume mixing
ratio in the two belt regions, which averaged 0.4-0.5 X 10^{-4} immediately
below the ammonia condensation level, while the other regions averaged twice
that value.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02784</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02784</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Usman</keyname><forenames>Muhammad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qadir</keyname><forenames>Asghar</forenames></author></authors><title>The extra scalar degrees of freedom from the two Higgs doublet model for
  dark energy</title><categories>physics.gen-ph hep-ph</categories><comments>20 pages, 4 figures, Presented at Fifth Italian-Pakistani Workshop on
  Relativistic Astrophysics</comments><msc-class>85A40</msc-class><journal-ref>Int. J. Mod. Phys. D 26, 1741003 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218271817410036</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In principle a minimal extension of the standard model of Particle Physics,
the two Higgs doublet model, can be invoked to explain the scalar field
responsible of dark energy. The two doublets are in general mixed. After
diagonalization, the lightest CP-even Higgs and CP-odd Higgs are jointly taken
to be the dark energy candidate. The dark energy obtained from Higgs fields in
this case is indistinguishable from the cosmological constant.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02790</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02790</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Silverstein</keyname><forenames>Eva</forenames></author></authors><title>The dangerous irrelevance of string theory</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>12 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We comment on the relation between string theory and empirical science,
grounding our discussion in cosmology, a subject with increasingly precise data
in which this connection operates at several levels. It is important to take
into account the phenomenon of dangerous irrelevance: over long times or large
field ranges, physics can become sensitive to higher scales than the input
energies. This pertains in inflationary cosmology (and possibly other aspects
of horizon physics). String theory also contributes to our understanding of
observational constraints and search strategies at the level of low energy
field theory. We illustrate this with a current example concerning a new form
of non-Gaussianity generated by very massive degrees of freedom coupling to the
inflaton. New constraints on such fields and couplings can be obtained from
existing data, increasing our empirical knowledge of the universe. This builds
in part from the development of the string landscape, which is neither random
nor an abdication of science as has sometimes been suggested. {\it Invited
contribution to the proceedings of the conference `Why trust a theory'.}
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02804</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02804</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Schich</keyname><forenames>Maximilian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huemer</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adamczyk</keyname><forenames>Piotr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manovich</keyname><forenames>Lev</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yang-Yu</forenames></author></authors><title>Network Dimensions in the Getty Provenance Index</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>13 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article we make a case for a systematic application of complex
network science to study art market history and more general collection
dynamics. We reveal social, temporal, spatial, and conceptual network
dimensions, i.e. network node and link types, previously implicit in the Getty
Provenance Index (GPI). As a pioneering art history database active since the
1980s, the GPI provides online access to source material relevant for research
in the history of collecting and art markets. Based on a subset of the GPI, we
characterize an aggregate of more than 267,000 sales transactions connected to
roughly 22,000 actors in four countries over 20 years at daily resolution from
1801 to 1820. Striving towards a deeper understanding on multiple levels we
disambiguate social dynamics of buying, brokering, and selling, while observing
a general broadening of the market, where large collections are split into
smaller lots. Temporally, we find annual market cycles that are shifted by
country and obviously favor international exchange. Spatially, we differentiate
near-monopolies from regions driven by competing sub-centers, while uncovering
asymmetries of international market flux. Conceptually, we track dynamics of
artist attribution that clearly behave like product categories in a very slow
supermarket. Taken together, we introduce a number of meaningful network
perspectives dealing with historical art auction data, beyond the analysis of
social networks within a single market region. The results presented here have
inspired a Linked Open Data conversion of the GPI, which is currently in
process and will allow further analysis by a broad set of researchers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02837</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02837</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Lhuillier</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel</forenames></author></authors><title>Optoelectronics of confined semiconductors : the case of colloidal
  nanocrystals and their application to photodetection</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>the perspective section has been intentionally removed</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work summarizes recent development in the filed of nanocrystal and their
use for optoelectronics. After the introduction on nanocrystals and their
transport properties, the manuscript is splitted in three parts : (i) narrow
abnd gap materials, (ii) 2D colloidal material and (iii) van der waals
heterostrctures
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02846</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02846</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Starodub</keyname><forenames>S. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roshchupkin</keyname><forenames>S. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dubov</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase shift's influence of two strong pulsed laser waves on effective
  interaction of electrons</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with arXiv:1705.10336</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The phase shift's influence of two strong pulsed laser waves on effective
interaction of electrons was studied. Considerable amplification of electrons
repulsion in the certain range of phase shifts and waves intensities is shown.
That leads to electrons scatter on greater distances than without an external
field. The value of the distance can be greater on 2-3 order of magnitude. Also
considerable influence of the phase shift of pulses of waves on the possibility
of effective attraction of electrons is shown.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02849</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02849</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Anderson</keyname><forenames>Johan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hnat</keyname><forenames>Bogdan</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistical analysis of Hasegawa - Wakatani turbulence</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><journal-ref>Physics of Plasmas 24, 062301 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4984985</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Resistive drift wave turbulence is a multipurpose paradigm that can be used
to understand transport at the edge of fusion devices. The Hasegawa-Wakatani
model captures the essential physics of drift turbulence while retaining the
simplicity needed to gain a qualitative understanding of this process. We
provide a theoretical interpretation of numerically generated probability
density functions (PDFs) of intermittent events in Hasegawa-Wakatani turbulence
with enforced equipartition of energy in large scale zonal flows and small
scale drift turbulence. We find that for a wide range of adiabatic index values
the stochastic component representing the small scale turbulent eddies of the
flow, obtained from the ARIMA model, exhibits super-diffusive statistics,
consistent with intermittent transport. The PDFs of large events (above one
standard deviation) are well approximated by the Laplace distribution, while
small events often exhibit a Gaussian character. Furthermore there exist a
strong influence of zonal flows for example, via shearing and then viscous
dissipation maintaining a sub-diffusive character of the fluxes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02876</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02876</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Convertino</keyname><forenames>Domenica</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luin</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marchetti</keyname><forenames>Laura</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coletti</keyname><forenames>Camilla</forenames></author></authors><title>Peripheral neuron survival and outgrowth on graphene</title><categories>physics.bio-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Graphene displays properties which make it appealing for neuroregenerative
medicine, yet its interaction with peripheral neurons has been scarcely
investigated. Here, we culture on graphene two established models for
peripheral neurons: PC12 cells and DRG primary neurons. We perform a
nano-resolved analysis of polymeric coatings on graphene and combine optical
microscopy and viability assays to assess the material cytocompatibility and
influence on differentiation. We find that differentiated PC12 cells display a
remarkably increased neurite length on graphene (up to 35%) with respect to
controls. DRG primary neurons survive both on bare and coated graphene and
present dense axonal networks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02895</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02895</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Sarkar</keyname><forenames>Jayanta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Padurariu</keyname><forenames>Ciprian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Puska</keyname><forenames>Antti</forenames></author><author><keyname>Golubev</keyname><forenames>Dmitry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hakonen</keyname><forenames>Pertti J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Hanbury-Brown and Twiss exchange effects in a four-terminal tunnel
  junction</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the current-current correlations in a four-terminal Al-AlOx-Al
tunnel junction where shot noise dominates. We demonstrate that
cross-correlations in the presence of two biasing sources of the Hanbury-Brown
and Twiss type are much stronger (approximately twice) than an incoherent sum
of correlations generated by single sources. The difference is due to voltage
fluctuations of the central island that give rise to current-current
correlations in the four contacts of the junction. Our measurements are in
close agreement with results obtained using a simple theoretical model based on
the theory of shot noise in multi-terminal conductors, generalized here to
arbitrary contacts.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02905</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02905</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Takano</keyname><forenames>Tetsushi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mizushima</keyname><forenames>Ray</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katori</keyname><forenames>Hidetoshi</forenames></author></authors><title>Precise determination of the isotope shift of ${}^{88}$Sr - ${}^{87}$Sr
  optical lattice clock by sharing perturbations</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Express 10, 072801 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.7567/APEX.10.072801</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the isotope shift between ${}^{88}$Sr and ${}^{87}$Sr on the
${}^1S_0 - {}^3P_0$ clock transitions. The interleaved operation of an optical
lattice clock with two isotopes allows the canceling out of common
perturbations, such as the quadratic Zeeman shift, the clock-light shift, and
the blackbody radiation shift. The isotope shift is determined to be 62 188
134.004(10) Hz, where the major uncertainty is introduced by the collisional
shift that is distinct for each isotope. Our result allows us to determine the
frequency of $^{88}$Sr-$^{87}$Sr optical lattice clocks with a fractional
uncertainty of $2\times 10^{-17}$. The scheme is generally applicable for
measuring the isotope shift with significantly reduced uncertainty.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02915</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02915</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Ghasemnezhad</keyname><forenames>Maryam</forenames></author></authors><title>Structure of a hot accretion flow in the presence of outflow and
  convection with large ordered magnetic field</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 Figures, Accepted for publication in MNRAS. arXiv admin
  note: text overlap with arXiv:1705.08356</comments><journal-ref>Mon Not R Astron Soc (2017) 469 (3): 3322-3328</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1118</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hydrodynamics and magnetohydrodynamic simulations of hot accretion flow have
indicated that there is an inward decreasing of mass accretion rate with
decreasing radius. Consequently, we have a flatter density profile ($\rho
\propto r^{-p}$ with $p\propto 1.5-s$ in the case of $\dot{M}\propto r^{s}$, $0
\leq s&lt;1$) compared to the case of a constant accretion rate (($\rho \propto
r^{-\frac{3}{2}}$). In order to describe this behavior two models have been
proposed: inflow-outflow solution and convection-dominated accretion flows. We
have studied the properties of a hot accretion flow in the presence of
convection, large scale magnetic field and outflow. We consider an axisymmetric
viscous flow in the steady state. We used the self-similar solutions to solve
the 1.5 dimensional inflow-outflow equations. We have assumed that the
convection as a free parameter in our model for simplicity. We have considered
two components of magnetic field (toroidal and vertical) in this paper. We have
shown that the strong convection makes the inflow accretes and rotates slower
while it becomes hotter and thicker. We have found that the thickness of the
disc deviates from non-convective solutions obviously. We have represented that
two components of magnetic field have the opposite effects on the thickness of
the disc and similar effects on the radial and angular velocities of the flow.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02920</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02920</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Kvashnina</keyname><forenames>K. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walker</keyname><forenames>H. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Magnani</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lander</keyname><forenames>G. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caciuffo</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Resonant x-ray spectroscopy of uranium intermetallics at the U $M_{4,5}$
  edges</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>11 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 245103 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.245103</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present resonant x-ray emission spectroscopic (RXES) data from the uranium
intermetallics UPd$_3$, USb, USn$_3$ and URu$_2$Si$_2$, at the U $M_{4,5}$
edges and compare the data to those from the well-localized $5f^2$
semiconductor UO$_2$. The technique is especially sensitive to any oxidation of
the surface, and this was found on the USb sample, thus preventing a good
comparison with a material known to be $5f^3$. We have found a small energy
shift between UO$_2$ and UPd$_3$, both known to have localized $5f^2$
configurations, which we ascribe to the effect of conduction electrons in
UPd$_3$. The spectra from UPd$_3$ and URu$_2$Si$_2$,are similar, strongly
suggesting a predominant $5f^2$ configuration for URu$_2$Si$_2$. The
valence-band resonant inelastic x-ray scattering (RIXS) provides information on
the U $P_3$ transitions (at about $18$~eV) between the U $5f$ and U $6p$
states, as well as transitions of between $3$ and $7$~eV from the valence band
into the unoccupied $5f$ states. These transitions are primarily involving
mixed ligand states (O $2p$ or Pd, Ru $4d$) and U $5f$ states. Calculations are
able to reproduce both these low-energy transitions reasonably well.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02923</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02923</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Fomin</keyname><forenames>Yu. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsiok</keyname><forenames>E. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ryzhov</keyname><forenames>V. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brazhkin</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>A novel anomalous region of water</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Water is the most important liquid in the Universe. At the same time it is
the most anomalous liquid. It demonstrates several dozens of anomalies, among
which are density anomaly, diffusion anomaly etc. Anomalous behavior of water
is a topic numerous publications. However, most of the publications investigate
the anomalous behavior of water in the vicinity of critical points: the
liquid-gas critical point and the second hypothetical critical point in
supercooled region. Here we analyze experimental data on such properties of
water as heat capacity, speed of sound, dynamic viscosity and thermal
conductivity. We show that these properties demonstrate anomalous maxima and
minima in a region which is far from both critical points. Therefore, we find a
novel region of anomalous properties of water (anomalous triangle) which cannot
be related to critical fluctuations. We also perform a molecular dynamics
simulations of this region with two common water models - SPC/E and TIP4P - and
show that these models fail to describe the novel anomalous region.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02931</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02931</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Johnsen</keyname><forenames>Sverre Gullikstad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johansen</keyname><forenames>Stein Tore</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wittgens</keyname><forenames>Bernd</forenames></author></authors><title>A wall-function approach for direct precipitation/crystallization
  fouling in cfd modelling</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>Proceedings of International COnference on Heat Exchanger Fouling and
  Cleaning - 2015, June 7-12, 2015, Enfield, Ireland Editors: M.R. Malayeri, H.
  M\&quot;uller-Steinhagen and A.P. Watkinson 9 pages, 7 figures, 3 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The main objective of this paper is to present a generic modelling framework,
for the diffusive mass transport through the turbulent, reactive boundary layer
of multi-component fluid mixtures that precipitate on the wall. The modelling
is based on Maxwell-Stefan diffusion in multi-component mixtures, the
relaxation to chemical equilibrium model, and the single-phase Navier-Stokes
equations. Final-ly, turbulence is introduced by Reynolds-averaging. The
governing equations are simplified in accordance with common assumptions of
computational fluid dynamics (CFD), and based on the assumption that the
over-all bulk flow is parallel to the wall, 1-dimensional equations for the
species and heat transport perpendicular to the wall have been formulated. The
equations are solved on a fine grid in order to fully resolve the boundary
layer, and the effect of allowing/disallowing deposition and chemical reactions
was investigated for a simplified test-case (4-component ideal mixture of
perfect gasses capable of chemical reaction and sublimation fouling).
  The developed framework can be employed as a sub-grid model for direct
precipitation/crystallization/solidifica-tion fouling in coarse grid CFD
models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02941</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02941</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Heydenreich</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Hofstad</keyname><forenames>Remco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hulshof</keyname><forenames>Tim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miermont</keyname><forenames>Gr&#xe9;gory</forenames></author></authors><title>Backbone scaling limit of the high-dimensional IIC: extended version</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>This is a thorough revision of a previous submission,
  arXiv:1301.3486v2, which was retracted because of an error in the proof. The
  results presented here are the same as those claimed in arXiv:1301.3486v2
  (modulo a few details), but large parts of the proof are different. 86 pages,
  46 figures</comments><msc-class>60K35 (primary), 60K37, 82B43 (secondary)</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We identify the scaling limit of the backbone of the high-dimensional
incipient infinite cluster (IIC), both in the finite-range and the long-range
setting. In the finite-range setting, this scaling limit is Brownian motion, in
the long-range setting, it is a stable motion. The proof relies on a novel lace
expansion that keeps track of the number of pivotal bonds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02955</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02955</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Bing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Liu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Qing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Min</forenames></author></authors><title>Radiation Pressure Cooling as a Quantum Dynamical Process</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 page main text + 10 page wide texted supplementary information</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 233604 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.233604</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One of the most fundamental problems in optomechanical cooling is how small
the thermal phonon number of a mechanical oscillator can be achieved under the
radiation pressure of a proper cavity field. Different from previous
theoretical predictions, which were based on an optomechanical system's
time-independent steady states, we treat such cooling as a dynamical process of
driving the mechanical oscillator from its initial thermal state, due to its
thermal equilibrium with the environment, to a stabilized quantum state of
higher purity. We find that the stabilized thermal phonon number left in the
end actually depends on how fast the cooling process could be. The cooling
speed is decided by an effective optomechanical coupling intensity, which
constitutes an essential parameter for cooling, in addition to the sideband
resolution parameter that has been considered in other theoretical studies. The
limiting thermal phonon number that any cooling process cannot surpass exhibits
a discontinuous jump across a certain value of the parameter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02958</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02958</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Giannopoulou</keyname><forenames>Konstantina-Stavroula</forenames></author></authors><title>Asymptotic approximation of the winger function in two-phase geometric
  optics</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>85 pages, 4 figures, Master (MSc) thesis</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a renormalization process of a two phase WKB solution, which is
based on an appropriate surgery of local uniform asymptotic approximations of
the Wigner transform of the WKB solution. We explain in details how this
process provides the correct spatial variation and frequency scales of the wave
field on the caustics where WKB method fails. The analysis has been thoroughly
presented in the case of a fundamental problem, that is the semiclassical Airy
equation, which arises from the model problem of acoustic propagation in a
layer with linear variation of the sound speed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02960</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02960</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Navia</keyname><forenames>Carlos E.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the rotation curves of galaxies at low and high redshifts</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>14 pages, 12 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The thermal history of the Universe is included in the Debye Gravitational
Theory (DGT) to describe the speed of rotation of the galaxies. The DGT
incorporate the temperature of Debye in the entropic gravitational theory.
According to the DGT, the expression of the rotation of the galaxies is not a
continuous function of the redshift, there is a discontinuity at $\sim 0.77$.
According to their redshift, the galaxies form two groups. (a) Those with
redshift above 0.77 with declining rotation curves like $R^{\beta}$ with $\beta
\leq -0.5$ (Newtonian regime). (b) Those with redshift below 0.77 with rising
rotation curves like $R^{\beta}$ with $\beta \geq 0$ (Mondian regime). At
$z\sim 0.77 $ an extra boost (Dirac delta-like twisting force) led the galaxies
to spin very fast.This scenario is consistent with a mysterious entity such as
the dark energy and that at $z\sim 0.77 $, in addition to accelerating the
expansion, boosted the rotation of the galaxies again, inducing a transition
between the Newtonian regime to the Mondian regime. It is possible to check
that the characteristics on galaxy rotations provided by the DGT for a broad
range of redshift from $z\sim 4$ to $z=0$ are in agreement with the
observations. We believe that the change in the form of rotation of galaxies at
$z\sim 0.77$ is new evidence for the hypothesis of dark energy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02963</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02963</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Runzhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Biao</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultrasound attenuation in $s^\pm$-wave two-band superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The two-band $s^{\pm}$-wave state is currently considered to be the most
promising candidate for newly discovered iron-based high-$T_c$ superconductors.
In this work we study theoretically the ultrasound attenuation in
$s^{\pm}$-wave two-band superconductors. The impurity effect is calculated
within the $\mathcal{T}$-matrix approximation. In particular, our theory
predict that, when the sizes of two order parameter are comparable, a
Hebel-Slichter peak may show up in the ultrasound attenuation versus
temperature curves. Our calculations also confirmed the presence of the
resonant impurity scattering at low temperature, observed previously by other
authors in the calculation of the NMR relaxation rate $1/T_{1}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02965</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02965</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>Bryan W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sung</keyname><forenames>Chih-Jen</forenames></author></authors><title>Comparative Autoignition Trends in the Butanol Isomers at Elevated
  Pressure</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>49 pages, 21 figures, 10 tables</comments><journal-ref>Energy &amp; Fuels vol. 27, no. 3 (March 2013): 1688-1698</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/ef302195c</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Autoignition experiments of stoichiometric mixtures of s-, t-, and i-butanol
in air have been performed using a heated rapid compression machine (RCM). At
compressed pressures of 15 and 30 bar and for compressed temperatures in the
range of 715-910 K, no evidence of a negative temperature coefficient region in
terms of ignition delay response is found. The present experimental results are
also compared with previously reported RCM data of n-butanol in air. The order
of reactivity of the butanols is
n-butanol&gt;s-butanol$\approx$i-butanol&gt;t-butanol at the lower pressure, but
changes to n-butanol&gt;t-butanol&gt;s-butanol&gt;i-butanol at higher pressure. In
addition, t-butanol shows pre-ignition heat release behavior, which is
especially evident at higher pressures. To help identify the controlling
chemistry leading to this pre-ignition heat release, off-stoichiometric
experiments are further performed at 30 bar compressed pressure, for t-butanol
at $\phi$ = 0.5 and $\phi$ = 2.0 in air. For these experiments, higher fuel
loading (i.e. $\phi$ = 2.0) causes greater pre-ignition heat release (as
indicated by greater pressure rise) than the stoichiometric or $\phi$ = 0.5
cases. Comparison of the experimental ignition delays with the simulated
results using two literature kinetic mechanisms shows generally good agreement,
and one mechanism is further used to explore and compare the fuel decomposition
pathways of the butanol isomers. Using this mechanism, the importance of peroxy
chemistry in the autoignition of the butanol isomers is highlighted and
discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02967</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02967</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>P. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>G. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Q. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sj&#xf6;qvist</keyname><forenames>Erik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tong</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Single-shot realization of nonadiabatic holonomic quantum gates in
  decoherence-free subspaces</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, no figure</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 062310 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.062310</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nonadiabatic holonomic quantum computation in decoherence-free subspaces has
attracted increasing attention recently, as it allows for high-speed
implementation and combines both the robustness of holonomic gates and the
coherence stabilization of decoherence-free subspaces. Since the first protocol
of nonadiabatic holonomic quantum computation in decoherence-free subspaces, a
number of schemes for its physical implementation have been put forward.
However, all previous schemes require two noncommuting gates to realize an
arbitrary one-qubit gate, which doubles the exposure time of gates to error
sources as well as the resource expenditure. In this paper, we propose an
alternative protocol for nonadiabatic holonomic quantum computation in
decoherence-free subspaces, in which an arbitrary one-qubit gate in
decoherence-free subspaces is realized by a single-shot implementation. The
present protocol not only maintains the merits of the original protocol, but
also avoids the extra work of combining two gates to implement an arbitrary
one-qubit gate and thereby reduces the exposure time to various error sources.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02971</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02971</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fu</keyname><forenames>Xin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shanker</keyname><forenames>Balasubramaniam</forenames></author></authors><title>Decoupled Potential Integral Equations for Electromagnetic Scattering
  from Dielectric Objects</title><categories>physics.comp-ph</categories><msc-class>45Axx, 45Bxx, 45Exx, 45Fxx, 65Rxx</msc-class><acm-class>G.1.9</acm-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent work on developing novel integral equation formulations has involved
using potentials as opposed to fields. This is a consequence of the additional
flexibility offered by using potentials to develop well conditioned systems.
Most of the work in this arena has wrestled with developing this formulation
for perfectly conducting objects (Vico et al., 2014 and Liu et al., 2015), with
recent effort made to addressing similar problems for dielectrics (Li et al.,
2017). In this paper, we present well-conditioned decoupled potential integral
equation (DPIE) formulated for electromagnetic scattering from homogeneous
dielectric objects, a fully developed version of that presented in the
conference communication (Li et al., 2017). The formulation is based on
boundary conditions derived for decoupled boundary conditions on the scalar and
vector potentials. The resulting DPIE is the second kind integral equation, and
does not suffer from either low frequency or dense mesh breakdown. Analytical
properties of the DPIE are studied. Results on the sphere analysis are provided
to demonstrate the conditioning and spectrum of the resulting linear system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02979</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02979</id><created>2017-06-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Burinskii</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>Stability of the lepton bag model based on the Kerr-Newman solution</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>20 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>JETP (Zh. Eksp. Teor. Fiz.) 148 (2015) 937</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S1063776115110023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the considered in previous paper \cite{BurGrBag} lepton bag
model, generating the external gravitational and electromagnetic fields of the
Kerr-Newman (KN) solution is supersymmetric and represents a BPS-saturated
soliton, interpolating between internal vacuum state and external KN solution.
We obtain Bogomolnyi equations for this phase transition, and show that
Bogomolnyi bound determines all important features of this bag model, including
its stable shape.
  In particular, for stationary KN solution the BPS-bound provides stability of
the ellipsoidal form of the bag and formation of the ring-string structure at
its border, while for the periodic electromagnetic excitations of the KN
solution, the BPS-bound controls deformation of the surface of the bag,
reproducing the known flexibility of bag models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02984</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02984</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Garofalo</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic Fields Threading Black Holes: restrictions from general
  relativity and implications for astrophysical black holes</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Astrophys Space Sci (2017) 362:121</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10509-017-3108-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The idea that black hole spin is instrumental in the generation of powerful
jets in active galactic nuclei and X-ray binaries is arguably the most
contentious claim in black hole astrophysics. Because jets are thought to
originate in the context of electromagnetism, and the modeling of Maxwell
fields in curved spacetime around black holes is challenging, various
approximations are made in numerical simulations that fall under the guise of
'ideal magnetohydrodynamics'. But the simplifications of this framework may
struggle to capture relevant details of real astrophysical environments near
black holes. In this work, we highlight tension between analytic and numerical
results, specifically between the analytically derived conserved Noether
currents for rotating black hole spacetimes and the results of general
relativistic numerical simulations (GRMHD). While we cannot definitively
attribute the issue to any specific approximation used in the numerical
schemes, there seem to be natural candidates, which we explore. GRMHD
notwithstanding, if electromagnetic fields around rotating black holes are
brought to the hole by accretion, we show from first principles that prograde
accreting disks likely experience weaker large-scale black hole-threading
fields, implying weaker jets than in retrograde configurations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02987</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02987</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>L&#xf3;pez-Moreno</keyname><forenames>Sinhu&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodr&#xed;guez-Hern&#xe1;ndez</keyname><forenames>Pl&#xe1;cida</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mu&#xf1;oz</keyname><forenames>Alfonso</forenames></author><author><keyname>Errandonea</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author></authors><title>First-Principles Study of InVO4 under Pressure: Phase Transitions from
  CrVO4- to AgMnO4-Type Structure</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Inorg. Chem. 56, 2697 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.inorgchem.6b02867</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  First-principles calculations have been carried out to study the InVO4
compound under pressure. In this work, total energy calculations were performed
in order to analyze the structural behavior of the experimentally known
polymorphs of InVO4: a-MnMoO4-type (I), CrVO4-type (III), and wolframite (V).
In addition, in this paper we present our results about the stability of this
compound beyond the pressures reached by experiments. We propose some new
high-pressure phases on the basis of the study of 13 possible candidates. The
quasi-harmonic approximation has been used to calculate the sequence of phase
transitions at 300 K: CrVO4-type, III (the transition pressure is given in
parentheses) -&gt; wolframite, V (4.4 GPa) -&gt; raspite, VI (28.1 GPa) -&gt;
AgMnO4-type, VII (44 GPa). Equations of state and phonon frequencies as a
function of pressure have been calculated for the studied phases. In order to
determine the stability of each phase, we also report the phonon dispersion
along the Brillouin zone and the phonon density of states for the most stable
polymorphs. Finally, the electronic band structure for the low- and
high-pressure phases for the studied polymorphs is presented as well as the
pressure evolution of the band gap by using the HSE06 hybrid functional.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02996</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02996</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>Bryan W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pitz</keyname><forenames>WIlliam J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mehl</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silke</keyname><forenames>Emma</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davis</keyname><forenames>Alexander C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sung</keyname><forenames>Chih-Jen</forenames></author></authors><title>Experiments and Modeling of the Autoignition of Methylcyclohexane at
  High Pressure</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>38 pages, 12 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>Combustion and Flame, vol. 161, no. 8 (August 2014): 1972-1983</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.combustflame.2014.01.018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  New experimental data are collected for methyl-cyclohexane (MCH) autoignition
in a heated rapid compression machine (RCM). Three mixtures of MCH/O2/N2/Ar at
equivalence ratios of $\phi$=0.5, 1.0, and 1.5 are studied and the ignition
delays are measured at compressed pressure of 50 bar and for compressed
temperatures in the range of 690-900 K. By keeping the fuel mole fraction in
the mixture constant, the order of reactivity, in terms of inverse ignition
delay, is measured to be $\phi$=0.5 &gt; $\phi$=1.0 &gt; $\phi$=1.5, demonstrating
the dependence of the ignition delay on oxygen concentration. In addition, an
existing model for the combustion of MCH is updated with new reaction rates and
pathways, including substantial updates to the low-temperature chemistry. The
new model shows good agreement with the overall ignition delays measured in
this study, as well as the ignition delays measured previously in the
literature using RCMs and shock tubes. This model therefore represents a strong
improvement compared to the previous version, which uniformly over-predicted
the ignition delays. Chemical kinetic analyses of the updated mechanism are
also conducted to help understand the fuel decomposition pathways and the
reactions controlling the ignition. Combined, these results and analyses
suggest that further investigation of several of the low-temperature fuel
decomposition pathways is required.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.03009</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.03009</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>Bryan W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Autoigniton of n-Butanol at Low to Intermediate Temperature and Elevated
  Pressure</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>63 pages, 32 figures, 2 tables, MS Thesis (August 2010)</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Autoignition delay experiments were performed for n-butanol in a heated rapid
compression machine. Experiments were performed at pressures of 15 and 30 bar,
in the temperature range 650-900 K, and for equivalence ratios of 0.5, 1.0, and
2.0. Additionally, the initial fuel mole fraction and initial oxygen mole
fraction were varied independently to determine the influence of each on
ignition delay. Over the conditions studied, it was found that the reactivity
of the mixture increased as equivalence ratio, initial fuel mole fraction or
initial oxygen mole fraction increased. A non-linear correlation to the
experimental data was performed and showed nearly second order dependence on
the initial oxygen mole fraction and nearly first order dependence on initial
fuel mole fraction and compressed pressure. This was the first study of the
ignition of n-butanol in this temperature and pressure range, and contributes
to a better understanding of the chemistry of this fuel under the conditions
relevant to practical devices. Experimentally measured ignition delays were
compared against the ignition delay computed from several reaction mechanisms
in the literature. The agreement between experiments and simulations was found
to be unsatisfactory. Sensitivity analysis was performed and indicated that the
uncertainties of the rate constants of parent fuel decomposition reactions play
a major role in causing the poor agreement. Further path analysis of the fuel
decomposition reactions supported this conclusion and highlighted the
particular importance of certain pathways. Based on these results, it was
concluded that further investigation of the fuel decomposition, including
speciation measurements, will be required.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.03013</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.03013</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Ichinose</keyname><forenames>Genki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Satotani</keyname><forenames>Yoshiki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sayama</keyname><forenames>Hiroki</forenames></author></authors><title>How mutation alters fitness of cooperation in networked evolutionary
  games</title><categories>q-bio.PE physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><msc-class>91A22</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cooperation is ubiquitous in every level of living organisms. It is known
that spatial (network) structure is a viable mechanism for cooperation to
evolve. Until recently, it has been difficult to predict whether cooperation
can evolve at a network (population) level. To address this problem, Pinheiro
et al. proposed a numerical metric, called Average Gradient of Selection (AGoS)
in 2012. AGoS can characterize and forecast the evolutionary fate of
cooperation at a population level. However, stochastic mutation of strategies
was not considered in the analysis of AGoS. Here we analyzed the evolution of
cooperation using AGoS where mutation may occur to strategies of individuals in
networks. Our analyses revealed that mutation always has a negative effect on
the evolution of cooperation regardless of the fraction of cooperators and
network structures. Moreover, we found that mutation affects the fitness of
cooperation differently on different social network structures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.03023</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.03023</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Sonier</keyname><forenames>J. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Comment on &quot;Discovery of slow magnetic fluctuations and critical slowing
  down in the pseudogap phase of YBa$_2$Cu$_3$O$_y$&quot;</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>4 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A recent zero-field (ZF) and longitudinal-field (LF) muon spin relaxation
($\mu$SR) study of YBa$_2$Cu$_3$O$_y$ [Jian~Zhang {\it et al.},
arXiv:1709.06799] claims to have detected critical slowing down of magnetic
fluctuations near the pseudogap temperature $T^*$, and attribute this to the
onset of slow fluctuating domains of intra-unit-cell magnetic order. Here it is
argued that the relaxation data displayed in this study are misleading due to
an improper account of the nuclear dipole contribution and a failure to
acknowledge the occurrence of muon diffusion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.03028</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.03028</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Giannella-Neto</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jandre</keyname><forenames>Frederico C.</forenames></author></authors><title>How big was Galileo's impact? Percussion in the Sixth Day of the &quot;Two
  New Sciences&quot;</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Giornata Sesta about the Force of Percussion is a relatively less known
Chapter from the Galileo's masterpiece &quot;Discourse about Two New Sciences&quot;. It
was first published lately (1718), long after the first edition of the Two New
Sciences (1638) and Galileo's death (1642). The Giornata Sesta focuses on how
to quantify the percussion force caused by a body in movement, and describes a
very interesting experiment known as &quot;the two-bucket experiment&quot;. In this
paper, we review this experiment reported by Galileo, develop a steady-state
theoretical model, and solve its transient form numerically; additionally, we
report the results from one real simplified analogous experiment. Finally, we
discuss the conclusions drawn by Galileo -- correct, despite a probably
unnoticeable imbalance --, showing that he did not report the thrust force
component in his setup -- which would be fundamental for the correct
calculation of the percussion force.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.03039</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.03039</id><created>2017-03-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>Kuntal</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultra-low-energy Electric field-induced Magnetization Switching in
  Multiferroic Heterostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Review paper</comments><journal-ref>SPIN (World Scientific) 6, 1630001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S2010324716300012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electric field-induced magnetization switching in multiferroics is intriguing
for both fundamental studies and potential technological applications. Here, we
review the recent developments on electric field-induced magnetization
switching in multiferroic heterostructures. Particularly, we study the dynamics
of magnetization switching between the two stable states in a shape-anisotropic
single-domain nanomagnet using stochastic Landau-Lifshitz-Gilbert (LLG)
equation in the presence of thermal fluctuations. For magnetostrictive
nanomagnets in strain-coupled multiferroic composites, such study of
magnetization dynamics, contrary to steady-state scenario, revealed intriguing
new phenomena on binary switching mechanism. While the traditional method of
binary switching requires to tilt the potential profile to the desired state of
switching, we show that no such tilting is necessary to switch successfully
since the magnetization's excursion out of magnet's plane can generate a
built-in asymmetry during switching. We also study the switching dynamics in
multiferroic heterostructures having magnetoelectric coupling at the interface
and magnetic exchange coupling that can facilitate to maintain the direction of
switching with the polarity of the applied electric field. We calculate the
performance metrics like switching delay and energy dissipation during
switching while simulating LLG dynamics. The performance metrics turn out to be
very encouraging for potential technological applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.03043</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.03043</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Holmes</keyname><forenames>Roisin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Xuebin B</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dunne</keyname><forenames>Aishling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Florea</keyname><forenames>Larisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wood</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tronci</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author></authors><title>Thiol-ene photo-click collagen-PEG hydrogels: impact of water-soluble
  photoinitiators on cell viability, gelation kinetics and rheological
  properties</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>29 pages, 6 figures, 2 schemes, 3 tables. Accepted in &quot;Polymers&quot;</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Thiol-ene photo-click hydrogels were prepared via step-growth polymerisation
using thiol-functionalised type-I collagen and 8-arm poly(ethylene glycol)
norbornene terminated (PEG-NB), as a potential injectable regenerative device.
Type-I collagen was thiol-functionalised by a ring opening reaction with
2-iminothiolane (2IT), whereby up to 80 Abs% functionalisation and 90 RPN%
triple helical preservation were recorded via 2,4,6-Trinitrobenzenesulfonic
acid (TNBS) colorimetric assay and circular dichroism (CD). Type, i.e.
2-Hydroxy-1-[4-(2-hydroxyethoxy)phenyl]-2-methyl-1-propanone (I2959) or lithium
phenyl-2,4,6-trimethylbenzoylphosphinate (LAP), and concentration of
photoinitiator were varied to ensure minimal photoinitiator-induced
cytotoxicity and to enable thiol-ene network formation of collagen-PEG
mixtures. The viability of G292 cells following 24 h culture in
photoinitiator-supplemented media was largely affected by the photoinitiator
concentration, with I2959-supplemented media observed to induce higher toxic
response compared to LAP-supplemented media. In line with the in vitro study,
selected photoinitiator concentrations were used to prepare thiol-ene
photo-click hydrogels. Gelation kinetics proved to be largely affected by the
specific photoinitiator, with LAP-containing thiol-ene mixtures leading to
significantly reduced complete gelation time with respect to I2959-containing
mixtures. Other than the specific photoinitiator, the photoinitiator
concentration was key to adjust hydrogel storage modulus (G'), whereby 15-fold
G' increase was observed in samples prepared with 0.5% (w/v) compared to 0.1%
(w/v) LAP. The photoinitiator-gelation-cytotoxicity relationships established
in this study will be instrumental to the design of orthogonal collagen-based
niches for regenerative medicine.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.03048</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.03048</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Mikhailichenko</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>To the Acceleration of Charged Particles with Travelling Laser Focus</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe here the latest results of calculations with FlexPDE code of
wake-fields induced by the bunch in micro-structures. These structures,
illuminated by swept laser bust, serve for acceleration of charged particles.
The basis of the scheme is a fast sweeping device for the laser bunch. After
sweeping, the laser bunch has a slope ~45o with respect to the direction of
propagation. So the every cell of the microstructure becomes excited locally
only for the moment when the particles are there. Self-consistent parameters of
collider based on this idea allow consideration this type of collider as a
candidate for the near-future accelerator era.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
